{
	"description": "Kanji for JLPT N1",
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "一切", "answers": [ "いっさい" ], "comment": "all; everything; the whole; lock, stock, and barrel\nabsolutely not (with negative); without exception; entirely not" },
	{ "question": "一別", "answers": [ "いちべつ" ], "comment": "parting" },
	{ "question": "一同", "answers": [ "いちどう" ], "comment": "all present; all concerned; all of us" },
	{ "question": "一向", "answers": [ "いっこう", "ひたすら" ], "comment": "nothing but; earnest; intent; determined; set on (something)\ncompletely; absolutely; totally\n(not) at all; (not) a bit; (not) in the least\nearnestly; intently; determinedly\nJōdo Shinshū" },
	{ "question": "一変", "answers": [ "いっぺん" ], "comment": "complete change; about-face" },
	{ "question": "一定", "answers": [ "いってい", "いちじょう" ], "comment": "fixed; settled; constant; definite; uniform; regularized; regularised; defined; standardized; standardised; certain; prescribed" },
	{ "question": "一帯", "answers": [ "いったい" ], "comment": "region; zone; whole place" },
	{ "question": "一律", "answers": [ "いちりつ" ], "comment": "uniform; even; across-the-board; equal" },
	{ "question": "一心", "answers": [ "いっしん" ], "comment": "one mind\nwholeheartedness; one's whole heart" },
	{ "question": "一息", "answers": [ "ひといき" ], "comment": "one breath; pause; rest\none go (i.e. in a short time)\nsmall amount of effort" },
	{ "question": "一括", "answers": [ "いっかつ" ], "comment": "all together; batch; one lump; one bundle; summing up" },
	{ "question": "一挙に", "answers": [ "いっきょに" ], "comment": "at a stroke; with a single swoop" },
	{ "question": "一敗", "answers": [ "いっぱい" ], "comment": "one defeat" },
	{ "question": "一日", "answers": [ "いちにち", "いちじつ", "ついたち" ], "comment": "one day\nfirst day of the month\nfirst day of the month\nfirst ten days of the lunar month\nfirst day of the month\nfirst ten days of the lunar month" },
	{ "question": "一昨昨日", "answers": [ "いっさくさくじつ", "さきおととい" ], "comment": "two days before yesterday; three days back (ago)" },
	{ "question": "一概に", "answers": [ "いちがいに" ], "comment": "unconditionally; as a rule" },
	{ "question": "一様", "answers": [ "いちよう" ], "comment": "uniformity; evenness; similarity; equality; impartiality; homogeneity" },
	{ "question": "一気", "answers": [ "いっき" ], "comment": "chug!; drink! (said repeatedly as a party cheer)" },
	{ "question": "一目", "answers": [ "ひとめ", "いちもく" ], "comment": "glance; look; glimpse\ncomplete view; bird's-eye view\nlook; glance\nstone (in the game of go)" },
	{ "question": "一筋", "answers": [ "ひとすじ" ], "comment": "one long straight object (e.g. strand of hair, beam of light, wisp of smoke)\na single bloodline\nearnest; resolute; intent; devoted\nordinary; common" },
	{ "question": "一羽", "answers": [ "いちわ" ], "comment": "one (bird)" },
	{ "question": "一見", "answers": [ "いっけん", "いちげん" ], "comment": "look; glimpse; glance\napparently; seemingly\nfirst meeting\nfirst visit to inn, restaurant, etc. without an introduction" },
	{ "question": "一言", "answers": [ "ひとこと", "いちごん", "いちげん" ], "comment": "single word; a few words; brief comment" },
	{ "question": "一連", "answers": [ "いちれん" ], "comment": "series; chain; sequence\ntwo reams (i.e. 1000 sheets of paper)\nverse; stanza" },
	{ "question": "一部", "answers": [ "いちぶ" ], "comment": "one part; one portion; one section; some\none copy (e.g. of a document)" },
	{ "question": "一部分", "answers": [ "いちぶぶん" ], "comment": "part; portion; section" },
	{ "question": "一面", "answers": [ "いちめん" ], "comment": "one face; one surface\nthe whole surface\none aspect; one side\n(on) the other hand\none broad, flat object\nfront page (e.g. newspaper)" },
	{ "question": "一頃", "answers": [ "ひところ" ], "comment": "once; some time ago" },
	{ "question": "丁寧", "answers": [ "ていねい" ], "comment": "polite; courteous; civil\ncareful; close; thorough; conscientious" },
	{ "question": "丁度", "answers": [ "ちょうど" ], "comment": "exactly; precisely; just; right\nas if; as though; quite" },
	{ "question": "万人", "answers": [ "ばんじん", "ばんにん", "まんにん" ], "comment": "all people; everybody\nten thousand people" },
	{ "question": "万能", "answers": [ "ばんのう" ], "comment": "all-purpose; utility\nalmighty; omnipotent" },
	{ "question": "丈", "answers": [ "たけ", "じょう" ], "comment": "height; stature\nlength (esp. of clothing)\nall (one has); everything\nmagnificence (of a waka poem, etc.)\n3.03 meters (ten shaku)\nlength; measure\nMr.; Mrs." },
	{ "question": "丈夫", "answers": [ "じょうぶ", "じょうふ" ], "comment": "healthy; robust; strong; solid; durable\nhero; manly person; warrior" },
	{ "question": "三味線", "answers": [ "しゃみせん", "さみせん" ], "comment": "shamisen; samisen; three-stringed Japanese lute" },
	{ "question": "三日月", "answers": [ "みかづき" ], "comment": "new moon; crescent moon" },
	{ "question": "上位", "answers": [ "じょうい" ], "comment": "superior (in rank); top; ranking\nhigher order (e.g. byte)\nhost computer (of connected device)" },
	{ "question": "上司", "answers": [ "じょうし" ], "comment": "superior authorities; boss" },
	{ "question": "上回る", "answers": [ "うわまわる" ], "comment": "to exceed (esp. figures: profits, unemployment rate, etc.); to surpass; to be more than; to be better than" },
	{ "question": "上手", "answers": [ "じょうず", "うわて", "かみて" ], "comment": "skill; skillful; dexterity\nflattery\nupper part\nupper stream; upper course of a river\nright side of the stage (audience's or camera's POV); stage left (actor's POV)\nskillful (only in comparisons); dexterity (only in comparisons)\nover-arm grip on opponent's belt" },
	{ "question": "上昇", "answers": [ "じょうしょう" ], "comment": "rising; ascending; climbing" },
	{ "question": "上演", "answers": [ "じょうえん" ], "comment": "performance (e.g. music, theatre, opera); staging" },
	{ "question": "上空", "answers": [ "じょうくう" ], "comment": "sky; the skies; high-altitude sky; upper air" },
	{ "question": "上陸", "answers": [ "じょうりく" ], "comment": "landing; disembarkation; landfall" },
	{ "question": "下がる", "answers": [ "さがる" ], "comment": "to come down; to go down; to fall; to drop; to sink; to get lower\nto hang; to dangle\nto move back; to step back; to withdraw; to retire\nto deteriorate; to fall off; to be downgraded\nto get closer to the present day\nto go south" },
	{ "question": "下らない", "answers": [ "くだらない" ], "comment": "good-for-nothing; stupid; trivial; worthless" },
	{ "question": "下位", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "low rank; subordinate; lower order (e.g. byte); low-end" },
	{ "question": "下取り", "answers": [ "したどり" ], "comment": "trade in; part exchange" },
	{ "question": "下地", "answers": [ "したじ" ], "comment": "groundwork; foundation\ninclination; aptitude; elementary knowledge of; grounding in\nundercoat; first coat\nsoy sauce" },
	{ "question": "下心", "answers": [ "したごころ" ], "comment": "secret intention; ulterior motive\nkanji \"heart\" radical at bottom" },
	{ "question": "下火", "answers": [ "したび" ], "comment": "burning low; waning; declining" },
	{ "question": "下番", "answers": [ "かばん" ], "comment": "going off duty" },
	{ "question": "下痢", "answers": [ "げり" ], "comment": "diarrhoea; diarrhea" },
	{ "question": "下調べ", "answers": [ "したしらべ" ], "comment": "preliminary investigation; preparation" },
	{ "question": "不便", "answers": [ "ふべん", "ふびん" ], "comment": "inconvenience; inexpediency; unhandiness\npity; compassion" },
	{ "question": "不動産", "answers": [ "ふどうさん" ], "comment": "real estate" },
	{ "question": "不可欠", "answers": [ "ふかけつ" ], "comment": "indispensable; essential" },
	{ "question": "不吉", "answers": [ "ふきつ" ], "comment": "ominous; sinister; unlucky; inauspicious" },
	{ "question": "不味い", "answers": [ "まずい" ], "comment": "unappetising; unappetizing; unsavoury; unsavory; unpleasant\nunskillful; unskilful; bungling; clumsy; poor\nugly; unattractive; homely; plain\nawkward; problematic; troublesome; unfavorable; unfavourable; unwise" },
	{ "question": "不在", "answers": [ "ふざい" ], "comment": "absence\ndisregard; indifference" },
	{ "question": "不審", "answers": [ "ふしん" ], "comment": "incomplete understanding; doubt; question; distrust; suspicion; strangeness; infidelity" },
	{ "question": "不当", "answers": [ "ふとう" ], "comment": "injustice; impropriety; unreasonableness; undeserved; unfair; invalid" },
	{ "question": "不意", "answers": [ "ふい" ], "comment": "sudden; abrupt; unexpected; unforeseen" },
	{ "question": "不振", "answers": [ "ふしん" ], "comment": "dullness; depression; slump; stagnation" },
	{ "question": "不明", "answers": [ "ふめい" ], "comment": "unclear; obscure; indistinct; uncertain; ambiguous\nunknown; unidentified\nignorance; lack of wisdom; lack of insight" },
	{ "question": "不景気", "answers": [ "ふけいき" ], "comment": "economic slump; hard times; recession; depression\npoor (business); dull; slack; inactive\ngloomy; cheerless; dismal" },
	{ "question": "不服", "answers": [ "ふふく" ], "comment": "dissatisfaction; discontent; disapproval; objection; complaint; protest; disagreement" },
	{ "question": "不況", "answers": [ "ふきょう" ], "comment": "recession; depression; slump" },
	{ "question": "不良", "answers": [ "ふりょう" ], "comment": "bad; poor; inferior\ndelinquent; hoodlum; hooligan" },
	{ "question": "不評", "answers": [ "ふひょう" ], "comment": "bad reputation; disgrace; unpopularity" },
	{ "question": "不調", "answers": [ "ふちょう" ], "comment": "bad condition; not to work out (i.e. a deal); disagreement; break-off; disorder; slump; out of form" },
	{ "question": "不順", "answers": [ "ふじゅん" ], "comment": "irregularity; unseasonableness" },
	{ "question": "与党", "answers": [ "よとう" ], "comment": "ruling party; government party; party in power; government" },
	{ "question": "世", "answers": [ "よ" ], "comment": "world; society; age; generation\ncounter for generations\nepoch" },
	{ "question": "世代", "answers": [ "せだい" ], "comment": "generation; the world; the age" },
	{ "question": "世帯", "answers": [ "せたい" ], "comment": "household; home; family; housekeeping" },
	{ "question": "世論", "answers": [ "せろん", "よろん" ], "comment": "public opinion; popular voice; public sentiment; consensus" },
	{ "question": "世辞", "answers": [ "せじ" ], "comment": "flattery; compliment" },
	{ "question": "丘陵", "answers": [ "きゅうりょう" ], "comment": "hill" },
	{ "question": "両極", "answers": [ "りょうきょく" ], "comment": "both extremities\nNorth and South Poles\npositive and negative poles" },
	{ "question": "両立", "answers": [ "りょうりつ" ], "comment": "compatibility; coexistence; standing together" },
	{ "question": "並びに", "answers": [ "ならびに" ], "comment": "and (also); both ... and; as well as" },
	{ "question": "並み", "answers": [ "なみ" ], "comment": "average; medium; common; ordinary\nline; row of (e.g. houses)\nmid-grade\nsame level; equal; each (e.g. month); set of (e.g. teeth)" },
	{ "question": "並列", "answers": [ "へいれつ" ], "comment": "running in parallel; lined up alongside\nparallel (electronics, computing, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "中っ腹", "answers": [ "ちゅうっぱら" ], "comment": "anger (held in check); irritation; rage" },
	{ "question": "中傷", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょう" ], "comment": "slander; libel; defamation; calumny; smear" },
	{ "question": "中和", "answers": [ "ちゅうわ" ], "comment": "neutralizing; neutralising; counteracting\nneutral; unbiased" },
	{ "question": "中指", "answers": [ "なかゆび", "ちゅうし" ], "comment": "middle finger; long finger; second finger; tall finger\nmiddle toe; third toe" },
	{ "question": "中断", "answers": [ "ちゅうだん" ], "comment": "interruption; suspension; break" },
	{ "question": "中枢", "answers": [ "ちゅうすう" ], "comment": "centre; center; pivot; mainstay; nucleus; backbone; central figure; pillar; key man" },
	{ "question": "中毒", "answers": [ "ちゅうどく" ], "comment": "poisoning\naddiction" },
	{ "question": "中程", "answers": [ "なかほど" ], "comment": "(about) middle; midway" },
	{ "question": "中立", "answers": [ "ちゅうりつ" ], "comment": "neutrality\nbreak between the light meal and the actual serving of tea (during a formal tea ceremony)" },
	{ "question": "中継", "answers": [ "ちゅうけい" ], "comment": "relay; hook-up\nrelay broadcasting\njoining; joint; intermediation; relaying; intermediary; relay; agency; brokerage\nmid-relief pitcher; middle reliever" },
	{ "question": "丸々", "answers": [ "まるまる" ], "comment": "plump; rotund; chubby\nentirely; completely; wholly" },
	{ "question": "丸ごと", "answers": [ "まるごと" ], "comment": "in its entirety; whole; wholly" },
	{ "question": "丸っきり", "answers": [ "まるっきり" ], "comment": "completely; perfectly; totally; just as if" },
	{ "question": "丸で", "answers": [ "まるで" ], "comment": "quite; entirely; completely; at all\nas if; as though; just like" },
	{ "question": "丸める", "answers": [ "まるめる" ], "comment": "to make round; to roll up; to curl up\nto seduce; to cajole; to explain away\nto round off (a fraction)\nto lump together" },
	{ "question": "丹念", "answers": [ "たんねん" ], "comment": "painstaking; careful; meticulous; scrupulous; detailed; elaborate" },
	{ "question": "主人公", "answers": [ "しゅじんこう" ], "comment": "protagonist; main character; hero(ine) (of a story)\nhead of household" },
	{ "question": "主任", "answers": [ "しゅにん" ], "comment": "person in charge; responsible official; senior staff" },
	{ "question": "主体", "answers": [ "しゅたい" ], "comment": "main constituent; core; nucleus\nsubject (philosophical); protagonist" },
	{ "question": "主催", "answers": [ "しゅさい" ], "comment": "sponsorship (i.e. conducting under one's auspices); promotion; organizing; organising; hosting; staging" },
	{ "question": "主導", "answers": [ "しゅどう" ], "comment": "leadership; initiative; spearhead" },
	{ "question": "主権", "answers": [ "しゅけん" ], "comment": "sovereignty; supremacy; dominion" },
	{ "question": "主演", "answers": [ "しゅえん" ], "comment": "starring; playing the leading part" },
	{ "question": "主観", "answers": [ "しゅかん" ], "comment": "subjectivity; subject (philosophical); ego\none's personal opinion; one's own idea" },
	{ "question": "主題", "answers": [ "しゅだい" ], "comment": "subject; theme; motif" },
	{ "question": "主食", "answers": [ "しゅしょく" ], "comment": "staple food" },
	{ "question": "久しい", "answers": [ "ひさしい" ], "comment": "long; long-continued; old (story)" },
	{ "question": "久し振り", "answers": [ "ひさしぶり" ], "comment": "a long time (since the last time); it's been a while (since I last saw, mailed, etc., you)" },
	{ "question": "乏しい", "answers": [ "とぼしい" ], "comment": "meagre; meager; scarce; limited; destitute; hard up; lacking; scanty; poor" },
	{ "question": "乗っ取る", "answers": [ "のっとる" ], "comment": "to take over; to capture; to seize; to commandeer; to occupy; to usurp\nto hijack (a vehicle)\nto conform to; to be in accordance with; to follow (rule, tradition, example, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "乗り換え", "answers": [ "のりかえ" ], "comment": "transfer (trains, buses, etc.); connection; connexion\nswitching (stock)\nchromosomal crossover; crossing over" },
	{ "question": "乗り込む", "answers": [ "のりこむ" ], "comment": "to board; to embark on; to get into (a car); to man (a ship); to help (someone) into\nto march into; to enter" },
	{ "question": "乗客", "answers": [ "じょうきゃく", "じょうかく" ], "comment": "passenger" },
	{ "question": "乙", "answers": [ "おつ", "きのと" ], "comment": "second (party to an agreement); the B party (e.g. in a contract); the latter; defendant\nstylish; chic; spicy; witty; tasty; romantic\nstrange; quaint; queer\nthank you; good job; goodbye; goodnight\nsecond in rank; second sign of the Chinese calendar" },
	{ "question": "乙女", "answers": [ "おとめ" ], "comment": "little girl; maiden; young lady; female usually between 7 and 18 years old" },
	{ "question": "乱す", "answers": [ "みだす" ], "comment": "to throw out of order; to disarrange; to disturb" },
	{ "question": "乱れる", "answers": [ "みだれる" ], "comment": "to be disordered; to be disarranged; to be disarrayed; to be disheveled; to be dishevelled\nto be discomposed; to be upset; to get confused; to be disturbed\nto lapse into chaos (due to war, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "乳", "answers": [ "ちち" ], "comment": "milk\nbreast\nloop\ndecorative bump (on a hanging bell)" },
	{ "question": "了承", "answers": [ "りょうしょう" ], "comment": "acknowledgement; acknowledgment; understanding (e.g. \"please be understanding of the mess during our renovation\"); noting; acceptance" },
	{ "question": "了解", "answers": [ "りょうかい" ], "comment": "comprehension; consent; understanding; agreement; roger (on the radio)" },
	{ "question": "予め", "answers": [ "あらかじめ" ], "comment": "beforehand; in advance; previously" },
	{ "question": "予想", "answers": [ "よそう" ], "comment": "expectation; anticipation; prediction; forecast; conjecture" },
	{ "question": "予感", "answers": [ "よかん" ], "comment": "presentiment; premonition; hunch\nto have a premonition; to have a hunch" },
	{ "question": "予言", "answers": [ "よげん", "かねごと" ], "comment": "prediction; prophecy; prognostication\npromise; prediction" },
	{ "question": "争い", "answers": [ "あらそい" ], "comment": "dispute; strife; quarrel; dissension; conflict; rivalry; contest" },
	{ "question": "事によると", "answers": [ "ことによると" ], "comment": "possibly; maybe; perhaps" },
	{ "question": "事前", "answers": [ "じぜん" ], "comment": "prior; beforehand; in advance; before the fact; ex ante" },
	{ "question": "事柄", "answers": [ "ことがら" ], "comment": "matter; thing; affair; circumstance" },
	{ "question": "事業", "answers": [ "じぎょう" ], "comment": "project; enterprise; business; industry; operations; venture; service\nact; deed; conduct" },
	{ "question": "事項", "answers": [ "じこう" ], "comment": "matter; item; facts" },
	{ "question": "互い違い", "answers": [ "たがいちがい" ], "comment": "alternate; alternation" },
	{ "question": "亜科", "answers": [ "あか" ], "comment": "subfamily" },
	{ "question": "交える", "answers": [ "まじえる" ], "comment": "to mix; to combine\nto exchange (words, fire, etc.)\nto cross (e.g. swords); to join together" },
	{ "question": "交わす", "answers": [ "かわす" ], "comment": "to exchange (messages, greetings, arguments, etc.)\nto intersect; to cross; to interlace\n... with one another; ... to each other" },
	{ "question": "交わる", "answers": [ "まじわる" ], "comment": "to cross; to intersect; to join; to meet\nto associate with; to mingle with; to consort with\nto have a sexual relationship; to copulate" },
	{ "question": "交互", "answers": [ "こうご" ], "comment": "mutual; reciprocal; alternate" },
	{ "question": "交付", "answers": [ "こうふ" ], "comment": "delivery; issuance; handing over; granting" },
	{ "question": "交易", "answers": [ "こうえき" ], "comment": "trade; commerce" },
	{ "question": "交渉", "answers": [ "こうしょう" ], "comment": "negotiations; discussions\nconnection" },
	{ "question": "享受", "answers": [ "きょうじゅ" ], "comment": "reception; acceptance; enjoyment; being given" },
	{ "question": "人体", "answers": [ "じんたい" ], "comment": "human body\npersonal appearance; looks" },
	{ "question": "人情", "answers": [ "にんじょう" ], "comment": "humanity; empathy; kindness; sympathy\nhuman nature; common sense; customs and manners" },
	{ "question": "人材", "answers": [ "じんざい" ], "comment": "capable person; talented person\nhuman resources; personnel" },
	{ "question": "人柄", "answers": [ "ひとがら" ], "comment": "personality; character; personal appearance; gentility" },
	{ "question": "人柱", "answers": [ "ひとばしら" ], "comment": "human pillar; human sacrifice" },
	{ "question": "人格", "answers": [ "じんかく" ], "comment": "personality; character; individuality" },
	{ "question": "人民", "answers": [ "じんみん" ], "comment": "people; public\nimperial subjects; the people" },
	{ "question": "人目", "answers": [ "ひとめ", "じんもく" ], "comment": "public gaze; public notice; attention" },
	{ "question": "人質", "answers": [ "ひとじち" ], "comment": "hostage" },
	{ "question": "今日日", "answers": [ "きょうび" ], "comment": "nowadays" },
	{ "question": "今更", "answers": [ "いまさら" ], "comment": "now (after such a long time); at this late hour (i.e. it is too late for something); at this point of time\nafresh; anew; again" },
	{ "question": "介入", "answers": [ "かいにゅう" ], "comment": "intervention" },
	{ "question": "介抱", "answers": [ "かいほう" ], "comment": "nursing; looking after" },
	{ "question": "介護", "answers": [ "かいご" ], "comment": "nursing; care; caregiving; caring" },
	{ "question": "仏", "answers": [ "ほとけ", "ふつ" ], "comment": "France\nBuddha; Buddhism\nBuddha; merciful person; Buddhist image\nthe dead; dead person; spirit of the dead" },
	{ "question": "仏像", "answers": [ "ぶつぞう" ], "comment": "statue of Buddha; image of Buddha; Buddhist statue; Buddhist image" },
	{ "question": "仕える", "answers": [ "つかえる" ], "comment": "to serve; to work for; to attend" },
	{ "question": "仕上がり", "answers": [ "しあがり" ], "comment": "finish; end; completion" },
	{ "question": "仕上げ", "answers": [ "しあげ" ], "comment": "end; finishing touches; being finished" },
	{ "question": "仕上げる", "answers": [ "しあげる" ], "comment": "to finish up; to complete; to finish off; to get through; to polish off" },
	{ "question": "仕付ける", "answers": [ "しつける" ], "comment": "to be used to; to get accustomed to; to be in the habit of doing\nto train; to discipline; to teach manners\nto tack (in needlework); to baste\nto plant (esp. rice seedlings)" },
	{ "question": "仕入れる", "answers": [ "しいれる" ], "comment": "to lay in stock; to replenish stock; to procure; to learn something that might be useful later" },
	{ "question": "仕切る", "answers": [ "しきる" ], "comment": "to partition; to divide; to mark off; to itemize\nto direct; to take control; to manage; to take responsibility\nto settle accounts\nto toe the mark" },
	{ "question": "仕掛け", "answers": [ "しかけ" ], "comment": "device; contrivance; mechanism; gadget\ntrick; trap; calculated manipulation; gambit\n(small) scale; half finished\ncommencement; initiation\nset up; laying out; preparation\nchallenge; attack" },
	{ "question": "仕掛ける", "answers": [ "しかける" ], "comment": "to start; to begin; to commence\nto challenge; to pick (a fight); to make (war)\nto set (traps); to plant (explosives); to lay (mines)" },
	{ "question": "仕様", "answers": [ "しよう" ], "comment": "way; method; means; resource; remedy\n(technical) specification" },
	{ "question": "仕立てる", "answers": [ "したてる" ], "comment": "to tailor; to make (clothing)\nto train; to bring up\nto make it seem like; to pass off\nto turn into a play or movie\nto prepare; to send; to despatch" },
	{ "question": "仕組み", "answers": [ "しくみ" ], "comment": "structure; construction; arrangement; contrivance; mechanism; workings\nplan; plot; contrivance" },
	{ "question": "仕舞", "answers": [ "しまい" ], "comment": "end; close; finish; termination\nnoh dance in plain clothes\nending; quitting; closing\nindicates disappointment for not having done what one wanted or intended to do" },
	{ "question": "仕舞う", "answers": [ "しまう" ], "comment": "to finish; to stop; to end; to put an end to; to bring to a close\nto close (a business, etc.); to close down; to shut down; to shut up\nto put away; to put back; to keep; to store\nto finish ...; to do ... completely" },
	{ "question": "他人", "answers": [ "たにん", "あだびと" ], "comment": "another person; other people; others\nunrelated person (i.e. not related by blood)\noutsider; stranger" },
	{ "question": "他動詞", "answers": [ "たどうし" ], "comment": "transitive verb" },
	{ "question": "他意", "answers": [ "たい" ], "comment": "ill will; malice; another intention; secret purpose; ulterior motive; fickleness; double-mindedness" },
	{ "question": "他方", "answers": [ "たほう" ], "comment": "one (esp. of two); the other; one way; the other way; one direction; the other direction; one side; the other side; one party; the other party\non the other hand" },
	{ "question": "付き", "answers": [ "つき" ], "comment": "furnished with; including\nattached to\nimpression; appearance\nluck\nsociality\nunder; assistant (e.g. to a manager)\nsoup base" },
	{ "question": "付き合う", "answers": [ "つきあう" ], "comment": "to associate with; to keep company with; to go out with; to go steady with; to get on with\nto go along with; to follow someone's lead; to accompany someone; to compromise" },
	{ "question": "付け加える", "answers": [ "つけくわえる" ], "comment": "to add one thing to another" },
	{ "question": "付属", "answers": [ "ふぞく" ], "comment": "attached; belonging (to); included; enclosed; affiliated; annexed; associated; subordinate; incidental; dependent; auxiliary" },
	{ "question": "付録", "answers": [ "ふろく" ], "comment": "appendix; supplement; annex; extra (of a newspaper or magazine)" },
	{ "question": "仙", "answers": [ "せん" ], "comment": "cent (monetary unit)\nhermit; wizard" },
	{ "question": "代", "answers": [ "だい", "よ", "しろ" ], "comment": "substitution\nmaterial\nprice\nmargin (e.g. for stapling, etc.); area required for something\nshiro (unit of land area equal to one-fiftieth of a tan; ~19.83 m.sq.)\nworld; society; age; generation\ncharge; cost; price\ngeneration; age; reign\nera\na representative of; on behalf of; for (someone)\nused after a phone number to indicate that it is a switchboard number\ncounter for decades of ages, eras, etc.\ncounter for generations (of inheritors to a throne, etc.)\nproxy application company\npronoun" },
	{ "question": "代わる代わる", "answers": [ "かわるがわる" ], "comment": "alternately; by turns" },
	{ "question": "代弁", "answers": [ "だいべん" ], "comment": "pay by proxy; act for another; speak for another" },
	{ "question": "代用", "answers": [ "だいよう" ], "comment": "substitution" },
	{ "question": "仮", "answers": [ "かり" ], "comment": "lacking substance and existing in name only; something without substance\ntemporary; provisional; interim\nfictitious; assumed (name); alias\nhypothetical; theoretical" },
	{ "question": "仰ぐ", "answers": [ "あおぐ" ], "comment": "to look up (at)\nto look up (to); to respect; to revere\nto ask for; to seek\nto turn to someone; to depend on\nto gulp down; to quaff; to take (e.g. poison)" },
	{ "question": "仰っしゃる", "answers": [ "おっしゃる" ], "comment": "to say; to speak; to tell; to talk" },
	{ "question": "仲人 (not ちゅうにん)", "answers": [ "なこうど" ], "comment": "matchmaker\ngo-between; intermediary; middleman; mediator; intercessor\ngo-between; matchmaker" },
	{ "question": "件", "answers": [ "くだん", "けん" ], "comment": "the aforementioned; the said; (man, incident, etc.) in question; the above-mentioned; the aforesaid\nthe usual\nmatter; case; item; affair; subject\npassage; paragraph" },
	{ "question": "任す", "answers": [ "まかす" ], "comment": "to entrust; to leave to a person" },
	{ "question": "任務", "answers": [ "にんむ" ], "comment": "duty; function; office; mission; task" },
	{ "question": "任命", "answers": [ "にんめい" ], "comment": "appointment; nomination; ordination; commission; designation" },
	{ "question": "企画", "answers": [ "きかく" ], "comment": "planning; project; plan; design" },
	{ "question": "休める", "answers": [ "やすめる" ], "comment": "to rest; to suspend; to give relief" },
	{ "question": "休学", "answers": [ "きゅうがく" ], "comment": "temporary absence from school" },
	{ "question": "休戦", "answers": [ "きゅうせん" ], "comment": "cease-fire; truce; armistice" },
	{ "question": "会見", "answers": [ "かいけん" ], "comment": "interview; audience" },
	{ "question": "会談", "answers": [ "かいだん" ], "comment": "conversation; conference (usu. between important people); discussion; interview" },
	{ "question": "伝来", "answers": [ "でんらい" ], "comment": "ancestral; hereditary; imported; transmitted; handed down" },
	{ "question": "伝言", "answers": [ "でんごん", "つてごと" ], "comment": "verbal message; word\nverbal message; word\nrumour; rumor" },
	{ "question": "伝説", "answers": [ "でんせつ" ], "comment": "tradition; legend; folklore" },
	{ "question": "伝達", "answers": [ "でんたつ" ], "comment": "transmission (e.g. news, chemical signals, electricity); communication; delivery; conveyance; transfer; relay; propagation; conduction" },
	{ "question": "伴う", "answers": [ "ともなう" ], "comment": "to accompany; to go hand in hand with; to be consequent upon\nto be accompanied by; to bring with; to take with; to be involved in" },
	{ "question": "似通う", "answers": [ "にかよう" ], "comment": "to resemble closely" },
	{ "question": "位置", "answers": [ "いち" ], "comment": "place; situation; position; location" },
	{ "question": "体付き", "answers": [ "からだつき" ], "comment": "body build; figure" },
	{ "question": "体力", "answers": [ "たいりょく" ], "comment": "stamina; endurance; physical strength; resilience; resistance to disease\nstrength of an organization (e.g. profitability, productivity, economic clout, stability, growth potential)" },
	{ "question": "体格", "answers": [ "たいかく" ], "comment": "physique; constitution" },
	{ "question": "体裁", "answers": [ "ていさい" ], "comment": "(outward) appearance\n(proper) format (e.g. of an essay); form; style\nappearances; decency; show; display\nlip-service; insincere words; glib talk" },
	{ "question": "体験", "answers": [ "たいけん" ], "comment": "personal experience; physical experience; one's own experience" },
	{ "question": "何処", "answers": [ "どこ" ], "comment": "where; what place\nhow much (long, far); what extent" },
	{ "question": "何処か", "answers": [ "どこか" ], "comment": "somewhere; anywhere; in some respects" },
	{ "question": "何故", "answers": [ "なぜ", "なにゆえ" ], "comment": "why; how" },
	{ "question": "何故なら", "answers": [ "なぜなら" ], "comment": "because; the reason is; if you want to know why" },
	{ "question": "何時", "answers": [ "いつ", "なんじ", "なんどき" ], "comment": "when; how soon\nwhat time?" },
	{ "question": "何気ない", "answers": [ "なにげない" ], "comment": "casual; unconcerned; nonchalant" },
	{ "question": "余り", "answers": [ "あまり", "あんまり" ], "comment": "remainder; rest; balance; remains; scraps; residue; remnant\nnot very (with negative sentence); not much\nsurplus; excess; fullness; too much\nmore than; over" },
	{ "question": "余地", "answers": [ "よち" ], "comment": "place; room; margin; scope" },
	{ "question": "余弦", "answers": [ "よげん" ], "comment": "cosine" },
	{ "question": "余所見", "answers": [ "よそみ" ], "comment": "looking away; looking aside" },
	{ "question": "余接", "answers": [ "よせつ" ], "comment": "cotangent" },
	{ "question": "余暇", "answers": [ "よか" ], "comment": "leisure; leisure time; spare time" },
	{ "question": "余興", "answers": [ "よきょう" ], "comment": "side show; entertainment" },
	{ "question": "作", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "work (e.g. of art); production\nharvest; cultivation; farming; crop; yield\ntechnique" },
	{ "question": "作戦", "answers": [ "さくせん" ], "comment": "tactics; strategy\nmilitary or naval operations" },
	{ "question": "作物", "answers": [ "さくもつ", "さくぶつ" ], "comment": "literary work\nproduce (e.g. agricultural); crops" },
	{ "question": "作用", "answers": [ "さよう" ], "comment": "action; operation; effect; function" },
	{ "question": "佳句", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "beautiful passage of literature" },
	{ "question": "使い道", "answers": [ "つかいみち" ], "comment": "purpose; utility; objective\nway to use something" },
	{ "question": "使命", "answers": [ "しめい" ], "comment": "mission; errand\ntask; duty; obligation" },
	{ "question": "使用人", "answers": [ "しようにん" ], "comment": "employee; servant" },
	{ "question": "例", "answers": [ "れい", "ためし" ], "comment": "custom; practice; habit; usual\nsaid; aforementioned\ninstance; example; case; illustration; usage\nprecedent\nprecedent; example" },
	{ "question": "例え", "answers": [ "たとえ" ], "comment": "example\nsimile; metaphor; allegory; fable; parable" },
	{ "question": "侍", "answers": [ "さむらい" ], "comment": "warrior (esp. of military retainers of daimyos in the Edo period); samurai\nman in attendance (on a person of high standing); retainer" },
	{ "question": "供", "answers": [ "きょう", "とも" ], "comment": "companion; follower; attendant; retinue" },
	{ "question": "依存", "answers": [ "いそん", "いぞん" ], "comment": "dependence; dependent; reliance" },
	{ "question": "依然", "answers": [ "いぜん" ], "comment": "still; as yet; as it has been" },
	{ "question": "侮辱", "answers": [ "ぶじょく" ], "comment": "insult; affront; slight; contempt (e.g. of court)" },
	{ "question": "侵す", "answers": [ "おかす" ], "comment": "to invade; to raid; to violate (airspace, etc.); to intrude; to trespass\nto infringe; to encroach\nto harm; to afflict; to affect" },
	{ "question": "侵略", "answers": [ "しんりゃく" ], "comment": "aggression; invasion; raid" },
	{ "question": "便宜", "answers": [ "べんぎ" ], "comment": "convenience; accommodation; advantage; expedience" },
	{ "question": "係り", "answers": [ "かかり" ], "comment": "charge; duty; person in charge; official; clerk\nconnection; linking" },
	{ "question": "促す", "answers": [ "うながす" ], "comment": "to urge; to press; to prompt; to suggest; to demand; to stimulate; to quicken; to incite; to invite (attention to)" },
	{ "question": "促進", "answers": [ "そくしん" ], "comment": "promotion; acceleration; encouragement; facilitation; spurring on" },
	{ "question": "保つ", "answers": [ "たもつ" ], "comment": "to keep; to preserve; to hold; to retain; to maintain; to support; to sustain; to last; to endure; to keep well (food); to wear well; to be durable" },
	{ "question": "保守", "answers": [ "ほしゅ" ], "comment": "maintenance\nconservatism; conservativeness; conservation" },
	{ "question": "保母", "answers": [ "ほぼ" ], "comment": "day-care worker in a kindergarten, nursery school, etc." },
	{ "question": "保温", "answers": [ "ほおん" ], "comment": "retaining warmth; keeping heat in; heat insulation" },
	{ "question": "保管", "answers": [ "ほかん" ], "comment": "charge; custody; safekeeping; deposit; storage" },
	{ "question": "保育", "answers": [ "ほいく" ], "comment": "nursing; nurturing; rearing; lactation; suckling" },
	{ "question": "保護", "answers": [ "ほご" ], "comment": "care; protection; shelter; safeguard; guardianship; favor; favour; patronage" },
	{ "question": "保険", "answers": [ "ほけん" ], "comment": "insurance; guarantee" },
	{ "question": "保障", "answers": [ "ほしょう" ], "comment": "guarantee; security; assurance; pledge; warranty" },
	{ "question": "保養", "answers": [ "ほよう" ], "comment": "health preservation; recuperation; recreation" },
	{ "question": "信任", "answers": [ "しんにん" ], "comment": "trust; confidence; credence" },
	{ "question": "信者", "answers": [ "しんじゃ" ], "comment": "believer; adherent; devotee" },
	{ "question": "修了", "answers": [ "しゅうりょう" ], "comment": "completion (of a course)" },
	{ "question": "修士", "answers": [ "しゅうし" ], "comment": "master's (academic degree)" },
	{ "question": "修学", "answers": [ "しゅうがく" ], "comment": "learning" },
	{ "question": "修行", "answers": [ "しゅぎょう" ], "comment": "ascetic practices\ntraining; practice; discipline; study" },
	{ "question": "修飾", "answers": [ "しゅうしょく" ], "comment": "ornamentation; embellishment; decoration; adornment; polish up (writing)\nmodification; qualification" },
	{ "question": "俺", "answers": [ "おれ" ], "comment": "I; me" },
	{ "question": "個", "answers": [ "こ" ], "comment": "counter for articles\ncounter for military units\nindividual\ncounter for the ichi-ni-san counting system (usu. directly preceding the item being counted); a noun read using its on-yomi\ncounter for the hito-futa-mi counting system (forming hitotsu, futatsu, mitsu, and misoji, yasoji, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "個々", "answers": [ "ここ" ], "comment": "individual; one by one; separate" },
	{ "question": "個別", "answers": [ "こべつ" ], "comment": "particular case; discrete; individual; separate" },
	{ "question": "個性", "answers": [ "こせい" ], "comment": "individuality; personality; idiosyncrasy" },
	{ "question": "倍率", "answers": [ "ばいりつ" ], "comment": "magnification; leverage; amplification; scaling factor; scale factor\nacceptance rate; pass rate (of an exam, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "倒産", "answers": [ "とうさん" ], "comment": "(corporate) bankruptcy; insolvency; commercial failure; failed business" },
	{ "question": "借り", "answers": [ "かり" ], "comment": "borrowing; debt; loan" },
	{ "question": "倣う", "answers": [ "ならう" ], "comment": "to imitate; to follow; to emulate" },
	{ "question": "値", "answers": [ "ね", "あたい" ], "comment": "price; cost\nvalue; worth; merit\nvalue; count; number\nvariable (computer programming, programing)\nlevel; value" },
	{ "question": "値する", "answers": [ "あたいする" ], "comment": "to be worth; to deserve; to merit" },
	{ "question": "値引き", "answers": [ "ねびき" ], "comment": "price reduction; discount" },
	{ "question": "値打ち", "answers": [ "ねうち" ], "comment": "value; worth; price; dignity" },
	{ "question": "倹約", "answers": [ "けんやく" ], "comment": "thrift; economy; frugality" },
	{ "question": "偏", "answers": [ "へん" ], "comment": "left-hand radical of a character" },
	{ "question": "偏る", "answers": [ "かたよる" ], "comment": "to be one-sided; to incline; to be partial; to be prejudiced; to lean; to be biased; to be biassed" },
	{ "question": "偏見", "answers": [ "へんけん" ], "comment": "prejudice; narrow view" },
	{ "question": "停滞", "answers": [ "ていたい" ], "comment": "stagnation; tie-up; congestion; retention; accumulation; falling into arrears" },
	{ "question": "健やか", "answers": [ "すこやか" ], "comment": "vigorous; healthy; sound" },
	{ "question": "健全", "answers": [ "けんぜん" ], "comment": "healthy; sound; wholesome" },
	{ "question": "健在", "answers": [ "けんざい" ], "comment": "in good health; well; going strong" },
	{ "question": "側", "answers": [ "かわ", "がわ", "そば" ], "comment": "near; close; beside; vicinity; proximity; besides; while\nthird person\nside (of something, or taking someone's side); part\n(watch) case\nside; edge; beside; besides; nearby\nwhile (doing); in addition to; at the same time" },
	{ "question": "側面", "answers": [ "そくめん" ], "comment": "side; flank; aspect; dimension; profile; sidelight; lateral" },
	{ "question": "偽造", "answers": [ "ぎぞう" ], "comment": "forgery; falsification; fabrication; counterfeiting" },
	{ "question": "傍ら", "answers": [ "かたわら" ], "comment": "side; edge; beside; besides; nearby\nwhile (doing); in addition to; at the same time" },
	{ "question": "傑作", "answers": [ "けっさく" ], "comment": "masterpiece; best work\namusing blunder; funny mistake; boner" },
	{ "question": "備え付ける", "answers": [ "そなえつける" ], "comment": "to provide; to furnish; to equip; to install" },
	{ "question": "備わる", "answers": [ "そなわる" ], "comment": "to be furnished with; to be provided with; to be equipped with\nto be possessed of; to be endowed with; to be gifted with\nto be among; to be one of" },
	{ "question": "催す", "answers": [ "もよおす" ], "comment": "to hold (a meeting); to give (a dinner); to show signs of\nto feel (sensation, emotion, call of nature, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "傷", "answers": [ "きず", "しょう" ], "comment": "wound; injury; cut; gash; bruise; scratch; scrape; scar\nchip; crack; scratch; nick\nflaw; defect; weakness; weak point\nstain (on one's reputation); disgrace; dishonor; dishonour\n(emotional) hurt; hurt feelings" },
	{ "question": "傷付く", "answers": [ "きずつく" ], "comment": "to be wounded; to get injured\nto get hurt feelings\nto get damaged; to get chipped; to get scratched" },
	{ "question": "傾く", "answers": [ "かたむく", "かたぶく" ], "comment": "to incline toward; to slant; to lurch; to heel over; to be disposed to; to trend toward; to be prone to\nto go down (sun); to wane; to sink; to decline\nto lean (esp. of a ripe ear of rice); to incline; to slant; to tilt\nto behave oddly; to attire oneself strangely\nto perform kabuki" },
	{ "question": "傾ける", "answers": [ "かたむける" ], "comment": "to incline; to lean; to tip; to tilt; to slant; to bend; to list\nto devote oneself to; to concentrate on; to pour one's energy into\nto ruin; to squander; to empty\nto drink (alcohol)" },
	{ "question": "傾斜", "answers": [ "けいしゃ" ], "comment": "inclination; slant; slope; bevel; list; dip; tilt; lean" },
	{ "question": "僅か", "answers": [ "わずか" ], "comment": "only; merely; (a) little; small quantity" },
	{ "question": "像", "answers": [ "ぞう" ], "comment": "image; figure; statue; picture; portrait\nfigure; form; shape; appearance\nimage" },
	{ "question": "僕", "answers": [ "ぼく", "しもべ" ], "comment": "servant; manservant; menial\nI; me\nyou\nmanservant" },
	{ "question": "億万長者", "answers": [ "おくまんちょうじゃ" ], "comment": "billionaire; multimillionaire; very rich person" },
	{ "question": "優位", "answers": [ "ゆうい" ], "comment": "predominance; ascendancy; superiority" },
	{ "question": "優先", "answers": [ "ゆうせん" ], "comment": "preference; priority; precedence" },
	{ "question": "優勢", "answers": [ "ゆうせい" ], "comment": "superiority; superior power; predominance; preponderance" },
	{ "question": "優美", "answers": [ "ゆうび" ], "comment": "grace; refinement; elegance; daintiness" },
	{ "question": "優越", "answers": [ "ゆうえつ" ], "comment": "supremacy; predominance; being superior to" },
	{ "question": "元年", "answers": [ "がんねん" ], "comment": "first year (of a specific reign)" },
	{ "question": "元来", "answers": [ "がんらい" ], "comment": "originally; primarily; essentially; logically; naturally" },
	{ "question": "元素", "answers": [ "げんそ" ], "comment": "chemical element" },
	{ "question": "元首", "answers": [ "げんしゅ" ], "comment": "ruler; sovereign" },
	{ "question": "充実", "answers": [ "じゅうじつ" ], "comment": "fullness; completion; perfection; substantiality\nenhancement; improvement; enrichment; upgrading\nreplenishment; repletion" },
	{ "question": "兆", "answers": [ "ちょう" ], "comment": "10^12; 1,000,000,000,000; trillion\nsign; omen; indication; portent" },
	{ "question": "兆し", "answers": [ "きざし" ], "comment": "signs; omen; symptoms" },
	{ "question": "先だって", "answers": [ "せんだって" ], "comment": "recently; the other day" },
	{ "question": "先に", "answers": [ "さきに" ], "comment": "before; earlier than; first; ahead; beyond; away; previously; recently\nformerly" },
	{ "question": "先代", "answers": [ "せんだい" ], "comment": "family predecessor; previous age; previous generation" },
	{ "question": "先天的", "answers": [ "せんてんてき" ], "comment": "inborn; innate; inherent; congenital; hereditary\na priori" },
	{ "question": "先着", "answers": [ "せんちゃく" ], "comment": "arriving first" },
	{ "question": "先行", "answers": [ "せんこう" ], "comment": "preceding; going first; leading; going ahead; taking priority" },
	{ "question": "光沢", "answers": [ "こうたく" ], "comment": "brilliance; polish; lustre; luster; glossy finish (of photographs)" },
	{ "question": "光熱費", "answers": [ "こうねつひ" ], "comment": "cost of fuel and lighting; cost of heat and electricity; energy bill; utility cost" },
	{ "question": "免れる", "answers": [ "まぬがれる", "まぬかれる" ], "comment": "to escape (disaster, death, etc.); to be saved from; to be rescued from\nto avoid (e.g. punishment); to evade (e.g. responsibility); to avert; to elude; to be exempted from" },
	{ "question": "免除", "answers": [ "めんじょ" ], "comment": "exemption; exoneration; discharge" },
	{ "question": "入手", "answers": [ "にゅうしゅ" ], "comment": "acquisition; obtaining; coming to hand" },
	{ "question": "入浴", "answers": [ "にゅうよく" ], "comment": "bathing\nto bathe; to take a bath; to enter a bath" },
	{ "question": "入賞", "answers": [ "にゅうしょう" ], "comment": "winning a prize or place (in a contest)" },
	{ "question": "全快", "answers": [ "ぜんかい" ], "comment": "complete recovery of health" },
	{ "question": "全滅", "answers": [ "ぜんめつ" ], "comment": "annihilation; total destruction; complete destruction; crushing defeat" },
	{ "question": "全盛", "answers": [ "ぜんせい" ], "comment": "height of prosperity" },
	{ "question": "公", "answers": [ "おおやけ" ], "comment": "you; buddy; pal\nmonarch; ruler; sovereign; (one's) master\npublic; open; formal; official; governmental\npublic matter; governmental matter\nprince; duke\nlord; sir\nfamiliar or derogatory suffix" },
	{ "question": "公募", "answers": [ "こうぼ" ], "comment": "public appeal (e.g. for contributions); public offering (of securities); public advertisement (of a post); open recruitment" },
	{ "question": "公団", "answers": [ "こうだん" ], "comment": "public corporation\npublic housing" },
	{ "question": "公演", "answers": [ "こうえん" ], "comment": "public performance\nexhibition in a foreign country" },
	{ "question": "公然", "answers": [ "こうぜん" ], "comment": "open; public; official; overt" },
	{ "question": "公用", "answers": [ "こうよう" ], "comment": "government business; official business\npublic; official; governmental" },
	{ "question": "公立", "answers": [ "こうりつ" ], "comment": "public (institution)" },
	{ "question": "公認", "answers": [ "こうにん" ], "comment": "official recognition; authorization; authorisation; licence; license; accreditation" },
	{ "question": "公開", "answers": [ "こうかい" ], "comment": "opening to the public; making available to the public; putting on display; exhibiting; showing (play, movie, etc.); holding (interview, etc.); open; public" },
	{ "question": "共", "answers": [ "とも", "きょう" ], "comment": "first-person plural (or singular)\nsecond or third person plural (implies speaker is of higher status than those referred to)\ntogether with\nsame\nboth; all; neither; none\nincluding ...\nincluding...; with ...; inclusive of; ...and all\ntogether with ..." },
	{ "question": "共働き", "answers": [ "ともばたらき" ], "comment": "(husband and wife) both working; dual income" },
	{ "question": "共和", "answers": [ "きょうわ" ], "comment": "republican; cooperative" },
	{ "question": "共存", "answers": [ "きょうそん", "きょうぞん" ], "comment": "coexistence" },
	{ "question": "共学", "answers": [ "きょうがく" ], "comment": "coeducation" },
	{ "question": "共感", "answers": [ "きょうかん" ], "comment": "sympathy; empathy; response" },
	{ "question": "共産", "answers": [ "きょうさん" ], "comment": "communism\nCommunist Party" },
	{ "question": "共稼ぎ", "answers": [ "ともかせぎ" ], "comment": "working together; (husband and wife) earning a living together" },
	{ "question": "共鳴", "answers": [ "きょうめい" ], "comment": "resonance; sympathetic (sound); (being in) sympathy" },
	{ "question": "兵器", "answers": [ "へいき" ], "comment": "arms; weapons; ordnance" },
	{ "question": "兵士", "answers": [ "へいし" ], "comment": "soldier" },
	{ "question": "兼ねて", "answers": [ "かねて" ], "comment": "previously; already; for some time; for quite a while" },
	{ "question": "兼業", "answers": [ "けんぎょう" ], "comment": "side line; second business" },
	{ "question": "兼用", "answers": [ "けんよう" ], "comment": "multi-use; combined use; combination; serving two purposes" },
	{ "question": "内乱", "answers": [ "ないらん" ], "comment": "civil war; insurrection; rebellion; domestic conflict" },
	{ "question": "内臓", "answers": [ "ないぞう" ], "comment": "internal organs; intestines; viscera" },
	{ "question": "内訳", "answers": [ "うちわけ" ], "comment": "itemization (of expenses); the items; breakdown; classification" },
	{ "question": "内部", "answers": [ "ないぶ" ], "comment": "interior; inside; internal" },
	{ "question": "内閣", "answers": [ "ないかく" ], "comment": "cabinet; (government) ministry" },
	{ "question": "内陸", "answers": [ "ないりく" ], "comment": "inland" },
	{ "question": "円満", "answers": [ "えんまん" ], "comment": "perfection; harmony; peace; smoothness; completeness; satisfaction; integrity" },
	{ "question": "円滑", "answers": [ "えんかつ" ], "comment": "smooth; undisturbed; uninterrupted; harmonious" },
	{ "question": "冊", "answers": [ "さつ" ], "comment": "counter for books\nvolume\nimperial edict to confer nobility titles (in ancient China)" },
	{ "question": "再び", "answers": [ "ふたたび" ], "comment": "again; once more; a second time" },
	{ "question": "再会", "answers": [ "さいかい" ], "comment": "another meeting; meeting again; reunion" },
	{ "question": "再建", "answers": [ "さいけん" ], "comment": "rebuilding; reconstruction; rehabilitation\nprotoform reconstruction\n(temple or shrine) rebuilding" },
	{ "question": "再現", "answers": [ "さいげん" ], "comment": "reappearance; reproduction; return; revival" },
	{ "question": "再生", "answers": [ "さいせい" ], "comment": "resuscitation; regeneration; restoration to life\nreformation; rehabilitation\nplayback; regeneration (sound, etc.); view (of a video clip)\nreclamation; recovery\nrebirth; reincarnation" },
	{ "question": "再発", "answers": [ "さいはつ" ], "comment": "return; relapse; reoccurrence" },
	{ "question": "冒頭", "answers": [ "ぼうとう" ], "comment": "beginning; start; outset" },
	{ "question": "写し", "answers": [ "うつし" ], "comment": "copy; duplicate; facsimile; transcript" },
	{ "question": "冠", "answers": [ "かん", "かんむり" ], "comment": "cap (esp. a traditional cap worn with sokutai or ikan clothing); crown; diadem; coronet\ntop kanji radical\nfirst verse of a haikai, etc.\nbest; peerless; first\nname; title; named sponsorship of a program, event, team, etc.\norder; rank" },
	{ "question": "冬眠", "answers": [ "とうみん" ], "comment": "hibernation; winter sleep" },
	{ "question": "冷やかす", "answers": [ "ひやかす" ], "comment": "to banter; to make fun of; to jeer at\nto cool; to refrigerate\nto window-shop; to look at without buying" },
	{ "question": "冷房", "answers": [ "れいぼう" ], "comment": "cooling; air-conditioning" },
	{ "question": "冷淡", "answers": [ "れいたん" ], "comment": "coolness; indifference" },
	{ "question": "冷蔵", "answers": [ "れいぞう" ], "comment": "cold storage; refrigeration" },
	{ "question": "冷酷", "answers": [ "れいこく" ], "comment": "cruelty; coldheartedness; relentless; ruthless" },
	{ "question": "凄い", "answers": [ "すごい" ], "comment": "terrible; dreadful\namazing (e.g. of strength); great (e.g. of skills); wonderful; terrific\nto a great extent; vast (in numbers)" },
	{ "question": "凝らす", "answers": [ "こらす", "こごらす" ], "comment": "to freeze; to congeal\nto concentrate one's attention on; to devote oneself to something; to ponder; to meditate\nto concentrate; to devote; to apply; to strain; to rack" },
	{ "question": "凝る", "answers": [ "こる", "しこる", "こごる" ], "comment": "to congeal; to freeze\nto grow stiff\nto be absorbed in; to be devoted to; to be a fanatic; to elaborate\nto stiffen; to harden" },
	{ "question": "処分", "answers": [ "しょぶん" ], "comment": "disposal; dealing (with a problem); disposition; measure; procedure\npunishment\nputting down (e.g. diseased animal)" },
	{ "question": "処置", "answers": [ "しょち" ], "comment": "measure; step; dealing with\nmedical treatment" },
	{ "question": "処罰", "answers": [ "しょばつ" ], "comment": "punishment" },
	{ "question": "凶作", "answers": [ "きょうさく" ], "comment": "bad harvest; poor crop" },
	{ "question": "出世", "answers": [ "しゅっせ" ], "comment": "success in life; getting ahead; successful career; promotion; climbing the corporate ladder; eminence" },
	{ "question": "出入り口", "answers": [ "でいりぐち" ], "comment": "exit and entrance" },
	{ "question": "出切る", "answers": [ "できる" ], "comment": "to be out of; to have no more at hand" },
	{ "question": "出動", "answers": [ "しゅつどう" ], "comment": "sailing; marching; going out; dispatch" },
	{ "question": "出合う", "answers": [ "であう" ], "comment": "to meet (by chance); to come across; to run across; to encounter; to happen upon\nto meet (e.g. of rivers, highways, etc.)\nto emerge and engage (an enemy)" },
	{ "question": "出品", "answers": [ "しゅっぴん" ], "comment": "exhibit; display; putting up for sale" },
	{ "question": "出来物", "answers": [ "できもの", "できぶつ" ], "comment": "tumour; tumor; growth; boil; ulcer; abscess; rash; pimple\nable man; fine man" },
	{ "question": "出演", "answers": [ "しゅつえん" ], "comment": "performance; stage appearance\nto act (in a play)" },
	{ "question": "出生", "answers": [ "しゅっしょう", "しゅっせい" ], "comment": "birth" },
	{ "question": "出産", "answers": [ "しゅっさん" ], "comment": "childbirth; (giving) birth; delivery; parturition; confinement\nproduction (of goods)" },
	{ "question": "出直し", "answers": [ "でなおし" ], "comment": "adjustment; touch up" },
	{ "question": "出社", "answers": [ "しゅっしゃ" ], "comment": "going to work (e.g. in the morning); coming to work" },
	{ "question": "出血", "answers": [ "しゅっけつ" ], "comment": "bleeding; haemorrhage; hemorrhage\nbleeding money; red ink; selling below cost" },
	{ "question": "出費", "answers": [ "しゅっぴ" ], "comment": "expenses; disbursements" },
	{ "question": "出題", "answers": [ "しゅつだい" ], "comment": "setting a question (for an exam)\nsetting a theme (for composition of poetry)" },
	{ "question": "刃", "answers": [ "やいば", "は" ], "comment": "edge (of a knife or sword)\nprong (of an electrical plug)\nblade; sword\nforged blade; wavy pattern on forged blades\nsharpness\nunhulled rice" },
	{ "question": "分", "answers": [ "ふん", "ぶん", "ぶ" ], "comment": "minute\nfun (one tenth of a monme, 5.787 grains)\none-tenth; one percent (one-tenth of a wari); 3 mm (one-tenth of a sun); 2.4 mm (one-tenth of a mon, a traditional unit used to measure shoe sizes); 0.1 degree (one-tenth of a do, used to measure body temperature on any temperature scale)\none-quarter of a ryou (obsolete unit of currency)\nthickness\nadvantageous circumstances\none-tenth of a monme of silver\npart; segment; share; ration\nrate\ndegree; one's lot; one's status; relation; duty; kind; lot\nin proportion to; just as much as" },
	{ "question": "分子", "answers": [ "ぶんし" ], "comment": "numerator\nmolecule\nmember; element" },
	{ "question": "分散", "answers": [ "ぶんさん" ], "comment": "dispersion; breakup; scattering; decentralization; decentralisation; distribution\nvariance\ndispersion" },
	{ "question": "分業", "answers": [ "ぶんぎょう" ], "comment": "division of labor; division of labour; specialization; specialisation; assembly-line production" },
	{ "question": "分母", "answers": [ "ぶんぼ" ], "comment": "denominator" },
	{ "question": "分裂", "answers": [ "ぶんれつ" ], "comment": "split; division; break up" },
	{ "question": "分配", "answers": [ "ぶんぱい" ], "comment": "division; splitting; sharing; distribution; dissemination; allocation" },
	{ "question": "分離", "answers": [ "ぶんり" ], "comment": "separation; partition; detachment; segregation; isolation" },
	{ "question": "切っ掛け", "answers": [ "きっかけ" ], "comment": "chance; start; cue; excuse; motive; impetus; occasion" },
	{ "question": "切ない", "answers": [ "せつない" ], "comment": "painful; heartrending; trying\noppressive; suffocating; miserable" },
	{ "question": "切り", "answers": [ "きり" ], "comment": "end; finish; stop\nbounds; limits\ndelivery date (of a futures contract)\nfinale (of a noh song); end of an act (in joruri or kabuki); final performance of the day (in vaudeville)\ncounter for slices (esp. thick slices); counter for cuts (e.g. fish, meat)\nonly; just\nsince; after\nremaining (in a particular state)" },
	{ "question": "切り替える", "answers": [ "きりかえる" ], "comment": "to change; to exchange; to convert; to renew; to throw a switch; to replace; to switch over" },
	{ "question": "切れ目", "answers": [ "きれめ" ], "comment": "break; pause; gap; end; rift; interruption; cut; section; notch; incision; end (of a task)" },
	{ "question": "切実", "answers": [ "せつじつ" ], "comment": "earnest; sincere; acute; keen; fervent\npressing; urgent; serious; severe\npertinent; appropriate" },
	{ "question": "切開", "answers": [ "せっかい" ], "comment": "incision; operation; section" },
	{ "question": "刊行", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "publication; issue" },
	{ "question": "刑", "answers": [ "けい" ], "comment": "penalty; sentence; punishment" },
	{ "question": "刑罰", "answers": [ "けいばつ" ], "comment": "judgement; judgment; penalty; punishment" },
	{ "question": "初版", "answers": [ "しょはん" ], "comment": "first edition" },
	{ "question": "初耳", "answers": [ "はつみみ" ], "comment": "something heard for the first time; hearing something for the first time" },
	{ "question": "初陣", "answers": [ "ういじん" ], "comment": "first campaign; one's first battle" },
	{ "question": "判", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "seal; stamp; monogram signature\njudgment; judgement\nsize (of paper or books)" },
	{ "question": "判定", "answers": [ "はんてい" ], "comment": "judgement; judgment; decision; adjudication; award; verdict; determination" },
	{ "question": "判決", "answers": [ "はんけつ" ], "comment": "judicial decision; judgement; judgment; sentence; decree" },
	{ "question": "利子", "answers": [ "りし" ], "comment": "interest (bank)" },
	{ "question": "利息", "answers": [ "りそく" ], "comment": "interest (bank)" },
	{ "question": "利根", "answers": [ "りこん" ], "comment": "intelligence; cleverness; innate aptitude" },
	{ "question": "利潤", "answers": [ "りじゅん" ], "comment": "profit; returns" },
	{ "question": "利点", "answers": [ "りてん" ], "comment": "advantage; point in favor; point in favour" },
	{ "question": "到底", "answers": [ "とうてい" ], "comment": "by no means; not at all; (cannot) possibly; utterly; absolutely" },
	{ "question": "到達", "answers": [ "とうたつ" ], "comment": "reaching; attaining; arrival" },
	{ "question": "制", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "system; organization; organisation; imperial command; laws; regulation; control; government; suppression; restraint; holding back; establishment" },
	{ "question": "制する", "answers": [ "せいする" ], "comment": "to hold back (e.g. emotions); to rein in (e.g. a horse, unruly people); to bridle\nto get the better of\nto control; to command" },
	{ "question": "制定", "answers": [ "せいてい" ], "comment": "enactment; establishment; creation" },
	{ "question": "制服", "answers": [ "せいふく" ], "comment": "uniform" },
	{ "question": "制約", "answers": [ "せいやく" ], "comment": "limitation; restriction; condition; constraints" },
	{ "question": "制裁", "answers": [ "せいさい" ], "comment": "restraint; sanctions; punishment" },
	{ "question": "刷り", "answers": [ "すり" ], "comment": "printing" },
	{ "question": "刺", "answers": [ "とげ", "し" ], "comment": "thorn; spine; prickle\nsplinter (esp. lodged in one's flesh); hard sharp item (esp. lodged in one's throat, e.g. fish bone)\nbiting words\ncalling card" },
	{ "question": "削減", "answers": [ "さくげん" ], "comment": "cut; reduction; curtailment" },
	{ "question": "前", "answers": [ "まえ" ], "comment": "previous; prior; former; first; earlier; some time ago; preceding\npoint (e.g. pencil); tip; end; nozzle\nhead (of a line); front\nahead; the other side\nthe future; hereafter\ndestination\nthe other party\nthe last (i.e. immediately preceding) (e.g. \"the last mayor\"); previous; one-time; former\npre- (e.g. \"premodern\")\nbefore; earlier\nago; before (some event); previously; (minutes) to (the hour)\nin front (of); before (e.g. the house)\nhead (of a line); front (e.g. of a bus); fore part\nin the presence of\nhelping; portion\nprivates; private parts" },
	{ "question": "前もって", "answers": [ "まえもって" ], "comment": "in advance; beforehand; previously" },
	{ "question": "前例", "answers": [ "ぜんれい" ], "comment": "precedent" },
	{ "question": "前売り", "answers": [ "まえうり" ], "comment": "advance sale; booking" },
	{ "question": "前提", "answers": [ "ぜんてい" ], "comment": "preamble; premise; reason; prerequisite; condition; assumption; hypothesis; given" },
	{ "question": "前置き", "answers": [ "まえおき" ], "comment": "preface; introduction" },
	{ "question": "前途", "answers": [ "ぜんと" ], "comment": "future prospects; outlook; the journey ahead" },
	{ "question": "剥がす", "answers": [ "はがす" ], "comment": "to tear off; to peel off; to rip off; to strip off; to skin; to flay; to disrobe; to deprive of; to detach; to disconnect" },
	{ "question": "剥ぐ", "answers": [ "はぐ" ], "comment": "to tear off; to peel off; to rip off; to strip off; to skin; to flay; to bark; to disrobe\nto strip of (e.g. clothes, rank); to deprive of; to divest" },
	{ "question": "剥げる", "answers": [ "はげる" ], "comment": "to come off; to be worn off\nto fade; to discolor; to discolour\nto peel off" },
	{ "question": "副", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "assistant; associate; vice-; sub-; deputy; substitute; auxiliary; supplementary; additional; collateral\nduplicate; copy\nadverb" },
	{ "question": "割", "answers": [ "わり", "かつ" ], "comment": "rate; ratio; proportion; percentage\nprofit\nassignment\n10%; unit of ten percent\nmatch; schedule of matches\ndiluted with (of drinks); mixed with" },
	{ "question": "割り当て", "answers": [ "わりあて" ], "comment": "allotment; assignment; allocation; quota; rationing\nallocation" },
	{ "question": "割り算", "answers": [ "わりざん" ], "comment": "division" },
	{ "question": "割り込む", "answers": [ "わりこむ" ], "comment": "to cut in; to thrust oneself into; to wedge oneself in; to muscle in on; to interrupt; to disturb" },
	{ "question": "割合に", "answers": [ "わりあいに" ], "comment": "comparatively" },
	{ "question": "割引き", "answers": [ "わりびき" ], "comment": "discount; reduction; rebate; (after a number) tenths discounted; tenths reduced" },
	{ "question": "創刊", "answers": [ "そうかん" ], "comment": "launching (e.g. newspaper); first issue" },
	{ "question": "創立", "answers": [ "そうりつ" ], "comment": "establishment; founding; organization; organisation" },
	{ "question": "創造", "answers": [ "そうぞう" ], "comment": "creation" },
	{ "question": "劇団", "answers": [ "げきだん" ], "comment": "troupe; theatrical company" },
	{ "question": "加入", "answers": [ "かにゅう" ], "comment": "becoming a member; joining; entry; admission; subscription; affiliation; adherence; signing" },
	{ "question": "加味", "answers": [ "かみ" ], "comment": "seasoning; flavoring; flavouring\naddition; inclusion; taking into account" },
	{ "question": "加工", "answers": [ "かこう" ], "comment": "manufacturing; processing; treatment; machining" },
	{ "question": "助", "answers": [ "すけ" ], "comment": "help; rescue; assistant\nassistance; help; helper\nbabe; chick; broad" },
	{ "question": "助け", "answers": [ "たすけ" ], "comment": "assistance; help; aid; support; reinforcement" },
	{ "question": "助動詞", "answers": [ "じょどうし" ], "comment": "auxiliary verb" },
	{ "question": "助言", "answers": [ "じょげん" ], "comment": "advice; suggestion" },
	{ "question": "助詞", "answers": [ "じょし" ], "comment": "particle; postposition" },
	{ "question": "努めて", "answers": [ "つとめて" ], "comment": "as much as possible; as far as possible; to the best of one's ability; diligently" },
	{ "question": "励ます", "answers": [ "はげます" ], "comment": "to encourage; to cheer; to raise (the voice)" },
	{ "question": "励む", "answers": [ "はげむ" ], "comment": "to strive; to endeavour; to endeavor; to make an effort; to be zealous" },
	{ "question": "労力", "answers": [ "ろうりょく" ], "comment": "labour; labor; effort; toil; trouble" },
	{ "question": "効き目", "answers": [ "ききめ" ], "comment": "effect; virtue; efficacy; impression" },
	{ "question": "効率", "answers": [ "こうりつ" ], "comment": "efficiency; efficacy; performance; utility factor" },
	{ "question": "勇敢", "answers": [ "ゆうかん" ], "comment": "brave; heroic; gallant" },
	{ "question": "動力", "answers": [ "どうりょく" ], "comment": "power; motive power; dynamic force\nthree-phase electricity" },
	{ "question": "動向", "answers": [ "どうこう" ], "comment": "trend; tendency; movement; attitude" },
	{ "question": "動員", "answers": [ "どういん" ], "comment": "mobilization; mobilisation" },
	{ "question": "動揺", "answers": [ "どうよう" ], "comment": "shaking; trembling; pitching; rolling; oscillation\ndisturbance; unrest; agitation; excitement; commotion; turmoil; discomposure; feeling shaken" },
	{ "question": "動機", "answers": [ "どうき" ], "comment": "motive; incentive\nmotif" },
	{ "question": "動的", "answers": [ "どうてき" ], "comment": "dynamic; kinetic" },
	{ "question": "勘弁", "answers": [ "かんべん" ], "comment": "pardon; forgiveness; forbearance" },
	{ "question": "勝る", "answers": [ "まさる" ], "comment": "to excel; to surpass; to exceed; to have an edge; to be superior; to outrival\nto outweigh; to preponderate" },
	{ "question": "勝利", "answers": [ "しょうり" ], "comment": "victory; triumph; conquest; success; win" },
	{ "question": "募る", "answers": [ "つのる" ], "comment": "to grow violent; to become stronger; to become worse\nto invite contributions, etc.; to solicit help, participation, etc.; to recruit (e.g. soldiers)" },
	{ "question": "募金", "answers": [ "ぼきん" ], "comment": "fund-raising; collection of funds" },
	{ "question": "勢力", "answers": [ "せいりょく" ], "comment": "influence; power; might; strength; potency; force; energy" },
	{ "question": "勤まる", "answers": [ "つとまる" ], "comment": "to be fit for; to be equal to; to function properly" },
	{ "question": "勤め先", "answers": [ "つとめさき" ], "comment": "place of work" },
	{ "question": "勤労", "answers": [ "きんろう" ], "comment": "labor; labour; exertion; diligent service" },
	{ "question": "勤勉", "answers": [ "きんべん" ], "comment": "diligent; industrious" },
	{ "question": "勤務", "answers": [ "きんむ" ], "comment": "service; duty; work" },
	{ "question": "勧め", "answers": [ "すすめ" ], "comment": "recommendation; advice; suggestion; encouragement" },
	{ "question": "勧告", "answers": [ "かんこく" ], "comment": "advice; counsel; remonstrance; recommendation" },
	{ "question": "勧誘", "answers": [ "かんゆう" ], "comment": "invitation; solicitation; canvassing; canvasing; inducement; persuasion; encouragement" },
	{ "question": "包む", "answers": [ "つつむ", "くるむ" ], "comment": "to wrap up; to tuck in; to pack; to do up; to cover with; to dress in\nto conceal; to hide; to be engulfed in; to be enveloped by\nto wrap up; to tuck in; to pack; to do up; to cover with; to dress in" },
	{ "question": "化ける", "answers": [ "ばける" ], "comment": "to take the form of (esp. in ref. to a spirit, fox, raccoon dog, etc.); to assume the shape of; to turn oneself into; to transform oneself into\nto disguise oneself as\nto change radically; to metamorphose\nto improve unexpectedly and dramatically (esp. of an actor, artist, rikishi, etc.)\nto age; to grow old (esp. in appearance); to show marks of age" },
	{ "question": "化する", "answers": [ "かする" ], "comment": "to change into; to convert into; to transform; to be reduced; to influence; to improve (someone)" },
	{ "question": "化合", "answers": [ "かごう" ], "comment": "chemical combination" },
	{ "question": "化石", "answers": [ "かせき" ], "comment": "fossil; petrifaction; fossilization; fossilisation" },
	{ "question": "化繊", "answers": [ "かせん" ], "comment": "synthetic fibres; synthetic fibers" },
	{ "question": "匹", "answers": [ "ひき" ], "comment": "counter for small animals\ncounter for rolls of cloth (two han in size)\ncounter for horses\nroll of cloth" },
	{ "question": "匹敵", "answers": [ "ひってき" ], "comment": "to be a match for; to rival; to equal; to compare with; to be equivalent to" },
	{ "question": "区", "answers": [ "く" ], "comment": "ward; district; section" },
	{ "question": "区々", "answers": [ "まちまち", "くく" ], "comment": "petty; trivial; insignificant; trifling\nseveral; various; divergent; conflicting; different; diverse" },
	{ "question": "区切り", "answers": [ "くぎり" ], "comment": "punctuation; pause; juncture\nend; (place to) stop" },
	{ "question": "区画", "answers": [ "くかく" ], "comment": "division; section; compartment; boundary; area; block" },
	{ "question": "区間", "answers": [ "くかん" ], "comment": "section (of track, etc.); segment; dimension\ninterval" },
	{ "question": "十分", "answers": [ "じゅうぶん", "じゅっぷん", "じっぷん" ], "comment": "10 minutes\nplenty; enough; sufficient; satisfactory; adequate\ndivision into ten\nperfectly; thoroughly; fully; in full" },
	{ "question": "十字路", "answers": [ "じゅうじろ" ], "comment": "crossroads" },
	{ "question": "半端", "answers": [ "はんぱ" ], "comment": "remnant; fragment; incomplete set; incompleteness\nfraction; odd sum\nhalfway; half-hearted; perfunctory\nirresponsible; foolish" },
	{ "question": "卑しい", "answers": [ "いやしい" ], "comment": "lowborn; humble; lowly\nvulgar; coarse; crude; mean; base; vile\nshabby\ngreedy; gluttonous; avaricious" },
	{ "question": "協会", "answers": [ "きょうかい" ], "comment": "association; society; organization; organisation" },
	{ "question": "協定", "answers": [ "きょうてい" ], "comment": "arrangement; pact; agreement" },
	{ "question": "協調", "answers": [ "きょうちょう" ], "comment": "cooperation; conciliation; harmony; coordination" },
	{ "question": "協議", "answers": [ "きょうぎ" ], "comment": "conference; consultation; discussion; negotiation" },
	{ "question": "単", "answers": [ "たん", "ひとえ" ], "comment": "one layer; single; onefold\nsingle; simple\nsingles (in tennis)\nwinning system (as in horse racing)" },
	{ "question": "単一", "answers": [ "たんいつ", "たんいち" ], "comment": "single; simple; sole; individual; unitary\nsize D (battery)" },
	{ "question": "単独", "answers": [ "たんどく" ], "comment": "sole; single; solo\nindependence; singleness; singularity" },
	{ "question": "単調", "answers": [ "たんちょう" ], "comment": "monotony; monotone; dullness\nmonotone; monotonic" },
	{ "question": "占領", "answers": [ "せんりょう" ], "comment": "occupying; having (an area) all to oneself\nmilitary occupation; possession; capture; seizure" },
	{ "question": "印", "answers": [ "いん", "しるし" ], "comment": "seal; stamp; mark; print\nmudra (symbolic hand gesture)\nIndia\nmark; sign\nsymbol; emblem\nbadge; crest; flag\nevidence; proof\ntoken (of gratitude, affection, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "印鑑", "answers": [ "いんかん" ], "comment": "stamp; seal" },
	{ "question": "危ぶむ", "answers": [ "あやぶむ" ], "comment": "to fear; to have misgivings; to be doubtful; to mistrust" },
	{ "question": "危害", "answers": [ "きがい" ], "comment": "injury; harm; danger" },
	{ "question": "危機", "answers": [ "きき" ], "comment": "crisis; danger; risk" },
	{ "question": "即する", "answers": [ "そくする" ], "comment": "to conform to; to agree with; to be adapted to; to be based on" },
	{ "question": "原", "answers": [ "はら", "げん" ], "comment": "original; primitive; primary; fundamental; raw\nfield; plain; prairie; tundra; moor; wilderness\nsuffixed to words indicating a class of people to create a plural (esp. in impolite contexts)" },
	{ "question": "原っぱ", "answers": [ "はらっぱ" ], "comment": "open field; empty lot; plain" },
	{ "question": "原作", "answers": [ "げんさく" ], "comment": "original work" },
	{ "question": "原典", "answers": [ "げんてん" ], "comment": "original (text)" },
	{ "question": "原則", "answers": [ "げんそく" ], "comment": "principle; general rule" },
	{ "question": "原子", "answers": [ "げんし" ], "comment": "atom" },
	{ "question": "原形", "answers": [ "げんけい" ], "comment": "original form; base form" },
	{ "question": "原文", "answers": [ "げんぶん" ], "comment": "the text; original" },
	{ "question": "原書", "answers": [ "げんしょ" ], "comment": "original document (not a copy or adaptation); book in its original language (esp. a European language)" },
	{ "question": "原油", "answers": [ "げんゆ" ], "comment": "crude oil" },
	{ "question": "原点", "answers": [ "げんてん" ], "comment": "origin (coordinates); starting point" },
	{ "question": "原爆", "answers": [ "げんばく" ], "comment": "atomic bomb; A-bomb" },
	{ "question": "厳か", "answers": [ "おごそか" ], "comment": "solemn (ceremony, atmosphere, etc.); austere; grave; majestic; dignified; stately; impressive" },
	{ "question": "厳密", "answers": [ "げんみつ" ], "comment": "strict; close" },
	{ "question": "参上", "answers": [ "さんじょう" ], "comment": "calling on; visiting" },
	{ "question": "参照", "answers": [ "さんしょう" ], "comment": "reference; bibliographical reference; consultation; browsing (e.g. when selecting a file to upload on a computer); checking out" },
	{ "question": "参議院", "answers": [ "さんぎいん" ], "comment": "House of Councillors" },
	{ "question": "及び", "answers": [ "および" ], "comment": "and; as well as" },
	{ "question": "及ぶ", "answers": [ "およぶ" ], "comment": "to reach; to amount to; to befall; to happen to; to extend\nto be up to the task; to come up to\nto compare with; to be a match (for)\nto commit (a crime)\nto require (to do) (usu. used in the negative)" },
	{ "question": "反", "answers": [ "はん", "ほん", "たん" ], "comment": "variable measure of fabric (28.8 cm in width); for kimonos: at least 10 m in length; for haori: at least 7.27 m in length; for other clothes: at least 6.06 m in length\n300 tsubo (991.74 meters square, 0.24506 acres)\nsix ken (10.91 m)\nanti-\nantithesis\nfanqie; traditional Chinese spelling system in which two characters are used: the first one for the onset, the second one for rhyme and tone" },
	{ "question": "反する", "answers": [ "はんする" ], "comment": "to be contrary to; to be inconsistent with; to contradict\nto act contrary to (rules or guidelines); to violate; to transgress\nto oppose; to rebel; to revolt" },
	{ "question": "反り", "answers": [ "そり" ], "comment": "warp; curvature; curve; arch\nturning over; flipping over\nreply; response\nmarks indicating the Japanese meaning of the texts of Chinese classics\nlapel" },
	{ "question": "反乱", "answers": [ "はんらん" ], "comment": "insurrection; mutiny; rebellion; revolt; uprising" },
	{ "question": "反射", "answers": [ "はんしゃ" ], "comment": "reflection; reverberation\nreflex; reflexes" },
	{ "question": "反応", "answers": [ "はんのう" ], "comment": "reaction; response" },
	{ "question": "反感", "answers": [ "はんかん" ], "comment": "antipathy; antagonism; animosity; revulsion; ill feeling" },
	{ "question": "反撃", "answers": [ "はんげき" ], "comment": "counterattack; counteroffensive; counterblow" },
	{ "question": "反発", "answers": [ "はんぱつ" ], "comment": "opposition; rebellion; revolt; resistance; backlash; refusal\nrebounding; recoiling; repulsion\nrally (e.g. in stock prices); recovery" },
	{ "question": "反省", "answers": [ "はんせい" ], "comment": "reflection; reconsideration; introspection; meditation; contemplation\nregret; repentance; remorse; being sorry" },
	{ "question": "反響", "answers": [ "はんきょう" ], "comment": "echo; reverberation\nrepercussion; reaction; response; influence" },
	{ "question": "収まる", "answers": [ "おさまる" ], "comment": "to be in one's place; to be installed; to settle into\nto be delivered; to be obtained; to be paid\nto be settled; to be sorted out\nto lessen (e.g. of storms, pain); to calm down\nto be fit tightly into (e.g. a frame); to be sheathed (in a scabbard)" },
	{ "question": "収容", "answers": [ "しゅうよう" ], "comment": "accommodation; reception; housing\nseating\ncustody (e.g. awaiting deportation); internment\nadmission; hospitalization\nentering (e.g. in dictionary)" },
	{ "question": "収支", "answers": [ "しゅうし" ], "comment": "income and expenditure" },
	{ "question": "収益", "answers": [ "しゅうえき" ], "comment": "earnings; proceeds; returns; revenue" },
	{ "question": "収集", "answers": [ "しゅうしゅう" ], "comment": "gathering up; collection; accumulation" },
	{ "question": "取っ手", "answers": [ "とって" ], "comment": "handle; grip; knob" },
	{ "question": "取りあえず", "answers": [ "とりあえず" ], "comment": "first of all; at once; right away\nfor now; for the time being" },
	{ "question": "取り分け", "answers": [ "とりわけ" ], "comment": "especially; above all\ninter alia; among others" },
	{ "question": "取り寄せる", "answers": [ "とりよせる" ], "comment": "to order; to send away for\nto pull something closer" },
	{ "question": "取り巻く", "answers": [ "とりまく" ], "comment": "to surround; to circle; to enclose" },
	{ "question": "取り引き", "answers": [ "とりひき" ], "comment": "transactions; dealings; business" },
	{ "question": "取り戻す", "answers": [ "とりもどす" ], "comment": "to take back; to regain; to get back; to recover" },
	{ "question": "取り扱い", "answers": [ "とりあつかい" ], "comment": "treatment; service; handling; management" },
	{ "question": "取り扱う", "answers": [ "とりあつかう" ], "comment": "to handle; to operate (a machine, etc.); to use\nto deal with (an issue); to manage\nto treat (someone); to deal with (someone)\nto deal in; to carry; to sell" },
	{ "question": "取り替え", "answers": [ "とりかえ" ], "comment": "swap; exchange" },
	{ "question": "取り次ぐ", "answers": [ "とりつぐ" ], "comment": "to act as an agent for; to intermediate\nto announce (someone's arrival); to answer (the door, the phone); to receive (a guest at reception); to usher in (a guest)\nto convey (a message)" },
	{ "question": "取り混ぜる", "answers": [ "とりまぜる" ], "comment": "to mix; to put together" },
	{ "question": "取り立てる", "answers": [ "とりたてる" ], "comment": "to collect (debts); to dun; to exact; to extort\nto appoint; to promote; to give patronage\nto emphasize; to focus on; to call attention to" },
	{ "question": "取り組む", "answers": [ "とりくむ" ], "comment": "to tackle; to wrestle with; to engage in a bout; to come to grips with; to make effort; to strive for; to deal with" },
	{ "question": "取り締まり", "answers": [ "とりしまり" ], "comment": "control; management; supervision" },
	{ "question": "取り締まる", "answers": [ "とりしまる" ], "comment": "to manage; to control; to supervise; to crack down on" },
	{ "question": "取り調べる", "answers": [ "とりしらべる" ], "comment": "to investigate; to examine" },
	{ "question": "取り除く", "answers": [ "とりのぞく" ], "comment": "to remove; to deinstall; to take away; to set apart" },
	{ "question": "取材", "answers": [ "しゅざい" ], "comment": "news coverage; collecting data (e.g. for an article); covering (something for media)\ninterview" },
	{ "question": "受かる", "answers": [ "うかる" ], "comment": "to pass (examination)" },
	{ "question": "受け付ける", "answers": [ "うけつける" ], "comment": "to accept; to receive (an application); to take up\nto withstand; to tolerate; to bear" },
	{ "question": "受け入れ", "answers": [ "うけいれ" ], "comment": "receiving; acceptance; reception" },
	{ "question": "受け入れる", "answers": [ "うけいれる" ], "comment": "to accept; to receive; to agree" },
	{ "question": "受け取り", "answers": [ "うけとり" ], "comment": "receipt" },
	{ "question": "受け止める", "answers": [ "うけとめる" ], "comment": "to catch; to stop the blow\nto react to; to take (advice, etc.); to accept; to come to grips with" },
	{ "question": "受け継ぐ", "answers": [ "うけつぐ" ], "comment": "to inherit; to succeed; to take over" },
	{ "question": "受身", "answers": [ "うけみ" ], "comment": "the defensive\npassive attitude; passivity; passiveness\nthe passive; passive voice\nukemi (the art of falling safely)" },
	{ "question": "口述", "answers": [ "こうじゅつ" ], "comment": "dictation; verbal statement" },
	{ "question": "口頭", "answers": [ "こうとう" ], "comment": "oral; verbal; parol" },
	{ "question": "古", "answers": [ "こ", "ふる", "いにしえ" ], "comment": "antiquity; ancient times\nused item; secondhand item\nold; used; previous" },
	{ "question": "古代", "answers": [ "こだい" ], "comment": "ancient times" },
	{ "question": "叫び", "answers": [ "さけび" ], "comment": "shout; scream; outcry" },
	{ "question": "召す", "answers": [ "めす" ], "comment": "to call; to invite; to send for; to summon\nto eat; to drink\nto put on; to wear\nto ride\nto catch (a cold); to take (a bath); to tickle (one's fancy); to put on (years); to commit (seppuku)\nto do\nhonorific suffix used after the -masu stem of a verb" },
	{ "question": "可哀想", "answers": [ "かわいそう" ], "comment": "poor; pitiable; pathetic; pitiful" },
	{ "question": "可愛い", "answers": [ "かわいい" ], "comment": "cute; adorable; charming; lovely; pretty\ndear; precious; darling; pet\ncute little; tiny" },
	{ "question": "可愛がる", "answers": [ "かわいがる" ], "comment": "to love; to be affectionate; to favor; to favour; to be partial to\nto torment; to tease; to be rough with" },
	{ "question": "可愛らしい", "answers": [ "かわいらしい" ], "comment": "lovely; sweet" },
	{ "question": "台本", "answers": [ "だいほん" ], "comment": "script; libretto; scenario" },
	{ "question": "台無し", "answers": [ "だいなし" ], "comment": "mess; spoiled; spoilt; (come to) nothing; ruin" },
	{ "question": "号", "answers": [ "ごう" ], "comment": "number; edition; make; model; issue; part of that group\nsobriquet; pen-name\nsuffix attached to names of ships, trains, airplanes, etc." },
	{ "question": "司法", "answers": [ "しほう" ], "comment": "administration of justice" },
	{ "question": "各々", "answers": [ "おのおの" ], "comment": "each\nyou (plural)" },
	{ "question": "各種", "answers": [ "かくしゅ" ], "comment": "every kind; all sorts" },
	{ "question": "合わす", "answers": [ "あわす" ], "comment": "to match (rhythm, speed, etc.)\nto join together; to unite; to combine; to add up\nto face; to be opposite (someone)\nto compare; to check with\nto cause to meet (e.g. an unpleasant fate)\nto place together; to connect; to overlap\nto mix; to combine\nto put blade to blade; to fight" },
	{ "question": "合わせ", "answers": [ "あわせ" ], "comment": "joint together; opposite; facing" },
	{ "question": "合併", "answers": [ "がっぺい" ], "comment": "combination; union; amalgamation; consolidation; merger; coalition; fusion; annexation; affiliation; incorporation" },
	{ "question": "合唱", "answers": [ "がっしょう" ], "comment": "chorus; singing in a chorus" },
	{ "question": "合意", "answers": [ "ごうい" ], "comment": "agreement; consent; mutual understanding; accord; consensus" },
	{ "question": "合成", "answers": [ "ごうせい" ], "comment": "composition; synthesis\ncomposite; compound; synthetic; mixed; combined\n(function) composition" },
	{ "question": "合致", "answers": [ "がっち" ], "comment": "agreement; concurrence; conformance; compliance" },
	{ "question": "合議", "answers": [ "ごうぎ" ], "comment": "consultation; conference" },
	{ "question": "合間", "answers": [ "あいま" ], "comment": "interval; break; pause; spare moment" },
	{ "question": "同い年", "answers": [ "おないどし" ], "comment": "the same age" },
	{ "question": "同士", "answers": [ "どうし" ], "comment": "fellow; mutual; companion; comrade" },
	{ "question": "同封", "answers": [ "どうふう" ], "comment": "enclosing (e.g. with a letter)" },
	{ "question": "同居", "answers": [ "どうきょ" ], "comment": "coexistence; living together" },
	{ "question": "同志", "answers": [ "どうし" ], "comment": "like-mindedness; (being of the) same mind; shared sentiment\ncomrade; fellow; kindred soul" },
	{ "question": "同情", "answers": [ "どうじょう" ], "comment": "sympathy; compassion; feeling pity for" },
	{ "question": "同意", "answers": [ "どうい" ], "comment": "agreement; consent; same opinion; approval\nsame meaning" },
	{ "question": "同感", "answers": [ "どうかん" ], "comment": "agreement; same opinion; same feeling; sympathy; concurrence" },
	{ "question": "同盟", "answers": [ "どうめい" ], "comment": "alliance; union; league" },
	{ "question": "同等", "answers": [ "どうとう" ], "comment": "equality; equal; same rights; same rank; equivalence" },
	{ "question": "同級", "answers": [ "どうきゅう" ], "comment": "the same grade; same class" },
	{ "question": "同調", "answers": [ "どうちょう" ], "comment": "sympathy; agreement with; alignment; conformity; tuning" },
	{ "question": "名付ける", "answers": [ "なづける" ], "comment": "to name; to call; to christen; to term" },
	{ "question": "名札", "answers": [ "なふだ" ], "comment": "name plate; name tag; label" },
	{ "question": "名残", "answers": [ "なごり" ], "comment": "remains; traces; vestiges; relics\n(the sorrow of) parting\nend" },
	{ "question": "名産", "answers": [ "めいさん" ], "comment": "noted product; local specialty" },
	{ "question": "名称", "answers": [ "めいしょう" ], "comment": "name; title" },
	{ "question": "名簿", "answers": [ "めいぼ" ], "comment": "register of names; list of names; roll; register\nproof of identity (for nobles, doctors, etc.) (Heian period)" },
	{ "question": "名誉", "answers": [ "めいよ" ], "comment": "honor; honour; credit; prestige" },
	{ "question": "名高い", "answers": [ "なだかい" ], "comment": "famous; celebrated; well-known" },
	{ "question": "吐く", "answers": [ "はく" ], "comment": "to breathe out; to breathe\nto tell (a lie); to use (foul language)\nto vomit; to throw up; to spit up\nto vomit; to throw up; to spit up\nto emit; to send forth; to breathe out\nto give (an opinion); to make (a comment); to express; to tell\nto confess" },
	{ "question": "向上", "answers": [ "こうじょう" ], "comment": "elevation; rise; improvement; advancement; progress" },
	{ "question": "君主", "answers": [ "くんしゅ" ], "comment": "ruler; monarch; sovereign" },
	{ "question": "吟味", "answers": [ "ぎんみ" ], "comment": "close examination; careful selection; testing; scrutiny\nexamination of criminal charges\nreciting and appreciating traditional poetry" },
	{ "question": "否", "answers": [ "いな", "いや" ], "comment": "no; the noes\nno; nay\nwell; er; why\nyou're welcome; not at all; don't mention it" },
	{ "question": "否決", "answers": [ "ひけつ" ], "comment": "rejection; negation; voting down" },
	{ "question": "吹奏", "answers": [ "すいそう" ], "comment": "playing wind instruments" },
	{ "question": "告げる", "answers": [ "つげる" ], "comment": "to tell; to inform; to announce\nto indicate; to signal; to mark" },
	{ "question": "告白", "answers": [ "こくはく" ], "comment": "confession; acknowledgement; acknowledgment\nprofession of love\nconfession of sins (e.g. the confessional)" },
	{ "question": "周", "answers": [ "しゅう" ], "comment": "Zhou (dynasty of China); Chou\nperimeter\ncounter for laps or circuits" },
	{ "question": "周期", "answers": [ "しゅうき" ], "comment": "cycle; period" },
	{ "question": "味わい", "answers": [ "あじわい" ], "comment": "flavour; flavor\nmeaning; significance" },
	{ "question": "味覚", "answers": [ "みかく" ], "comment": "taste; palate; sense of taste" },
	{ "question": "呼び止める", "answers": [ "よびとめる" ], "comment": "to challenge; to call somebody to halt" },
	{ "question": "命中", "answers": [ "めいちゅう" ], "comment": "a hit; hitting something that was aimed at" },
	{ "question": "和", "answers": [ "わ" ], "comment": "calm (at sea); lull\nsum\nharmony; peace\nJapan; Japanese-style\nsoft; fragile; weak; poorly built; insubstantial\ntranquil; calm; quiet; peaceful" },
	{ "question": "和やか", "answers": [ "なごやか" ], "comment": "mild; calm; gentle; quiet; harmonious" },
	{ "question": "和らげる", "answers": [ "やわらげる" ], "comment": "to soften; to moderate; to relieve" },
	{ "question": "和文", "answers": [ "わぶん" ], "comment": "Japanese text; sentence in Japanese" },
	{ "question": "和風", "answers": [ "わふう" ], "comment": "Japanese style\nlight wind; moderate breeze" },
	{ "question": "品種", "answers": [ "ひんしゅ" ], "comment": "kind (of goods); brand\n(taxonomical) form\nbreed; cultivar" },
	{ "question": "品質", "answers": [ "ひんしつ" ], "comment": "(material) quality" },
	{ "question": "唐突", "answers": [ "とうとつ" ], "comment": "abrupt; sudden" },
	{ "question": "唱える", "answers": [ "となえる" ], "comment": "to recite; to chant\nto cry; to yell; to shout\nto advocate; to advance; to preach; to insist" },
	{ "question": "唾", "answers": [ "つば", "つばき" ], "comment": "saliva; spit; sputum" },
	{ "question": "商権", "answers": [ "しょうけん" ], "comment": "commercial supremacy; commercial rights" },
	{ "question": "問い合わせる", "answers": [ "といあわせる" ], "comment": "to enquire; to inquire; to seek information" },
	{ "question": "問う", "answers": [ "とう" ], "comment": "to ask; to inquire\nto charge (e.g. with a crime); to accuse\nwithout regard to; to not matter\nto call into question; to doubt; to question" },
	{ "question": "問屋", "answers": [ "といや", "とんや" ], "comment": "wholesale store" },
	{ "question": "善し悪し", "answers": [ "よしあし" ], "comment": "right or wrong; good or bad; merits or demerits; quality; suitability" },
	{ "question": "善良", "answers": [ "ぜんりょう" ], "comment": "goodness; excellence; virtue" },
	{ "question": "喜劇", "answers": [ "きげき" ], "comment": "comedy; funny show" },
	{ "question": "喫茶", "answers": [ "きっさ" ], "comment": "tea drinking\nteahouse; tearoom; coffee lounge; coffee shop; (rather formal) cafe" },
	{ "question": "営む", "answers": [ "いとなむ" ], "comment": "to run (a business); to operate; to conduct; to practice (law, medicine, etc.)\nto carry out; to perform; to lead (a life)\nto hold (a Buddhist or Shinto ceremony)" },
	{ "question": "嘆く", "answers": [ "なげく" ], "comment": "to lament; to grieve; to regret\nto deplore" },
	{ "question": "器", "answers": [ "うつわ" ], "comment": "bowl; vessel; container\nability; capacity; calibre; caliber\ndevice; instrument\nvessel; container" },
	{ "question": "器官", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "organ (of body, plant, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "噴出", "answers": [ "ふんしゅつ" ], "comment": "spewing; gushing; spouting; eruption; effusion" },
	{ "question": "回収", "answers": [ "かいしゅう" ], "comment": "collection; recovery; withdrawal; retrieval" },
	{ "question": "回覧", "answers": [ "かいらん" ], "comment": "circulation (esp. documents); sending round" },
	{ "question": "回路", "answers": [ "かいろ" ], "comment": "circuit (electric)\ncycle (e.g. Krebs cycle)" },
	{ "question": "回送", "answers": [ "かいそう" ], "comment": "forwarding; sending on; redirecting (e.g. mail)\ndeadheading (e.g. train)" },
	{ "question": "団結", "answers": [ "だんけつ" ], "comment": "unity; union; combination; teaming up" },
	{ "question": "図々しい", "answers": [ "ずうずうしい" ], "comment": "impudent; shameless" },
	{ "question": "図る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "to plan; to attempt; to devise\nto plot; to conspire; to scheme\nto aim for; to strive for; to work towards; to seek" },
	{ "question": "固める", "answers": [ "かためる" ], "comment": "to harden; to freeze; to strengthen; to solidify; to make (a fist); to tramp down (snow, dirt)\nto put together; to collect; to gather; to consolidate\nto make secure; to stabilize; to settle down; to strengthen (belief, resolution, etc.); to establish (evidence)\nto fortify; to reinforce; to support\nto wear for a specific purpose (armor, coat, etc.)\nto swear; to resolutely vow; to sincerely promise\nto tie tightly; to fasten\nto hold a bow fully drawn" },
	{ "question": "固体", "answers": [ "こたい" ], "comment": "solid (body); solid matter; solid-state" },
	{ "question": "固定", "answers": [ "こてい" ], "comment": "fixation; fixing (e.g. salary, capital)\nfixed handle" },
	{ "question": "固有", "answers": [ "こゆう" ], "comment": "characteristic; traditional; peculiar; inherent; native; eigen-" },
	{ "question": "国交", "answers": [ "こっこう" ], "comment": "diplomatic relations" },
	{ "question": "国土", "answers": [ "こくど" ], "comment": "country; territory; domain; realm" },
	{ "question": "国境", "answers": [ "こっきょう", "くにざかい" ], "comment": "national border; provincial border" },
	{ "question": "国定", "answers": [ "こくてい" ], "comment": "state-sponsored; national" },
	{ "question": "国有", "answers": [ "こくゆう" ], "comment": "national ownership" },
	{ "question": "国産", "answers": [ "こくさん" ], "comment": "domestic; domestically-produced; produced within a country" },
	{ "question": "国連", "answers": [ "こくれん" ], "comment": "United Nations; UN" },
	{ "question": "国防", "answers": [ "こくぼう" ], "comment": "national defence; national defense" },
	{ "question": "圏", "answers": [ "けん" ], "comment": "sphere; circle; range\ncategory (only in the context of \"category theory\")" },
	{ "question": "園", "answers": [ "その" ], "comment": "garden (esp. man-made); orchard; park; plantation\nplace; location" },
	{ "question": "土俵", "answers": [ "どひょう" ], "comment": "(wrestling) ring\nforum (e.g. for discussion)\nsandbag; gabion" },
	{ "question": "土台", "answers": [ "どだい" ], "comment": "foundation; base; basis\nfrom the beginning; from the outset; by nature" },
	{ "question": "土手", "answers": [ "どて" ], "comment": "embankment; bank\nbeef sinew stewed in miso and mirin" },
	{ "question": "土木", "answers": [ "どぼく" ], "comment": "engineering works; civil engineering; public works" },
	{ "question": "圧力", "answers": [ "あつりょく" ], "comment": "pressure; stress\ncoercion; arm-twisting" },
	{ "question": "圧迫", "answers": [ "あっぱく" ], "comment": "pressure\noppression; suppression" },
	{ "question": "在庫", "answers": [ "ざいこ" ], "comment": "inventory; stock; stockpile" },
	{ "question": "地主", "answers": [ "じぬし" ], "comment": "landlord; landowner" },
	{ "question": "地元", "answers": [ "じもと" ], "comment": "home area; home town\nlocal" },
	{ "question": "地形", "answers": [ "ちけい", "じぎょう" ], "comment": "terrain; geographical features; topography" },
	{ "question": "地方", "answers": [ "ちほう", "じかた" ], "comment": "district; region; area; locality\nthe country; countryside; the provinces; rural area\nperson in charge of music (in a Japanese dance performance)\nperson singing ballads (in noh)\ncoast (esp. as seen from the water); shore\nthe country; countryside; the provinces; rural area" },
	{ "question": "地獄", "answers": [ "じごく" ], "comment": "hell" },
	{ "question": "均衡", "answers": [ "きんこう" ], "comment": "equilibrium; balance" },
	{ "question": "坊ちゃん", "answers": [ "ぼっちゃん" ], "comment": "son (of others)\nyoung master\ngreen young man from a well-to-do family" },
	{ "question": "垂れる", "answers": [ "たれる" ], "comment": "to hang; to droop; to dangle; to sag; to lower; to pull down\nto leave behind (at death); to give; to confer\nto drip; to ooze; to trickle; to drop\nto droop; to hang down; to weep" },
	{ "question": "埋まる", "answers": [ "うまる", "うずまる" ], "comment": "to be buried; to be covered; to be surrounded\nto overflow; to be crowded; to be filled\nto be repaid (e.g. debt); to be replenished" },
	{ "question": "埋め込む", "answers": [ "うめこむ" ], "comment": "to bury; to embed; to implant" },
	{ "question": "埋蔵", "answers": [ "まいぞう" ], "comment": "burying in the ground\nhaving underground deposits" },
	{ "question": "城下", "answers": [ "じょうか" ], "comment": "land near a castle\ncastle town" },
	{ "question": "域外", "answers": [ "いきがい" ], "comment": "outside the area" },
	{ "question": "執着", "answers": [ "しゅうちゃく", "しゅうじゃく" ], "comment": "attachment; adhesion; tenacity; fixation; obsession" },
	{ "question": "基", "answers": [ "もと", "もとい" ], "comment": "origin; source\nbase; basis; foundation; root\ncause\ningredient; material\noriginal cost (or capital, principal, etc.)\n(plant) root; (tree) trunk\nfirst section of a waka\nhandle (chopsticks, brush, etc.); grip\ngroup\n(free) radical\ncounter for installed or mounted objects (e.g. stone lanterns, gravestones, satellites)\nbasis; foundation\ncause" },
	{ "question": "基金", "answers": [ "ききん" ], "comment": "fund; foundation" },
	{ "question": "堂々", "answers": [ "どうどう" ], "comment": "magnificent; grand; impressive; dignified; majestic; imposing; stately\nfair; square; open; unashamed; brazen\ngrandly; boldly; confidently\nfairly; squarely; unreservedly; brazenly" },
	{ "question": "堤防", "answers": [ "ていぼう" ], "comment": "bank; weir; embankment; levee" },
	{ "question": "堪える", "answers": [ "たえる", "こらえる", "こたえる" ], "comment": "to bear; to stand; to endure; to put up with\nto support; to withstand; to resist; to brave\nto be fit for; to be equal to" },
	{ "question": "堪らない", "answers": [ "たまらない" ], "comment": "intolerable; unbearable; unendurable\nirresistible; tremendous; out of this world\ncannot help (doing); cannot but do; anxious to do" },
	{ "question": "報じる", "answers": [ "ほうじる" ], "comment": "to inform; to report" },
	{ "question": "報ずる", "answers": [ "ほうずる" ], "comment": "to inform; to report" },
	{ "question": "報道", "answers": [ "ほうどう" ], "comment": "information; report; journalism; news\nto report" },
	{ "question": "報酬", "answers": [ "ほうしゅう" ], "comment": "remuneration; recompense; reward; toll" },
	{ "question": "塩", "answers": [ "しお", "えん" ], "comment": "salt (i.e. sodium chloride); common salt; table salt\nsalt (e.g. sodium chloride, calcium sulfate, etc.)\nhardship; toil; trouble\nsaltiness" },
	{ "question": "塾", "answers": [ "じゅく" ], "comment": "coaching school; cramming school; juku" },
	{ "question": "境遇", "answers": [ "きょうぐう" ], "comment": "environment; circumstances" },
	{ "question": "墓地", "answers": [ "ぼち", "はかち" ], "comment": "cemetery; graveyard" },
	{ "question": "増し", "answers": [ "まし" ], "comment": "better; less objectionable; preferable\nmore; increase; extra\nincrease; growth" },
	{ "question": "増強", "answers": [ "ぞうきょう" ], "comment": "augment; reinforce; increase" },
	{ "question": "増進", "answers": [ "ぞうしん" ], "comment": "promoting; increase; advance" },
	{ "question": "墜落", "answers": [ "ついらく" ], "comment": "falling; crashing" },
	{ "question": "壁", "answers": [ "かべ" ], "comment": "wall; partition\nbarrier; obstacle\nChinese \"Wall\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)" },
	{ "question": "壇", "answers": [ "だん" ], "comment": "platform; podium; rostrum\nmandala" },
	{ "question": "壊す", "answers": [ "こわす" ], "comment": "to break; to destroy; to demolish\nto wreck; to ruin; to spoil; to damage\nto break (a bill, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "壊れる", "answers": [ "こわれる" ], "comment": "to be broken; to break\nto fall through; to come to nothing" },
	{ "question": "壮大", "answers": [ "そうだい" ], "comment": "magnificent; grand; majestic; splendid" },
	{ "question": "声明", "answers": [ "せいめい" ], "comment": "declaration; statement; proclamation" },
	{ "question": "声質", "answers": [ "せいしつ" ], "comment": "voice quality; type of voice" },
	{ "question": "声高", "answers": [ "こわだか" ], "comment": "with a loud voice" },
	{ "question": "売り出し", "answers": [ "うりだし" ], "comment": "(bargain) sale" },
	{ "question": "売り出す", "answers": [ "うりだす" ], "comment": "to put on the market; to put out for sale; to put on sale; to begin selling; to market\nto become popular" },
	{ "question": "変動", "answers": [ "へんどう" ], "comment": "change; fluctuation" },
	{ "question": "変遷", "answers": [ "へんせん" ], "comment": "change; transition; vicissitudes" },
	{ "question": "変革", "answers": [ "へんかく" ], "comment": "change; transformation; innovation; reform; revolution; revolutionizing; upheaval\nReformation" },
	{ "question": "夕暮れ", "answers": [ "ゆうぐれ" ], "comment": "evening; dusk; twilight" },
	{ "question": "夕焼け", "answers": [ "ゆうやけ" ], "comment": "evening glow; red sunset; afterglow (of sunset)" },
	{ "question": "外方", "answers": [ "がいほう", "そっぽ" ], "comment": "the other way\noutside daimyo; non-Tokugawa daimyo\noutsider; one not included in the favored (favoured) group" },
	{ "question": "外来", "answers": [ "がいらい" ], "comment": "foreign; imported\noutpatient; outpatient care; outpatient clinic; outpatient ward" },
	{ "question": "外相", "answers": [ "がいしょう" ], "comment": "Foreign Minister" },
	{ "question": "外観", "answers": [ "がいかん" ], "comment": "appearance; exterior; facade" },
	{ "question": "外貨", "answers": [ "がいか" ], "comment": "foreign currency; foreign money; foreign exchange\nforeign goods; imported goods" },
	{ "question": "多岐", "answers": [ "たき" ], "comment": "digression; many divergences" },
	{ "question": "多忙", "answers": [ "たぼう" ], "comment": "busy; pressure of work" },
	{ "question": "多数決", "answers": [ "たすうけつ" ], "comment": "majority rule" },
	{ "question": "多様", "answers": [ "たよう" ], "comment": "diverse; varied" },
	{ "question": "夜中", "answers": [ "よなか", "よじゅう", "やちゅう" ], "comment": "middle of the night; dead of night\nduring the night; at night\nall night; the whole night" },
	{ "question": "夜具", "answers": [ "やぐ" ], "comment": "bedding; bedclothes" },
	{ "question": "夜更かし", "answers": [ "よふかし" ], "comment": "staying up late; keeping late hours; sitting up late at night; nighthawk" },
	{ "question": "夜更け", "answers": [ "よふけ" ], "comment": "late at night; small hours of the morning" },
	{ "question": "大事", "answers": [ "だいじ", "おおごと" ], "comment": "important; valuable; serious matter\nsafe (Tochigi dialect); OK" },
	{ "question": "大人しい", "answers": [ "おとなしい" ], "comment": "obedient; docile; quiet" },
	{ "question": "大便", "answers": [ "だいべん" ], "comment": "feces; excrement; shit" },
	{ "question": "大宗", "answers": [ "たいそう" ], "comment": "leading figure; foundation" },
	{ "question": "大尉", "answers": [ "たいい" ], "comment": "captain (Army, U.S. Marine Corps, USAF); lieutenant (Navy); flight lieutenant (RAF, RAAF, RNZAF, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "大幅", "answers": [ "おおはば" ], "comment": "big; large; drastic; substantial\nfull-width cloth (approx. 72 cm wide for traditional Japanese clothing; approx. 140 cm wide for Western clothing)" },
	{ "question": "大方", "answers": [ "おおかた" ], "comment": "large part; greater part; majority\npeople in general; general public; public at large\nmostly; for the most part; almost; nearly\nprobably; maybe; perhaps" },
	{ "question": "大柄", "answers": [ "おおがら" ], "comment": "large build\nlarge pattern\narrogance; haughtiness; insolence" },
	{ "question": "大概", "answers": [ "たいがい" ], "comment": "in general; almost all\nmainly; mostly; most likely\nmoderately; suitably" },
	{ "question": "大水", "answers": [ "おおみず" ], "comment": "flood" },
	{ "question": "大砲", "answers": [ "たいほう" ], "comment": "gun; cannon; artillery" },
	{ "question": "大空", "answers": [ "おおぞら" ], "comment": "heavens; firmament; sky" },
	{ "question": "大筋", "answers": [ "おおすじ" ], "comment": "outline; summary" },
	{ "question": "大胆", "answers": [ "だいたん" ], "comment": "bold; daring; audacious" },
	{ "question": "大衆", "answers": [ "たいしゅう" ], "comment": "general public; the masses" },
	{ "question": "大部", "answers": [ "たいぶ" ], "comment": "lengthy (of a book, etc.); voluminous\nmost (e.g. most part); greater; fairly; a good deal; much" },
	{ "question": "大金", "answers": [ "たいきん" ], "comment": "large amount of money; great cost" },
	{ "question": "天", "answers": [ "あま", "テン", "あめ" ], "comment": "sky\nheaven\nsvarga (heaven-like realm visited as a stage of death and rebirth)\ndeva (divine being of Buddhism)" },
	{ "question": "天井", "answers": [ "てんじょう" ], "comment": "ceiling; ceiling price" },
	{ "question": "天体", "answers": [ "てんたい" ], "comment": "heavenly body; celestial body; astronomical object" },
	{ "question": "天国", "answers": [ "てんごく" ], "comment": "paradise; heaven; Kingdom of Heaven" },
	{ "question": "天地", "answers": [ "てんち", "あめつち" ], "comment": "heaven and earth; the universe; nature; top and bottom; realm; sphere; world\ntop and bottom\ngods of heaven and earth" },
	{ "question": "天才", "answers": [ "てんさい" ], "comment": "genius; prodigy; natural gift" },
	{ "question": "天災", "answers": [ "てんさい" ], "comment": "natural calamity; disaster" },
	{ "question": "天皇", "answers": [ "てんのう", "すめらぎ" ], "comment": "Emperor of Japan" },
	{ "question": "失格", "answers": [ "しっかく" ], "comment": "disqualification; elimination; incapacity (legal)" },
	{ "question": "失調", "answers": [ "しっちょう" ], "comment": "lack of harmony; lack of balance; lack of coordination; malfunction\nataxia" },
	{ "question": "奇数", "answers": [ "きすう" ], "comment": "odd number" },
	{ "question": "奈落", "answers": [ "ならく" ], "comment": "Naraka; hell; hades\nvery bottom; the end; worst possible circumstances\ntheatre basement; theater basement" },
	{ "question": "奉る", "answers": [ "たてまつる" ], "comment": "to offer; to present\nto set someone up in a high position; to revere at a distance\nto do respectfully" },
	{ "question": "奉仕", "answers": [ "ほうし" ], "comment": "service; ministry; attendance; church work\noffering goods at a reduced price; providing a service for free" },
	{ "question": "契る", "answers": [ "ちぎる" ], "comment": "to pledge; to vow; to promise; to swear\nto have sexual intercourse (esp. between husband and wife); to share a bed" },
	{ "question": "契機", "answers": [ "けいき" ], "comment": "opportunity; chance" },
	{ "question": "奨励", "answers": [ "しょうれい" ], "comment": "encouragement; promotion; inducement; incitement; stimulation" },
	{ "question": "奮闘", "answers": [ "ふんとう" ], "comment": "hard struggle; strenuous effort" },
	{ "question": "女史", "answers": [ "じょし" ], "comment": "Ms (nuance of status); Miss; Madame\nhighbrow (woman); cerebral" },
	{ "question": "奴", "answers": [ "やつ", "やっこ" ], "comment": "servant (esp. a samurai's attendant)\nchivalrous man (c. Edo period)\ncubed tofu (often served cold)\nkite shaped like a footman\nEdo-period hairstyle worn by samurai's attendants\nenslavement (of a woman; Edo-period punishment for her own or her husband's crime)\nhe; she; him; her\nfellow; guy; chap\nthing; object\n(derogatory or familiar) he; she; him; her\nderogatory suffix (referring to others)\nhumble suffix (referring to oneself)\nslave\nretainer; servant\ncaptive\nvarlet\nI; me" },
	{ "question": "好い", "answers": [ "いい", "よい" ], "comment": "good; excellent; fine; nice; pleasant; agreeable\nsufficient (can be used to turn down an offer); ready; prepared\nprofitable (e.g. deal, business offer, etc.); beneficial\nOK" },
	{ "question": "好ましい", "answers": [ "このましい" ], "comment": "nice; likeable; desirable" },
	{ "question": "好意", "answers": [ "こうい" ], "comment": "good will; favor; favour; courtesy" },
	{ "question": "好況", "answers": [ "こうきょう" ], "comment": "prosperous conditions; healthy economy" },
	{ "question": "好評", "answers": [ "こうひょう" ], "comment": "popularity; favorable reputation; favourable reputation" },
	{ "question": "好調", "answers": [ "こうちょう" ], "comment": "favourable; favorable; promising; satisfactory; in good shape" },
	{ "question": "妊娠", "answers": [ "にんしん" ], "comment": "conception; pregnancy" },
	{ "question": "妥協", "answers": [ "だきょう" ], "comment": "compromise; giving in" },
	{ "question": "妥結", "answers": [ "だけつ" ], "comment": "settlement; an agreement" },
	{ "question": "妨害", "answers": [ "ぼうがい" ], "comment": "disturbance; obstruction; hindrance; jamming; interference" },
	{ "question": "妬む", "answers": [ "ねたむ" ], "comment": "to be jealous of; to envy; to begrudge" },
	{ "question": "姉妹", "answers": [ "しまい", "きょうだい" ], "comment": "sisters" },
	{ "question": "始末", "answers": [ "しまつ" ], "comment": "management; dealing with; settlement; cleaning up; disposal\ncourse of events; circumstances; particulars\nend result (usu. bad); outcome\neconomizing; economising; frugality; being thrifty" },
	{ "question": "始発", "answers": [ "しはつ" ], "comment": "first departure (of the day: train, bus, etc.); first train; first bus\ndeparting one's home station (of a train, bus, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "姓名", "answers": [ "せいめい" ], "comment": "full name" },
	{ "question": "委託", "answers": [ "いたく" ], "comment": "entrusting (something to a person); consignment (of goods); putting in someone's charge; trust; commission" },
	{ "question": "威力", "answers": [ "いりょく" ], "comment": "power; might; authority; influence" },
	{ "question": "婿", "answers": [ "むこ" ], "comment": "husband; groom\n(one's) son-in-law" },
	{ "question": "嫉妬", "answers": [ "しっと" ], "comment": "jealousy; envy" },
	{ "question": "子息", "answers": [ "しそく" ], "comment": "son" },
	{ "question": "字", "answers": [ "ジ", "あざ" ], "comment": "section of village\ncharacter (i.e. kanji)\nhand-writing; penmanship\nthe ... word (i.e. \"the L word\" = \"love\")\nChinese courtesy name (name formerly given to adult Chinese men, used in place of their given name in formal situations)\nnickname\nsection of a village" },
	{ "question": "字体", "answers": [ "じたい" ], "comment": "type; font; lettering" },
	{ "question": "存続", "answers": [ "そんぞく" ], "comment": "duration; continuance" },
	{ "question": "季刊", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "quarterly (e.g. magazine)" },
	{ "question": "孤児", "answers": [ "こじ" ], "comment": "orphan" },
	{ "question": "孤独", "answers": [ "こどく" ], "comment": "solitude; loneliness; isolation" },
	{ "question": "孤立", "answers": [ "こりつ" ], "comment": "isolation; being alone; being friendless" },
	{ "question": "学士", "answers": [ "がくし" ], "comment": "university graduate; bachelor\nbachelor's degree" },
	{ "question": "学歴", "answers": [ "がくれき" ], "comment": "academic background" },
	{ "question": "学芸", "answers": [ "がくげい" ], "comment": "arts and sciences; liberal arts" },
	{ "question": "学説", "answers": [ "がくせつ" ], "comment": "theory" },
	{ "question": "守備", "answers": [ "しゅび" ], "comment": "defense; defence" },
	{ "question": "守衛", "answers": [ "しゅえい" ], "comment": "security guard; doorkeeper" },
	{ "question": "安っぽい", "answers": [ "やすっぽい" ], "comment": "cheap-looking; tawdry; insignificant" },
	{ "question": "安静", "answers": [ "あんせい" ], "comment": "rest; quiet; repose" },
	{ "question": "完璧", "answers": [ "かんぺき" ], "comment": "perfect; complete; flawless" },
	{ "question": "官僚", "answers": [ "かんりょう" ], "comment": "bureaucrat; bureaucracy" },
	{ "question": "宙返り", "answers": [ "ちゅうがえり" ], "comment": "somersault; looping-the-loop" },
	{ "question": "定年", "answers": [ "ていねん" ], "comment": "retirement age\nyears of service in a military rank before eligibility for promotion" },
	{ "question": "定義", "answers": [ "ていぎ" ], "comment": "definition" },
	{ "question": "定食", "answers": [ "ていしょく" ], "comment": "set meal; special (of the day)" },
	{ "question": "宛", "answers": [ "あて" ], "comment": "aim; object; purpose; end\nexpectations; prospects; hopes\nsomething that can be relied upon\nsnack served with alcoholic drink\npad; guard\nblow; strike\naddressed to\nper" },
	{ "question": "宛てる", "answers": [ "あてる" ], "comment": "to address" },
	{ "question": "宝器", "answers": [ "ほうき" ], "comment": "treasured article or vessel; outstanding individual" },
	{ "question": "実", "answers": [ "み", "じつ" ], "comment": "truth; reality\nsincerity; honesty; fidelity\ncontent; substance\n(good) result\nfruit; nut\nseed\n(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.\ncontent; substance\ntruth; reality\nsincerity; honesty; integrity; fidelity\nthat's right (used when recalling forgotten information, suddenly changing the subject, etc.)\npit (of a fruit); stone\ncore\ntongue (piece of wood used to connect two boards)\nclitoris\nthe real person; said person\nreal thing; genuine article" },
	{ "question": "実情", "answers": [ "じつじょう" ], "comment": "real condition; actual circumstances; actual state of affairs" },
	{ "question": "実態", "answers": [ "じったい" ], "comment": "true state; actual condition; reality" },
	{ "question": "実業家", "answers": [ "じつぎょうか" ], "comment": "businessman; industrialist" },
	{ "question": "実費", "answers": [ "じっぴ" ], "comment": "actual expense; cost price" },
	{ "question": "実質", "answers": [ "じっしつ" ], "comment": "substance; essence\nreal (in economics, vs. nominal, e.g. real interest rate); substantive; substantial; essential; tangible" },
	{ "question": "実践", "answers": [ "じっせん" ], "comment": "practice; practising; putting into practice; implementation" },
	{ "question": "客観", "answers": [ "きゃっかん" ], "comment": "objectivity; objective; object (philosophical)" },
	{ "question": "宣教", "answers": [ "せんきょう" ], "comment": "religious mission; religious proclamation" },
	{ "question": "宣言", "answers": [ "せんげん" ], "comment": "declaration; proclamation; announcement" },
	{ "question": "室", "answers": [ "しつ", "むろ" ], "comment": "room\nwife (of someone of high rank)\nscabbard\nChinese \"Encampment\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\ngreenhouse; icehouse; cellar" },
	{ "question": "宮殿", "answers": [ "きゅうでん" ], "comment": "palace" },
	{ "question": "害する", "answers": [ "がいする" ], "comment": "to injure; to damage; to harm; to hurt\nto kill\nto hinder; to obstruct" },
	{ "question": "家主", "answers": [ "やぬし", "いえぬし" ], "comment": "landlord; landlady\nhouse owner; home owner; head of the household" },
	{ "question": "家出", "answers": [ "いえで" ], "comment": "running away from home; elopement\nouting; going out\nbecoming a Buddhist monk; entering the priesthood" },
	{ "question": "家来", "answers": [ "けらい" ], "comment": "retainer; retinue; servant" },
	{ "question": "家畜", "answers": [ "かちく" ], "comment": "domestic animals; livestock; cattle" },
	{ "question": "家計", "answers": [ "かけい" ], "comment": "household economy; family finances" },
	{ "question": "容易い", "answers": [ "たやすい" ], "comment": "easy; simple; light" },
	{ "question": "宿命", "answers": [ "しゅくめい" ], "comment": "fate; destiny; predestination" },
	{ "question": "寄こす", "answers": [ "よこす" ], "comment": "to send; to forward\nto hand over (e.g. money)" },
	{ "question": "寄り掛かる", "answers": [ "よりかかる" ], "comment": "to lean against; to recline on; to lean on\nto rely on; to depend on" },
	{ "question": "寄与", "answers": [ "きよ" ], "comment": "contribution; service" },
	{ "question": "寄贈", "answers": [ "きぞう", "きそう" ], "comment": "donation; presentation; gift" },
	{ "question": "密か", "answers": [ "ひそか" ], "comment": "secret; private; surreptitious" },
	{ "question": "密度", "answers": [ "みつど" ], "comment": "density" },
	{ "question": "密接", "answers": [ "みっせつ" ], "comment": "related; connected; close; intimate" },
	{ "question": "密集", "answers": [ "みっしゅう" ], "comment": "crowd; close formation; dense" },
	{ "question": "富", "answers": [ "とみ" ], "comment": "riches; wealth; fortune\nresources\nlottery" },
	{ "question": "富む", "answers": [ "とむ" ], "comment": "to be rich; to become rich; to be abundant (with); to abound (with); to be rich (in)" },
	{ "question": "富豪", "answers": [ "ふごう" ], "comment": "wealthy person; millionaire" },
	{ "question": "寒気", "answers": [ "さむけ", "かんき" ], "comment": "chill; the shivers; shivering fit\ncold; coldness; cold air" },
	{ "question": "寛容", "answers": [ "かんよう" ], "comment": "tolerance; open-mindedness; forbearance; generosity" },
	{ "question": "寝かせる", "answers": [ "ねかせる" ], "comment": "to put to bed\nto lay down lengthwise; to put a thing on its side\nto set something aside unused; to let lie idle\nto ferment; to lay down (wine)" },
	{ "question": "察する", "answers": [ "さっする" ], "comment": "to guess; to sense; to presume; to judge\nto sympathize with; to sympathise with" },
	{ "question": "審判", "answers": [ "しんぱん", "しんばん" ], "comment": "refereeing; trial; judgement; judgment; umpire; referee" },
	{ "question": "審査", "answers": [ "しんさ" ], "comment": "judging; inspection; examination; investigation; review" },
	{ "question": "審議", "answers": [ "しんぎ" ], "comment": "deliberation" },
	{ "question": "対して", "answers": [ "たいして" ], "comment": "for; in regard to; per" },
	{ "question": "対処", "answers": [ "たいしょ" ], "comment": "dealing with; coping with" },
	{ "question": "対応", "answers": [ "たいおう" ], "comment": "interaction; correspondence; coping with; dealing with; support; response; reception\nsoftware support; ability of a computer system to run specific software; compatibility" },
	{ "question": "対抗", "answers": [ "たいこう" ], "comment": "opposition; antagonism" },
	{ "question": "対比", "answers": [ "たいひ" ], "comment": "contrast; comparison" },
	{ "question": "対決", "answers": [ "たいけつ" ], "comment": "confrontation; showdown" },
	{ "question": "対立", "answers": [ "たいりつ" ], "comment": "confrontation; opposition; antagonism" },
	{ "question": "対等", "answers": [ "たいとう" ], "comment": "equality (esp. of status, on equal terms); equivalence\nequivalent; equal" },
	{ "question": "対話", "answers": [ "たいわ" ], "comment": "dialogue; discussion; conversation; interaction" },
	{ "question": "対談", "answers": [ "たいだん" ], "comment": "talk; dialogue; conversation" },
	{ "question": "対辺", "answers": [ "たいへん" ], "comment": "opposite side" },
	{ "question": "対面", "answers": [ "たいめん" ], "comment": "interview; meeting\nopposing (traffic, etc.); facing; confronting\nopposite player\nopposite side; (person) directly opposite" },
	{ "question": "封", "answers": [ "ふう" ], "comment": "seal" },
	{ "question": "封建", "answers": [ "ほうけん" ], "comment": "feudalistic" },
	{ "question": "封鎖", "answers": [ "ふうさ" ], "comment": "blockade\nfreezing (funds)" },
	{ "question": "専ら", "answers": [ "もっぱら" ], "comment": "wholly; solely; entirely; exclusively; devotedly; fixedly\nprincipally; mostly; chiefly; mainly" },
	{ "question": "専修", "answers": [ "せんしゅう" ], "comment": "specialization; specialisation" },
	{ "question": "専用", "answers": [ "せんよう" ], "comment": "exclusive use; personal use; dedicated\nprivate (e.g. network)" },
	{ "question": "尊い", "answers": [ "とうとい", "たっとい" ], "comment": "precious; valuable; priceless; noble; exalted; sacred" },
	{ "question": "尊ぶ", "answers": [ "とうとぶ", "たっとぶ" ], "comment": "to value; to prize; to esteem; to respect" },
	{ "question": "導く", "answers": [ "みちびく" ], "comment": "to guide; to lead; to show the way; to conduct\nto derive; to deduce" },
	{ "question": "導入", "answers": [ "どうにゅう" ], "comment": "introduction; bringing in; leading in; installation" },
	{ "question": "小児科", "answers": [ "しょうにか" ], "comment": "pediatrics" },
	{ "question": "小切手", "answers": [ "こぎって" ], "comment": "cheque; check" },
	{ "question": "小売", "answers": [ "こうり" ], "comment": "retail" },
	{ "question": "小柄", "answers": [ "こがら" ], "comment": "small build; small stature; petite\nsmall pattern\nknife attached to the sheath of a sword\nsterigma" },
	{ "question": "小銭", "answers": [ "こぜに" ], "comment": "coins; small change" },
	{ "question": "少数", "answers": [ "しょうすう" ], "comment": "minority; few" },
	{ "question": "尚", "answers": [ "なお" ], "comment": "furthermore; still; yet; more; still more; in addition; greater; further" },
	{ "question": "尚更", "answers": [ "なおさら" ], "comment": "still more; even more; all the more\nstill less; even less" },
	{ "question": "就業", "answers": [ "しゅうぎょう" ], "comment": "employment; starting work" },
	{ "question": "尻尾", "answers": [ "しっぽ" ], "comment": "tail (animal)" },
	{ "question": "尽くす", "answers": [ "つくす" ], "comment": "to exhaust; to run out\nto devote; to serve (a person); to befriend\nto do to exhaustion" },
	{ "question": "尾", "answers": [ "お" ], "comment": "tail (animal, kite, comet, etc.); tail end\nslope at the foot of a mountain\nChinese \"Tail\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\ncounter for fish, shrimp, etc." },
	{ "question": "尿", "answers": [ "にょう" ], "comment": "urine" },
	{ "question": "局限", "answers": [ "きょくげん" ], "comment": "limit; localize; localise" },
	{ "question": "居住", "answers": [ "きょじゅう" ], "comment": "residence" },
	{ "question": "居候", "answers": [ "いそうろう" ], "comment": "lodger who pays nothing for room and board; freeloader; sponger" },
	{ "question": "屈折", "answers": [ "くっせつ" ], "comment": "bending; indentation\nrefraction\ninflection\nwarping (e.g. of opinion, reasoning, etc.); distortion" },
	{ "question": "届け", "answers": [ "とどけ" ], "comment": "report; notification; registration" },
	{ "question": "屋敷", "answers": [ "やしき" ], "comment": "residence; estate; grounds; premises; mansion" },
	{ "question": "展望", "answers": [ "てんぼう" ], "comment": "view; outlook; prospect" },
	{ "question": "展示", "answers": [ "てんじ" ], "comment": "exhibition; display" },
	{ "question": "展覧会", "answers": [ "てんらんかい" ], "comment": "exhibition" },
	{ "question": "履歴", "answers": [ "りれき" ], "comment": "personal history; background; career\nlog; record\nhysteresis" },
	{ "question": "山岳", "answers": [ "さんがく" ], "comment": "mountains" },
	{ "question": "山脈", "answers": [ "さんみゃく" ], "comment": "mountain range" },
	{ "question": "山腹", "answers": [ "さんぷく" ], "comment": "hillside; mountainside" },
	{ "question": "岩石", "answers": [ "がんせき" ], "comment": "rock" },
	{ "question": "峰", "answers": [ "みね" ], "comment": "peak; summit; ridge; top\nback of a blade" },
	{ "question": "崇拝", "answers": [ "すうはい" ], "comment": "worship; adoration; admiration; cult" },
	{ "question": "崖", "answers": [ "がけ" ], "comment": "cliff" },
	{ "question": "崩壊", "answers": [ "ほうかい" ], "comment": "collapse; crumbling; breaking down; caving in\ndecay" },
	{ "question": "工作", "answers": [ "こうさく" ], "comment": "handicraft\nwork; construction; manufacturing\nmaneuvering; manoeuvering" },
	{ "question": "工学", "answers": [ "こうがく" ], "comment": "engineering" },
	{ "question": "左利き", "answers": [ "ひだりきき" ], "comment": "left-handedness; left-hander\ndrinker; wine lover" },
	{ "question": "左程", "answers": [ "さほど" ], "comment": "not so; not particularly; not very; not that much" },
	{ "question": "巧み", "answers": [ "たくみ" ], "comment": "skillful; adroit; dexterous; masterful; clever; ingenious; cunning" },
	{ "question": "巧妙", "answers": [ "こうみょう" ], "comment": "ingenious; skillful; clever; deft" },
	{ "question": "巨", "answers": [ "きょ" ] },
	{ "question": "差し出す", "answers": [ "さしだす" ], "comment": "to present; to submit; to tender; to hold out" },
	{ "question": "差し引く", "answers": [ "さしひく" ], "comment": "to deduct; to take away; to dock\nto make allowances for something; to bear something in mind\nto ebb and flow" },
	{ "question": "差し掛かる", "answers": [ "さしかかる" ], "comment": "to come near to; to approach" },
	{ "question": "差し支える", "answers": [ "さしつかえる" ], "comment": "to interfere; to hinder; to become impeded" },
	{ "question": "差異", "answers": [ "さい" ], "comment": "difference; disparity; gap" },
	{ "question": "差額", "answers": [ "さがく" ], "comment": "balance; difference; margin" },
	{ "question": "巻", "answers": [ "まき", "カン" ], "comment": "roll (e.g. of cloth)\nwinding\nvolume (of book)\nvolume (of book); reel (of film)" },
	{ "question": "市", "answers": [ "シ", "いち" ], "comment": "market; fair\ncity" },
	{ "question": "市街", "answers": [ "しがい" ], "comment": "urban areas; the streets; town; city" },
	{ "question": "布告", "answers": [ "ふこく" ], "comment": "edict; ordinance; proclamation" },
	{ "question": "布巾", "answers": [ "ふきん" ], "comment": "tea-towel; dish cloth" },
	{ "question": "帯びる", "answers": [ "おびる" ], "comment": "to wear (sword, decoration, etc.); to carry\nto be entrusted (e.g. with a mission); to take on\nto have a trace of; to be tinged with" },
	{ "question": "帰京", "answers": [ "ききょう" ], "comment": "returning to Tokyo\nreturning to the capital" },
	{ "question": "帳", "answers": [ "とばり", "ちょう" ], "comment": "book; register\ncurtain; hanging; bunting" },
	{ "question": "幕", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "curtain; bunting\nact (in play)" },
	{ "question": "干し物", "answers": [ "ほしもの" ], "comment": "things dried in the sun (esp. clothes, dyed cloth, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "干渉", "answers": [ "かんしょう" ], "comment": "interference; intervention; meddling" },
	{ "question": "平たい", "answers": [ "ひらたい" ], "comment": "flat; even; level; simple\nplain (speech, etc.); simple" },
	{ "question": "平均", "answers": [ "へいきん" ], "comment": "average; mean\nbalance; equilibrium" },
	{ "question": "平常", "answers": [ "へいじょう" ], "comment": "normal; usual" },
	{ "question": "平方", "answers": [ "へいほう" ], "comment": "square (e.g. metre)" },
	{ "question": "平行", "answers": [ "へいこう" ], "comment": "concurrent; occurring together; at the same time\nparallel" },
	{ "question": "年号", "answers": [ "ねんごう" ], "comment": "name of an era; year number" },
	{ "question": "年寄り", "answers": [ "としより" ], "comment": "old people; the aged\ntrustee of the Japan Sumo Association; retired high-ranking wrestler who is licensed to coach and receives retirement pay\nsenior statesman (of the Tokugawa shogunate)\nimportant local official (under the Tokugawa Shogunate)" },
	{ "question": "年生", "answers": [ "ねんせい" ], "comment": "pupil in ... year; student in ... year" },
	{ "question": "年輪", "answers": [ "ねんりん" ], "comment": "annual tree ring" },
	{ "question": "年鑑", "answers": [ "ねんかん" ], "comment": "yearbook; almanac; annual" },
	{ "question": "年長", "answers": [ "ねんちょう" ], "comment": "senior; older" },
	{ "question": "年頃", "answers": [ "としごろ" ], "comment": "approximate age; apparent age\nmarriageable age (esp. of a woman); age of maturity; age of adulthood\nappropriate age (to ...); old enough (to ...)\npast few years; for some years" },
	{ "question": "幹", "answers": [ "みき", "かん" ], "comment": "(tree) trunk; (arrow) shaft; (tool) handle; backbone; base\ntrunk; stem; stalk\nshaft (of an arrow)\nhandle" },
	{ "question": "幹線", "answers": [ "かんせん" ], "comment": "main line; trunk line" },
	{ "question": "幹部", "answers": [ "かんぶ" ], "comment": "management; (executive) staff; leaders; leadership; top brass; upper echelons" },
	{ "question": "幽霊", "answers": [ "ゆうれい" ], "comment": "ghost; specter; spectre; apparition; phantom" },
	{ "question": "幾多", "answers": [ "いくた" ], "comment": "many; numerous" },
	{ "question": "庁", "answers": [ "ちょう" ], "comment": "government office; agency; board" },
	{ "question": "広まる", "answers": [ "ひろまる" ], "comment": "to spread; to be propagated" },
	{ "question": "床", "answers": [ "ゆか", "とこ" ], "comment": "bed; bedding\nsickbed\nalcove\nriverbed\nseedbed\nstraw \"core\" of a tatami mat\nfloor\nfloor\nstage (for the narrator and the shamisen player)\ndining platform built across a river\ncounter for beds" },
	{ "question": "度々", "answers": [ "たびたび" ], "comment": "often; again and again; over and over again; repeatedly; frequently" },
	{ "question": "度忘れ", "answers": [ "どわすれ" ], "comment": "lapse of memory; forgetting for a moment something one knows well; (something) slipping one's mind" },
	{ "question": "座標", "answers": [ "ざひょう" ], "comment": "coordinate; coordinates" },
	{ "question": "座談会", "answers": [ "ざだんかい" ], "comment": "symposium; round-table discussion" },
	{ "question": "庶務", "answers": [ "しょむ" ], "comment": "general affairs" },
	{ "question": "庶民", "answers": [ "しょみん" ], "comment": "masses; common people" },
	{ "question": "廃れる", "answers": [ "すたれる" ], "comment": "to go out of use; to become obsolete; to die out; to go out of fashion" },
	{ "question": "廃棄", "answers": [ "はいき" ], "comment": "disposal; abandonment; scrapping; discarding; abolition\nannulment; cancellation; abrogation; repeal" },
	{ "question": "延べ", "answers": [ "のべ" ], "comment": "futures\ncredit (buying)\nstretching\ntotal (preceding counter, unit, etc.); aggregate; gross" },
	{ "question": "建前", "answers": [ "たてまえ" ], "comment": "face; official stance; public position or attitude (as opposed to private thoughts)\nceremony for the erection of the framework of a house" },
	{ "question": "弁償", "answers": [ "べんしょう" ], "comment": "reimbursement; compensation; reparation; indemnity" },
	{ "question": "弁解", "answers": [ "べんかい" ], "comment": "explanation (e.g. for one's actions); excuse; justification; defense; defence" },
	{ "question": "弁論", "answers": [ "べんろん" ], "comment": "discussion; debate; argument" },
	{ "question": "弁護", "answers": [ "べんご" ], "comment": "defense; defence; pleading; advocacy" },
	{ "question": "弄ぶ", "answers": [ "もてあそぶ" ], "comment": "to play with (a toy, one's hair, etc.); to fiddle with\nto toy with (one's emotions, etc.); to trifle with\nto do with something as one pleases\nto appreciate" },
	{ "question": "式場", "answers": [ "しきじょう" ], "comment": "ceremonial hall (e.g. wedding, funeral); hall for ceremonies; place of ceremony" },
	{ "question": "弓", "answers": [ "ゆみ" ], "comment": "bow (and arrow)\narchery\nbow (for a violin, etc.)\nbow (and arrow)\nunit of distance to an archery target (approx. six feet)\nunit of distance for land surveying (approx. eight feet)\nbow (and arrow; esp. of a noble)" },
	{ "question": "引きずる", "answers": [ "ひきずる" ], "comment": "to drag along; to pull\nto force someone along\nto prolong; to drag out\nto influence strongly; to seduce" },
	{ "question": "引き上げる", "answers": [ "ひきあげる" ], "comment": "to pull up; to drag up; to lift up\nto increase; to raise (e.g. taxes)\nto withdraw; to leave; to pull out; to retire\nto promote (someone to a higher position)\nto return home\nto expedite the schedule" },
	{ "question": "引き下げる", "answers": [ "ひきさげる" ], "comment": "to pull down; to lower; to reduce; to withdraw" },
	{ "question": "引き分け", "answers": [ "ひきわけ" ], "comment": "draw (in competition); tie game" },
	{ "question": "引き取る", "answers": [ "ひきとる" ], "comment": "to take over; to take back; to collect; to claim\nto take charge of; to take custody of; to look after; to take care of; to adopt\nto retire to a private place; to withdraw; to get out" },
	{ "question": "引き受ける", "answers": [ "ひきうける" ], "comment": "to take on; to undertake; to accept; to take charge of; to assume responsibility for\nto take over; to inherit\nto guarantee; to vouch for\nto contract (a disease)" },
	{ "question": "引き起こす", "answers": [ "ひきおこす" ], "comment": "to cause; to induce; to bring about; to provoke\nto pull upright; to help up (e.g. a fallen person)" },
	{ "question": "引っ掛ける", "answers": [ "ひっかける" ], "comment": "to hang (something) on (something); to throw on (clothes)\nto hook; to catch; to trap; to ensnare\nto cheat; to evade payment; to jump a bill\nto drink (alcohol)\nto splash someone (with)\nto hit the ball off the end of the bat" },
	{ "question": "弟", "answers": [ "おとうと" ], "comment": "younger brother; little brother; kid brother\npupil; apprentice" },
	{ "question": "弱", "answers": [ "じゃく" ], "comment": "little less than; fewer than; under\nweakness; the weak" },
	{ "question": "弱まる", "answers": [ "よわまる" ], "comment": "to abate; to weaken; to be emaciated; to be dejected; to be perplexed" },
	{ "question": "弱める", "answers": [ "よわめる" ], "comment": "to weaken" },
	{ "question": "弱る", "answers": [ "よわる" ], "comment": "to weaken; to be troubled; to be downcast; to be emaciated; to be dejected; to be perplexed; to impair" },
	{ "question": "張り紙", "answers": [ "はりがみ" ], "comment": "paper patch; paper backing; poster; sticker; label" },
	{ "question": "強いて", "answers": [ "しいて" ], "comment": "by force" },
	{ "question": "強いる", "answers": [ "しいる" ], "comment": "to force; to compel; to coerce" },
	{ "question": "強まる", "answers": [ "つよまる" ], "comment": "to get strong; to gain strength" },
	{ "question": "強める", "answers": [ "つよめる" ], "comment": "to strengthen; to emphasize; to emphasise" },
	{ "question": "強制", "answers": [ "きょうせい" ], "comment": "obligation; coercion; compulsion; enforcement" },
	{ "question": "強気", "answers": [ "つよき", "ごうぎ" ], "comment": "confident; assured; self-assured; firm; strong; cocksure\nbullish (e.g. market)\ngreat; grand\nobstinate; stubborn" },
	{ "question": "強烈", "answers": [ "きょうれつ" ], "comment": "strong; intense; severe" },
	{ "question": "強硬", "answers": [ "きょうこう" ], "comment": "firm; vigorous; unbending; unyielding; strong; stubborn" },
	{ "question": "強行", "answers": [ "きょうこう" ], "comment": "forcing; enforcement\nforced; enforced" },
	{ "question": "弾", "answers": [ "たま" ], "comment": "ball; sphere; globe; orb\nbead (of sweat, dew, etc.); drop; droplet\nball (in sports)\npile (of noodles, etc.)\nbullet\nbulb (i.e. a light bulb)\nlens (of glasses, etc.)\nbead (of an abacus)\nball (i.e. a testicle)\ngem; jewel (esp. spherical; sometimes used figuratively); pearl\nfemale entertainer (e.g. a geisha)\nperson (when commenting on their nature); character\nitem, funds or person used as part of a plot\negg\ncoin\nprecious; beautiful; excellent\ncounter for parts (of a story, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "弾く", "answers": [ "ひく", "はじく" ], "comment": "to flip; to snap; to flick\nto repel\nto use (an abacus); to calculate\nto strum; to pluck the strings (of a guitar, etc.)\nto play (piano, guitar)" },
	{ "question": "弾む", "answers": [ "はずむ" ], "comment": "to spring; to bound; to bounce; to be stimulated; to be encouraged; to get lively; to treat oneself to; to splurge on" },
	{ "question": "弾力", "answers": [ "だんりょく" ], "comment": "elasticity; flexibility" },
	{ "question": "当たり", "answers": [ "あたり" ], "comment": "hit\nsuccess\nguess; prediction\naffability; friendliness\nsensation; touch\nbruise (on fruit)\nsituation in which a stone or chain of stones may be captured on the next move (in the game of go)\nbite (of a fish on a hook); strike\nper; each" },
	{ "question": "当たり前", "answers": [ "あたりまえ" ], "comment": "natural; reasonable; obvious\nusual; common; ordinary; commonplace; the norm" },
	{ "question": "当て字", "answers": [ "あてじ" ], "comment": "kanji used as a phonetic symbol, instead of for the meaning; phonetic-equivalent character; substitute character\nkanji used for their meaning, irrespective of reading" },
	{ "question": "当人", "answers": [ "とうにん" ], "comment": "the one concerned; the said person" },
	{ "question": "当選", "answers": [ "とうせん" ], "comment": "being elected\nbeing selected (to win a prize, etc.)\nwinning (in a lottery, raffle, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "形勢", "answers": [ "けいせい" ], "comment": "condition; situation; prospects" },
	{ "question": "形態", "answers": [ "けいたい" ], "comment": "form; shape; figure" },
	{ "question": "形成", "answers": [ "けいせい" ], "comment": "formation; molding; taking form\nrepair (e.g. plastic surgery); replacement; -plasty" },
	{ "question": "役", "answers": [ "やく", "えき" ], "comment": "war; campaign; battle\nunpaid work (ritsuryo system); forced labor\nuse; service; role\npost; position\nscoring combination (e.g. in mahjong, card games, etc.); hand" },
	{ "question": "役場", "answers": [ "やくば" ], "comment": "town hall" },
	{ "question": "役立つ", "answers": [ "やくだつ" ], "comment": "to be useful; to be helpful; to serve the purpose" },
	{ "question": "役職", "answers": [ "やくしょく" ], "comment": "post; managerial position; official position" },
	{ "question": "彼方", "answers": [ "かなた", "あなた", "あちら", "あっち" ], "comment": "beyond; across; the other side; the distance\nthat way (direction distant from both speaker and listener); over there; yonder\nthat one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener); that\nthat person (someone physically distant from both speaker and listener, or someone not present but known by both speaker and listener)\nthere (place distant from both speaker and listener); over there; foreign country (esp. a Western nation)" },
	{ "question": "征服", "answers": [ "せいふく" ], "comment": "conquest; subjugation; overcoming" },
	{ "question": "待ち合わせ", "answers": [ "まちあわせ" ], "comment": "appointment" },
	{ "question": "待ち望む", "answers": [ "まちのぞむ" ], "comment": "to wait eagerly for; to look forward to" },
	{ "question": "待ち遠しい", "answers": [ "まちどおしい" ], "comment": "looking forward to; anxiously awaited" },
	{ "question": "待望", "answers": [ "たいぼう" ], "comment": "waiting expectantly; waiting eagerly; looking forward to\nlong-awaited" },
	{ "question": "待遇", "answers": [ "たいぐう" ], "comment": "treatment; reception; service\nworking conditions; salary; pay; remuneration" },
	{ "question": "後回し", "answers": [ "あとまわし" ], "comment": "putting off; postponing" },
	{ "question": "後悔", "answers": [ "こうかい" ], "comment": "regret; repentance; remorse" },
	{ "question": "後退", "answers": [ "こうたい" ], "comment": "retreat\nbackspace; BS" },
	{ "question": "徐々に", "answers": [ "じょじょに" ], "comment": "gradually; steadily; quietly; slowly; little by little\nsoon" },
	{ "question": "徐行", "answers": [ "じょこう" ], "comment": "going slowly" },
	{ "question": "徒歩", "answers": [ "とほ" ], "comment": "walking; going on foot\nfoot soldier (Edo period); samurai on foot\ngoing on foot; walking" },
	{ "question": "従って", "answers": [ "したがって" ], "comment": "therefore; consequently; accordingly" },
	{ "question": "従事", "answers": [ "じゅうじ" ], "comment": "engaging; pursuing; following (e.g. profession or occupation)" },
	{ "question": "従来", "answers": [ "じゅうらい" ], "comment": "up to now; so far\ntraditional; conventional; usual; existing" },
	{ "question": "従業員", "answers": [ "じゅうぎょういん" ], "comment": "employee; worker" },
	{ "question": "得点", "answers": [ "とくてん" ], "comment": "score; points made; marks obtained; runs" },
	{ "question": "お負け", "answers": [ "おまけ" ], "comment": "freebie (e.g. with a purchase); something additional; bonus; an extra\nprice reduction; discount\nexaggeration" },
	{ "question": "復旧", "answers": [ "ふっきゅう", "ふくきゅう" ], "comment": "restoration; restitution; rehabilitation" },
	{ "question": "復活", "answers": [ "ふっかつ" ], "comment": "revival (e.g. musical); come-back\nrestoration; rebirth; resurrection" },
	{ "question": "復興", "answers": [ "ふっこう" ], "comment": "revival; renaissance; reconstruction; restoration" },
	{ "question": "微か", "answers": [ "かすか" ], "comment": "faint; dim; weak; slight; vague; indistinct; hazy\npoor; wretched; meagre; meager; scanty" },
	{ "question": "微笑", "answers": [ "びしょう" ], "comment": "smile" },
	{ "question": "微量", "answers": [ "びりょう" ], "comment": "minuscule amount; extremely small quantity" },
	{ "question": "徴収", "answers": [ "ちょうしゅう" ], "comment": "collection (of fees, taxes, etc.); levy" },
	{ "question": "徹する", "answers": [ "てっする" ], "comment": "to penetrate; to sink in\nto devote oneself (to); to do intently and exclusively\nto do throughout (e.g. the night)" },
	{ "question": "心中", "answers": [ "しんじゅう", "しんちゅう" ], "comment": "double suicide; lovers suicide\nin one's heart; true motives; mind" },
	{ "question": "心地", "answers": [ "ここち" ], "comment": "feeling; sensation; mood\nsensation of doing (usu. after -masu stem of verb)\npadding; lining; foundation" },
	{ "question": "心強い", "answers": [ "こころづよい" ], "comment": "heartening; reassuring" },
	{ "question": "心得", "answers": [ "こころえ" ], "comment": "knowledge; understanding\nrules; regulations; guideline; directions\ndeputy; acting" },
	{ "question": "心情", "answers": [ "しんじょう" ], "comment": "sentiment; emotions; one's feelings; one's heart" },
	{ "question": "心掛け", "answers": [ "こころがけ" ], "comment": "intention; attention; dedication; care; prudence; readiness; mental attitude" },
	{ "question": "心掛ける", "answers": [ "こころがける" ], "comment": "to keep in mind; to bear in mind; to try; to aim to do; to endeavor; to endeavour" },
	{ "question": "心細い", "answers": [ "こころぼそい" ], "comment": "helpless; forlorn; hopeless; unpromising; lonely; discouraging; disheartening" },
	{ "question": "必修", "answers": [ "ひっしゅう" ], "comment": "required (subject)" },
	{ "question": "必然", "answers": [ "ひつぜん" ], "comment": "inevitable; necessary; certain; sure\ninevitability; necessity" },
	{ "question": "必至", "answers": [ "ひっし" ], "comment": "inevitable; necessary; foregone\nbrinkmate (inevitable checkmate)" },
	{ "question": "志", "answers": [ "こころざし" ], "comment": "will; resolution; intention; ambition; aim; goal\nkindness; goodwill; kind offer\ngift (as a token of gratitude)" },
	{ "question": "志す", "answers": [ "こころざす" ], "comment": "to plan; to intend; to aspire to; to set aims (sights on)" },
	{ "question": "志向", "answers": [ "しこう" ], "comment": "intention; aim; preference (for)" },
	{ "question": "志望", "answers": [ "しぼう" ], "comment": "wish; desire; ambition" },
	{ "question": "応募", "answers": [ "おうぼ" ], "comment": "application; subscription; entry (competition, raffle, etc.); enlistment" },
	{ "question": "応急", "answers": [ "おうきゅう" ], "comment": "emergency; first-aid" },
	{ "question": "忠告", "answers": [ "ちゅうこく" ], "comment": "advice; warning" },
	{ "question": "忠実", "answers": [ "ちゅうじつ" ], "comment": "faithfulness; devotion; loyalty; honesty; truth; fidelity\nsincerity; conscientiousness; diligence\nhealthiness; fitness\nfaithfulness; devotion" },
	{ "question": "快い", "answers": [ "こころよい" ], "comment": "pleasant; agreeable" },
	{ "question": "念", "answers": [ "ねん" ], "comment": "sense; idea; thought; feeling\ndesire; concern\nattention; care" },
	{ "question": "怒り", "answers": [ "いかり" ], "comment": "anger; rage; fury; wrath; indignation" },
	{ "question": "怒る", "answers": [ "おこる", "いかる" ], "comment": "to get angry; to get mad\nto tell someone off; to scold\nto be angular; to be square" },
	{ "question": "怒鳴る", "answers": [ "どなる" ], "comment": "to shout; to yell" },
	{ "question": "思い付き", "answers": [ "おもいつき" ], "comment": "plan; idea; suggestion" },
	{ "question": "思惑", "answers": [ "おもわく", "しわく" ], "comment": "expectation; anticipation; prediction; forecast; calculations\npurpose; intention; motive; ulterior motive\nothers' opinions of one\nspeculation\nperceptive mental disturbances" },
	{ "question": "思考", "answers": [ "しこう" ], "comment": "thought; consideration; thinking" },
	{ "question": "怠い", "answers": [ "だるい" ], "comment": "sluggish; languid; listless; heavy (heart, legs, etc.); dull\nbothersome; tiresome" },
	{ "question": "怠慢", "answers": [ "たいまん" ], "comment": "negligence; neglect; carelessness; procrastination" },
	{ "question": "急かす", "answers": [ "せかす" ], "comment": "to hurry; to urge on" },
	{ "question": "怪獣", "answers": [ "かいじゅう" ], "comment": "monster" },
	{ "question": "恋する", "answers": [ "こいする" ], "comment": "to fall in love with; to love" },
	{ "question": "恋愛", "answers": [ "れんあい" ], "comment": "love; love-making; passion; emotion; affections" },
	{ "question": "恐らく", "answers": [ "おそらく" ], "comment": "perhaps; likely; probably; I dare say" },
	{ "question": "恐れ", "answers": [ "おそれ" ], "comment": "fear; horror; anxiety; concern; uneasiness" },
	{ "question": "恐れ入る", "answers": [ "おそれいる" ], "comment": "to be sorry; to beg pardon; to be much obliged; to feel small\nto be grateful\nto be amazed; to be filled with awe; to be surprised\nto be disconcerted; to be embarrassed" },
	{ "question": "恥じらう", "answers": [ "はじらう" ], "comment": "to feel shy; to be bashful; to blush" },
	{ "question": "恩恵", "answers": [ "おんけい" ], "comment": "grace; favor; favour; blessing; benefit" },
	{ "question": "恵み", "answers": [ "めぐみ" ], "comment": "blessing; grace" },
	{ "question": "恵む", "answers": [ "めぐむ" ], "comment": "to bless; to show mercy to\nto give (money, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "悟る", "answers": [ "さとる" ], "comment": "to perceive; to sense; to discern\nto understand; to comprehend; to realize\nto attain enlightenment" },
	{ "question": "悩ましい", "answers": [ "なやましい" ], "comment": "seductive; carnal; enchanting\ntroubling; difficult; thorny; hard\nanxious; uneasy" },
	{ "question": "悩ます", "answers": [ "なやます" ], "comment": "to afflict; to torment; to harass; to molest" },
	{ "question": "悩み", "answers": [ "なやみ" ], "comment": "trouble; troubles; worry; distress; sorrows; anguish; agony; problem" },
	{ "question": "悪", "answers": [ "あく", "わる" ], "comment": "evil; wickedness\nbad thing; bad person" },
	{ "question": "悪い", "answers": [ "わるい", "にくい" ], "comment": "bad; poor; inferior\nevil; sinful\nunprofitable; unbeneficial\nat fault; to blame; in the wrong\nsorry\nhateful; abominable; poor-looking; detestable\namazing; fantastic; admirable; lovely; wonderful\ndifficult to ...; hard to ..." },
	{ "question": "悪化", "answers": [ "あっか" ], "comment": "(suffer) deterioration; growing worse; aggravation; degeneration; corruption" },
	{ "question": "悪口", "answers": [ "わるくち", "わるぐち", "あっこう" ], "comment": "abuse; insult; slander; evil speaking; bad mouth" },
	{ "question": "悪戯", "answers": [ "いたずら" ], "comment": "mischief; prank; trick; practical joke\npastime; hobby\nplaying with (a lighter, etc.); fooling around with; messing around with; amusing oneself with; tampering with\nlewd behaviour; sexual misconduct; sexual assault; molestation; rape\noffensive joke" },
	{ "question": "悪日", "answers": [ "あくび" ], "comment": "unlucky day" },
	{ "question": "悪者", "answers": [ "わるもの" ], "comment": "bad fellow; rascal; ruffian; scoundrel" },
	{ "question": "悲惨", "answers": [ "ひさん" ], "comment": "disastrous; tragic; miserable; wretched; pitiful; woeful" },
	{ "question": "悲観", "answers": [ "ひかん" ], "comment": "pessimism; disappointment" },
	{ "question": "悲鳴", "answers": [ "ひめい" ], "comment": "shriek; scream" },
	{ "question": "情", "answers": [ "じょう" ], "comment": "feelings; emotion; sentiment\ncompassion; sympathy\npassion; affection; love\nthe way things really are; the actual situation" },
	{ "question": "情け", "answers": [ "なさけ" ], "comment": "pity; sympathy; compassion; mercy\naffection" },
	{ "question": "情け深い", "answers": [ "なさけぶかい" ], "comment": "tender-hearted; compassionate; charitable; good-hearted" },
	{ "question": "情勢", "answers": [ "じょうせい" ], "comment": "state of things; state of affairs; condition; situation; circumstances" },
	{ "question": "情熱", "answers": [ "じょうねつ" ], "comment": "passion; enthusiasm; zeal" },
	{ "question": "情緒", "answers": [ "じょうちょ", "じょうしょ" ], "comment": "emotion; feeling\natmosphere; mood; spirit" },
	{ "question": "惑星", "answers": [ "わくせい" ], "comment": "planet" },
	{ "question": "惜しむ", "answers": [ "おしむ" ], "comment": "to be frugal; to be sparing\nto value; to hold dear\nto regret (e.g. a loss); to feel sorry (for)\nto be unwilling; to be reluctant" },
	{ "question": "惨め", "answers": [ "みじめ" ], "comment": "miserable; wretched; unhappy; sad; pitiable" },
	{ "question": "意向", "answers": [ "いこう" ], "comment": "intention; idea; inclination" },
	{ "question": "意図", "answers": [ "いと" ], "comment": "intention; aim; design" },
	{ "question": "意地", "answers": [ "いじ" ], "comment": "stubbornness; obstinacy; willpower; pride\ndisposition; nature\nappetite; desire; greed" },
	{ "question": "意欲", "answers": [ "いよく" ], "comment": "will; desire; ambition; urge (e.g. creative urge)" },
	{ "question": "意気込む", "answers": [ "いきごむ" ], "comment": "to be enthusiastic about; to be eager; to be keen" },
	{ "question": "意趣返し", "answers": [ "いしゅがえし" ], "comment": "revenge" },
	{ "question": "愚か", "answers": [ "おろか" ], "comment": "foolish; stupid" },
	{ "question": "愚痴", "answers": [ "ぐち" ], "comment": "idle complaint; grumble\nmoha (ignorance, folly)" },
	{ "question": "愛想", "answers": [ "あいそ", "あいそう" ], "comment": "civility; courtesy; compliments; sociability; graces" },
	{ "question": "愛憎", "answers": [ "あいぞう" ], "comment": "love and hate; likes and dislikes" },
	{ "question": "感度", "answers": [ "かんど" ], "comment": "sensitivity; reception (e.g. radio and television); severity (quake)" },
	{ "question": "感慨", "answers": [ "かんがい" ], "comment": "strong feelings; deep emotion" },
	{ "question": "感染", "answers": [ "かんせん" ], "comment": "infection; contagion" },
	{ "question": "感無量", "answers": [ "かんむりょう" ], "comment": "deep feeling; inexpressible feeling; filled with emotion" },
	{ "question": "感触", "answers": [ "かんしょく" ], "comment": "feel (i.e. tactile sensation); touch; feeling; sensation; texture (e.g. food, cloth)" },
	{ "question": "態勢", "answers": [ "たいせい" ], "comment": "attitude; posture; preparedness; readiness" },
	{ "question": "慌ただしい", "answers": [ "あわただしい" ], "comment": "busy; hurried; confused; flurried" },
	{ "question": "慌てる", "answers": [ "あわてる" ], "comment": "to become confused (disconcerted, disorganized, disorganised); to be flustered; to panic\nto be in a hurry; to rush" },
	{ "question": "慎む", "answers": [ "つつしむ" ], "comment": "to be careful; to be discreet\nto do in moderation; to refrain (from overdoing); to abstain\nto be purified; to be chaste" },
	{ "question": "慕う", "answers": [ "したう" ], "comment": "to yearn for; to long for; to pine for; to miss; to love dearly; to adore\nto follow (someone)\nto idolize (for virtue, learning, status, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "慣らす", "answers": [ "ならす" ], "comment": "to accustom; to train (e.g. one's ear)\nto tame; to domesticate; to train (e.g. an animal)" },
	{ "question": "慣れ", "answers": [ "なれ" ], "comment": "practice; practising; experience" },
	{ "question": "慣例", "answers": [ "かんれい" ], "comment": "custom; precedent; of convention" },
	{ "question": "慣用", "answers": [ "かんよう" ], "comment": "common; customary" },
	{ "question": "慣習", "answers": [ "かんしゅう" ], "comment": "usual (historical) custom" },
	{ "question": "慣行", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "customary practice; habit; traditional event" },
	{ "question": "憂鬱", "answers": [ "ゆううつ" ], "comment": "depression; melancholy; dejection; gloom" },
	{ "question": "憎しみ", "answers": [ "にくしみ" ], "comment": "hatred" },
	{ "question": "憤慨", "answers": [ "ふんがい" ], "comment": "indignation; resentment" },
	{ "question": "憧れ", "answers": [ "あこがれ" ], "comment": "yearning; longing; aspiration" },
	{ "question": "懐く", "answers": [ "なつく" ], "comment": "to become emotionally attached\nto embrace; to hold in the arms (e.g. a baby); to hug\nto harbour (e.g. grudge); to harbor; to bear; to have (e.g. ambition); to entertain (e.g. hope, suspicion)\nto have sex with; to make love to; to sleep with\nto sit on eggs" },
	{ "question": "懲りる", "answers": [ "こりる" ], "comment": "to learn by experience; to learn one's lesson; to learn the hard way\nto have enough (of); to be disgusted with" },
	{ "question": "懸想", "answers": [ "けそう" ], "comment": "falling in love; attachment" },
	{ "question": "懸賞", "answers": [ "けんしょう" ], "comment": "offering prizes; winning; reward" },
	{ "question": "成り立つ", "answers": [ "なりたつ" ], "comment": "to consist of; to be made up of; to be composed of\nto be practical (logical, feasible, viable); to be concluded; to hold true" },
	{ "question": "成るべく", "answers": [ "なるべく" ], "comment": "as much as possible; wherever practicable" },
	{ "question": "成る丈", "answers": [ "なるたけ" ], "comment": "as much as possible; if possible" },
	{ "question": "成年", "answers": [ "せいねん" ], "comment": "adult age; majority" },
	{ "question": "成果", "answers": [ "せいか" ], "comment": "fruits (of one's labors); results; outcome; accomplishment" },
	{ "question": "成熟", "answers": [ "せいじゅく" ], "comment": "maturity; ripeness" },
	{ "question": "我がまま", "answers": [ "わがまま" ], "comment": "selfishness; egoism; self-indulgence; wilfulness; willfulness\ndisobedience\nwhim" },
	{ "question": "戦", "answers": [ "いくさ" ], "comment": "war; battle; campaign; fight\ntroops; forces\nwar; battle\nmatch; competition" },
	{ "question": "戦力", "answers": [ "せんりょく" ], "comment": "war potential; military strength; fighting power\nability (to compete); capabilities; valuable asset" },
	{ "question": "戦災", "answers": [ "せんさい" ], "comment": "war damage" },
	{ "question": "戦術", "answers": [ "せんじゅつ" ], "comment": "tactics" },
	{ "question": "戦闘", "answers": [ "せんとう" ], "comment": "battle; fight; combat" },
	{ "question": "戯曲", "answers": [ "ぎきょく" ], "comment": "play; drama" },
	{ "question": "戸", "answers": [ "と", "こ" ], "comment": "door (esp. Japanese-style)\nshutter; window shutter\nentrance (to a home)\nnarrows\ncounter for houses, households, apartments, etc." },
	{ "question": "戸籍", "answers": [ "こせき" ], "comment": "family register\ncensus" },
	{ "question": "戸締り", "answers": [ "とじまり" ], "comment": "closing up; fastening the doors" },
	{ "question": "所々", "answers": [ "ところどころ", "しょしょ" ], "comment": "here and there; some parts (of something); several places" },
	{ "question": "所が", "answers": [ "ところが" ], "comment": "even so; however; still; whereupon; even though; nevertheless; on the contrary; as a matter of fact; despite" },
	{ "question": "所で", "answers": [ "ところで" ], "comment": "by the way; incidentally\neven if; no matter (who, what, when, where, why, how)" },
	{ "question": "所在", "answers": [ "しょざい" ], "comment": "whereabouts" },
	{ "question": "所定", "answers": [ "しょてい" ], "comment": "fixed; prescribed; certain; given" },
	{ "question": "所属", "answers": [ "しょぞく" ], "comment": "attached to; belong to; member; affiliation" },
	{ "question": "所得", "answers": [ "しょとく" ], "comment": "income; earnings" },
	{ "question": "所持", "answers": [ "しょじ" ], "comment": "possession; owning" },
	{ "question": "扉", "answers": [ "とびら" ], "comment": "door; gate; opening\ntitle page" },
	{ "question": "手元", "answers": [ "てもと" ], "comment": "at hand; on hand; nearby; close at hand\nway of moving one's arms; skill\nmoney at hand; pocket money\ngrip; handle" },
	{ "question": "手分け", "answers": [ "てわけ" ], "comment": "division of labour; division of labor; splitting into groups (e.g. to search)" },
	{ "question": "手回し", "answers": [ "てまわし" ], "comment": "turning by hand; hand-turned; hand-cranked\npreparations; arrangements" },
	{ "question": "手引き", "answers": [ "てびき" ], "comment": "guidance; guide; introduction; guideline" },
	{ "question": "手当て", "answers": [ "てあて" ], "comment": "salary; pay; compensation; allowance (e.g. housing allowance); benefit; bonus\nmedical care; treatment\nadvance preparation" },
	{ "question": "手掛かり", "answers": [ "てがかり" ], "comment": "clue; lead; key; trail; scent; track\nhandhold; hold" },
	{ "question": "手掛ける", "answers": [ "てがける" ], "comment": "to handle; to manage; to deal with; to work with; to have experience with\nto rear; to look after" },
	{ "question": "手数", "answers": [ "てすう", "てかず" ], "comment": "trouble; bother\nnumber of moves (in go, shogi, etc.)\nnumber of punches (in boxing)" },
	{ "question": "手本", "answers": [ "てほん" ], "comment": "copybook\nmodel; pattern" },
	{ "question": "手法", "answers": [ "しゅほう" ], "comment": "technique; method" },
	{ "question": "手芸", "answers": [ "しゅげい" ], "comment": "handicrafts" },
	{ "question": "手軽", "answers": [ "てがる" ], "comment": "easy; simple; informal; offhand; cheap" },
	{ "question": "手近", "answers": [ "てぢか" ], "comment": "near; close by; within reach; handy\nfamiliar" },
	{ "question": "手遅れ", "answers": [ "ておくれ" ], "comment": "being (too) late\nbelated treatment" },
	{ "question": "手配", "answers": [ "てはい" ], "comment": "arrangement; preparations\nsearch (by police)" },
	{ "question": "手錠", "answers": [ "てじょう" ], "comment": "handcuffs; manacles" },
	{ "question": "手際", "answers": [ "てぎわ" ], "comment": "performance; skill; tact" },
	{ "question": "手順", "answers": [ "てじゅん" ], "comment": "process; procedure; sequence; protocol; instruction" },
	{ "question": "打ち切る", "answers": [ "うちきる" ], "comment": "to stop; to abort; to discontinue; to close" },
	{ "question": "打ち合わせ", "answers": [ "うちあわせ" ], "comment": "advance arrangements; preparatory meeting; briefing session\noverlap (of a coat, etc.)\nmaking something match exactly" },
	{ "question": "打ち合わせる", "answers": [ "うちあわせる" ], "comment": "to knock together\nto arrange (e.g. a meeting)" },
	{ "question": "打ち消し", "answers": [ "うちけし" ], "comment": "negation; denial; negative" },
	{ "question": "打ち込む", "answers": [ "うちこむ" ], "comment": "to drive in (e.g. nail, stake); to hammer in\nto hit (a ball, etc.); to drive; to smash\nto fire into (e.g. a crowd); to launch (e.g. missiles); to lob (e.g. grenades)\nto input (data); to enter\nto devote oneself to; to go heart and soul into; to throw oneself into; to go head over heels for\nto practice hitting (baseball, tennis, etc.)\nto hit (an opponent in kendo, boxing, etc.); to get a blow in\nto invade one's opponent's territory (in the game of go); to place a stone in an opponent's formation\nto pour (concrete, etc.) into a form\nto throw; to toss; to cast\nto hit; to strike; to smash; to hammer in; to drive in\nto fire into (e.g. a crowd); to launch (e.g. missiles); to lob (e.g. grenades)\nto wear (sword, etc.); to carry" },
	{ "question": "打付ける", "answers": [ "ぶつける" ], "comment": "to nail\nto knock; to bang (e.g. one's head); to strike (hard)\nto throw (e.g. a rock); to fling\nto hit (e.g. one's head); to strike; to crash into\nto throw (e.g. a ball, a question, a demand)\nto express; to vent (e.g. one's anger)" },
	{ "question": "打撃", "answers": [ "だげき" ], "comment": "blow; shock; strike; damage\nbatting" },
	{ "question": "打開", "answers": [ "だかい" ], "comment": "break in the deadlock" },
	{ "question": "扱い", "answers": [ "あつかい" ], "comment": "treatment; service" },
	{ "question": "扶養", "answers": [ "ふよう" ], "comment": "support (family, esp. dependents: children or spouse); maintenance" },
	{ "question": "承諾", "answers": [ "しょうだく" ], "comment": "consent; acquiescence; agreement" },
	{ "question": "技", "answers": [ "ギ", "わざ" ], "comment": "technique; art; skill" },
	{ "question": "技能", "answers": [ "ぎのう" ], "comment": "technical skill; ability; capacity" },
	{ "question": "把握", "answers": [ "はあく" ], "comment": "grasp; catch; understanding" },
	{ "question": "抑制", "answers": [ "よくせい" ], "comment": "control; restraint; suppression; constraint; curtailment; inhibition; check; curb" },
	{ "question": "抑圧", "answers": [ "よくあつ" ], "comment": "check; restraint; oppression; suppression" },
	{ "question": "投げ出す", "answers": [ "なげだす" ], "comment": "to throw down; to throw out; to stretch out (one's legs)\nto abandon; to resign\nto give freely; to give generously; to sacrifice (e.g. one's life)\nto start to throw" },
	{ "question": "投入", "answers": [ "とうにゅう" ], "comment": "throwing into; inserting; depositing\ninvestment; putting in (personnel, etc.)\nrelease of a product\nmaking (an electrical circuit)" },
	{ "question": "投資", "answers": [ "とうし" ], "comment": "investment" },
	{ "question": "抗争", "answers": [ "こうそう" ], "comment": "dispute; resistance" },
	{ "question": "抗議", "answers": [ "こうぎ" ], "comment": "protest; objection" },
	{ "question": "折り返す", "answers": [ "おりかえす" ], "comment": "to turn up; to fold back\nto loopback (a signal, a message)" },
	{ "question": "折衷", "answers": [ "せっちゅう" ], "comment": "compromise; cross; blending; eclecticism" },
	{ "question": "抜かす", "answers": [ "ぬかす" ], "comment": "to omit; to leave out; to skip\nto say; to speak" },
	{ "question": "抜け出す", "answers": [ "ぬけだす" ], "comment": "to slip out; to sneak away; to excel\nto break (out of a loop)" },
	{ "question": "押さえる", "answers": [ "おさえる" ], "comment": "to pin something down; to hold something down; to hold something back; to stop; to restrain; to curb\nto seize; to grasp; to arrest\nto gain control of something; to govern; to keep down (e.g. information); to suppress\nto catch happening; to determine (important points); to find (proof); to understand" },
	{ "question": "押し寄せる", "answers": [ "おしよせる" ], "comment": "to advance on; to close in; to march on; to descend on (the enemy); to move towards; to surge forward (crowd, wave of nostalgia, wave, etc.); to rush for (the door); to inundate; to overwhelm; to push aside" },
	{ "question": "押し込む", "answers": [ "おしこむ" ], "comment": "to push into; to cram into; to stuff into; to crowd into\nto break in; to burgle; to burglarize" },
	{ "question": "抽選", "answers": [ "ちゅうせん" ], "comment": "lottery; raffle; drawing (of lots)" },
	{ "question": "担う", "answers": [ "になう" ], "comment": "to carry on shoulder; to shoulder (gun)\nto bear (burden, responsibility, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "担架", "answers": [ "たんか" ], "comment": "stretcher; litter" },
	{ "question": "拒否", "answers": [ "きょひ" ], "comment": "denial; veto; rejection; refusal" },
	{ "question": "拒絶", "answers": [ "きょぜつ" ], "comment": "refusal; rejection" },
	{ "question": "拘束", "answers": [ "こうそく" ], "comment": "restriction; restraint; binding; constraint" },
	{ "question": "招き", "answers": [ "まねき" ], "comment": "invitation" },
	{ "question": "拝借", "answers": [ "はいしゃく" ], "comment": "borrowing" },
	{ "question": "拝啓", "answers": [ "はいけい" ], "comment": "Dear (so and so); Dear Sir; Dear Madam; To Whom It May Concern" },
	{ "question": "拡散", "answers": [ "かくさん" ], "comment": "scattering; diffusion; spread (e.g. signal across the spectrum)" },
	{ "question": "持ち", "answers": [ "もち" ], "comment": "hold; charge; keep possession; in charge\nwear; durability; life; draw\nusage" },
	{ "question": "持ち切り", "answers": [ "もちきり" ], "comment": "hot topic; talk of the town" },
	{ "question": "持てる", "answers": [ "もてる" ], "comment": "to be able to possess (hold, get, etc.)\nto be well liked; to be popular; to be pampered (spoiled, doted upon, etc.); to be welcomed\nto endure (the tests of time, the elements, etc.); to last\npossessed\npossessing riches; having wealth" },
	{ "question": "持て成す", "answers": [ "もてなす" ], "comment": "to entertain; to make welcome" },
	{ "question": "持続", "answers": [ "じぞく" ], "comment": "continuation; persisting; lasting; sustaining; enduring" },
	{ "question": "指令", "answers": [ "しれい" ], "comment": "orders; instructions; directive; command" },
	{ "question": "指図", "answers": [ "さしず" ], "comment": "instruction; mandate; directions" },
	{ "question": "指差す", "answers": [ "ゆびさす" ], "comment": "to point at" },
	{ "question": "指揮", "answers": [ "しき" ], "comment": "command; direction" },
	{ "question": "指摘", "answers": [ "してき" ], "comment": "pointing out; identification" },
	{ "question": "指示", "answers": [ "しじ" ], "comment": "indication; denotation; designation\ninstructions; directions" },
	{ "question": "挑む", "answers": [ "いどむ" ], "comment": "to challenge; to throw down the gauntlet; to contend for; to tackle\nto pressure someone for sex; to woo; to make love to" },
	{ "question": "挑戦", "answers": [ "ちょうせん" ], "comment": "challenge; defiance; dare; attempt; try" },
	{ "question": "振り", "answers": [ "ふり" ], "comment": "swing; shake; wave; swinging\nappearance; behaviour\npretence (pretense); show; pretending (to)\ngoing to restaurant, hotel etc. without a reservation or introduction\nmove (dance); postures\nlead in (e.g. to a running joke, asking a question); lead up\nunsewn part of a hanging sleeve on a traditional Japanese woman's garment\ncounter for swords, blades, etc.\nnot wearing underwear or pants\nstyle; manner\nafter (period of time) again (e.g. meeting again after a year); for the first time in (period of time)" },
	{ "question": "振り出し", "answers": [ "ふりだし" ], "comment": "starting point; beginning; outset\ndrawing; issuing; draft; draught\nshaking out\nthrow (of dice); toss\ninfusion" },
	{ "question": "振動", "answers": [ "しんどう" ], "comment": "oscillation; vibration" },
	{ "question": "振興", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "promotion; encouragement" },
	{ "question": "捕らえる", "answers": [ "とらえる" ], "comment": "to catch; to capture; to seize; to arrest; to grab; to catch hold of\nto grasp (e.g. meaning); to perceive; to capture (e.g. features)\nto captivate; to move (one's heart)" },
	{ "question": "捕獲", "answers": [ "ほかく" ], "comment": "capture; seizure" },
	{ "question": "捕虜", "answers": [ "ほりょ" ], "comment": "prisoner (of war)" },
	{ "question": "捕鯨", "answers": [ "ほげい" ], "comment": "whaling; whale fishing" },
	{ "question": "捜査", "answers": [ "そうさ" ], "comment": "search (esp. in criminal investigations); investigation; inquiry; enquiry" },
	{ "question": "捜索", "answers": [ "そうさく" ], "comment": "search (esp. for someone or something missing); manhunt\nlegally authorized search of a person, building, etc." },
	{ "question": "据える", "answers": [ "すえる" ], "comment": "to place (in position); to fix; to set (e.g. table); to lay (foundation)\nto install; to seat (someone)\nto settle (upon something); to fix (e.g. one's gaze)\nto apply (moxa)" },
	{ "question": "据え付ける", "answers": [ "すえつける" ], "comment": "to install; to equip; to mount" },
	{ "question": "授ける", "answers": [ "さずける" ], "comment": "to grant; to award; to teach" },
	{ "question": "掌", "answers": [ "てのひら", "たなごころ" ], "comment": "palm (of one's hand)" },
	{ "question": "排水", "answers": [ "はいすい" ], "comment": "drainage" },
	{ "question": "排除", "answers": [ "はいじょ" ], "comment": "exclusion; removal; rejection; elimination; abatement; lifting (sanctions, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "掛け", "answers": [ "かけ" ], "comment": "credit\nmoney owed on an account; bill\nhot noodles in broth\nproportion (of wholesale price, as tenths of list price)\nin the midst of\nrest; rack; hanger\n-clad\nin the midst of\ntenths (e.g. wholesale price, as tenths of retail price)\ntimes (i.e. multiplied by)\nable-to-seat (of a chair, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "採択", "answers": [ "さいたく" ], "comment": "adoption; selection; choice" },
	{ "question": "採掘", "answers": [ "さいくつ" ], "comment": "mining" },
	{ "question": "採決", "answers": [ "さいけつ" ], "comment": "vote; roll call" },
	{ "question": "採用", "answers": [ "さいよう" ], "comment": "use; adoption; acceptance\nappointment; employment; engagement; recruitment" },
	{ "question": "採算", "answers": [ "さいさん" ], "comment": "profit" },
	{ "question": "採集", "answers": [ "さいしゅう" ], "comment": "collecting; gathering" },
	{ "question": "探検", "answers": [ "たんけん" ], "comment": "exploration; expedition" },
	{ "question": "接ぐ", "answers": [ "つぐ" ], "comment": "to join\nto piece together\nto set (bones)\nto graft (trees)\nto join (cloth, wood, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "接続詞", "answers": [ "せつぞくし" ], "comment": "conjunction" },
	{ "question": "接触", "answers": [ "せっしょく" ], "comment": "touch; contact" },
	{ "question": "控える", "answers": [ "ひかえる" ], "comment": "to be temperate in; to refrain; to abstain; to hold back; to restrain oneself from excessive ...\nto make notes; to jot down (e.g. phone number)\nto be in preparation for; to be in waiting for\nto be soon; to be in the offing\nto be in a close relationship (e.g. as a backer, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "控室", "answers": [ "ひかえしつ" ], "comment": "waiting room" },
	{ "question": "控除", "answers": [ "こうじょ" ], "comment": "subtraction; deduction (e.g. tax); subsidy" },
	{ "question": "推測", "answers": [ "すいそく" ], "comment": "guess; conjecture" },
	{ "question": "推理", "answers": [ "すいり" ], "comment": "reasoning; inference; mystery or detective genre (movie, novel, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "推薦", "answers": [ "すいせん" ], "comment": "recommendation; referral; endorsement" },
	{ "question": "推進", "answers": [ "すいしん" ], "comment": "propulsion; drive\npromotion (e.g. of a government policy); furtherance; implementation" },
	{ "question": "措置", "answers": [ "そち" ], "comment": "measure; step; action" },
	{ "question": "掲げる", "answers": [ "かかげる" ], "comment": "to publish; to print; to carry (an article)\nto put up; to hang out; to hoist; to fly (a sail); to float (a flag, kite, etc.)\nto tuck up (e.g. sleeves); to roll up\nto tout (a principle, plan, etc.); to adopt (a slogan)\nto stoke a fire; to fan a flame" },
	{ "question": "掲載", "answers": [ "けいさい" ], "comment": "publication (e.g. article in paper); appearance; insertion\nto insert (e.g. an article); to run (e.g. in a newspaper); to carry (e.g. an article); to post (e.g. on the Web)" },
	{ "question": "描写", "answers": [ "びょうしゃ" ], "comment": "depiction; description; portrayal" },
	{ "question": "提供", "answers": [ "ていきょう" ], "comment": "offer; tender; program sponsoring; programme sponsoring; furnishing; provisioning; supply" },
	{ "question": "提携", "answers": [ "ていけい" ], "comment": "cooperation; tie-up; joint business; link-up; sponsorship" },
	{ "question": "提示", "answers": [ "ていじ" ], "comment": "presentation; exhibit; suggest; citation" },
	{ "question": "換算", "answers": [ "かんさん" ], "comment": "conversion (e.g. yen to dollars); change; exchange; translation (numerical)" },
	{ "question": "揺さぶる", "answers": [ "ゆさぶる" ], "comment": "to shake; to jolt; to rock; to swing" },
	{ "question": "揺らぐ", "answers": [ "ゆらぐ" ], "comment": "to swing; to sway; to shake; to tremble\nto waver; to feel shaken; to become unstable" },
	{ "question": "揺れる", "answers": [ "ゆれる" ], "comment": "to shake; to sway; to waver" },
	{ "question": "損なう", "answers": [ "そこなう" ], "comment": "to harm; to hurt; to injure; to damage; to spoil; to mar\nto fail to ...; to miss one's opportunity to ..." },
	{ "question": "損失", "answers": [ "そんしつ" ], "comment": "loss (e.g. assets or profits)" },
	{ "question": "携わる", "answers": [ "たずさわる" ], "comment": "to engage in; to participate; to take part" },
	{ "question": "携帯", "answers": [ "けいたい" ], "comment": "something carried (in the hand); handheld; portable\nmobile telephone; cell phone" },
	{ "question": "搾取", "answers": [ "さくしゅ" ], "comment": "exploitation; squeezing; sweating" },
	{ "question": "摂取", "answers": [ "せっしゅ" ], "comment": "intake; absorption; adoption\nassimilation" },
	{ "question": "摘む", "answers": [ "つむ", "つまむ" ], "comment": "to pluck; to pick; to trim\nto pinch; to hold; to pick up" },
	{ "question": "操る", "answers": [ "あやつる" ], "comment": "to manipulate; to operate; to handle; to operate (e.g. a machine); to steer (a ship)\nto have a good command of (a language); to be fluent in\nto operate a puppet; to pull the strings of a puppet\nto mastermind; to pull the strings; to control from the shadows\nto play (a musical instrument)" },
	{ "question": "操縦", "answers": [ "そうじゅう" ], "comment": "steering; piloting; flying; control; operation; handling\nmanagement; handling; control; manipulation" },
	{ "question": "擦る", "answers": [ "こする", "する", "なする", "なぞる", "かする", "さする" ], "comment": "to rub; to scrub\nto pat; to stroke\nto rub off; to polish; to grind; to graze; to scrape\nto be equal to\nto be about to reach\nto rub; to chafe; to strike (match); to file; to frost (glass)\nto lose (e.g. a match); to forfeit; to squander one's money (e.g. through gambling, Pachinko, etc.)\nto graze; to touch lightly\nto take a percentage; to exploit; to squeeze\nto rub in; to smear on; to spread on; to daub\nto lay the blame on" },
	{ "question": "擦れ違い", "answers": [ "すれちがい" ], "comment": "passing each other; crossing paths without meeting; being at cross purposes" },
	{ "question": "支持", "answers": [ "しじ" ], "comment": "support; holding up; propping\nsupport; backing; endorsing" },
	{ "question": "改まる", "answers": [ "あらたまる" ], "comment": "to be renewed\nto stand on ceremony; to be formal\nto take a turn for the worse" },
	{ "question": "改修", "answers": [ "かいしゅう" ], "comment": "repair; improvement" },
	{ "question": "改宗", "answers": [ "かいしゅう" ], "comment": "religious conversion" },
	{ "question": "改定", "answers": [ "かいてい" ], "comment": "revision (of a rule, price, etc.); reform; alteration; change" },
	{ "question": "改悪", "answers": [ "かいあく" ], "comment": "deterioration; changing for the worse" },
	{ "question": "改良", "answers": [ "かいりょう" ], "comment": "improvement; reform" },
	{ "question": "改訂", "answers": [ "かいてい" ], "comment": "revision (of text); alteration; change" },
	{ "question": "改革", "answers": [ "かいかく" ], "comment": "reform; reformation; innovation" },
	{ "question": "攻め", "answers": [ "せめ" ], "comment": "attack; offence; offense\ndominant partner of a homosexual relationship\na barrage of; a flood of" },
	{ "question": "放り出す", "answers": [ "ほうりだす" ], "comment": "to throw out\nto drop; to toss; to dump\nto abandon; to neglect; to leave behind; to give up\nto dismiss; to fire; to expel\nto expel; to eject; to push out; to force out" },
	{ "question": "放り込む", "answers": [ "ほうりこむ" ], "comment": "to throw into; to toss into" },
	{ "question": "放出", "answers": [ "ほうしゅつ" ], "comment": "release; emission; ejection" },
	{ "question": "放射", "answers": [ "ほうしゃ" ], "comment": "radiation; emission" },
	{ "question": "放射能", "answers": [ "ほうしゃのう" ], "comment": "radioactivity" },
	{ "question": "放棄", "answers": [ "ほうき" ], "comment": "abandonment; renunciation; resignation; abdication (responsibility, right)" },
	{ "question": "放置", "answers": [ "ほうち" ], "comment": "leaving as is; leaving alone; leaving to chance; neglecting; abandoning" },
	{ "question": "政権", "answers": [ "せいけん" ], "comment": "(political) administration; political power" },
	{ "question": "政策", "answers": [ "せいさく" ], "comment": "political measures; policy" },
	{ "question": "故", "answers": [ "こ", "ゆえ" ], "comment": "used item; secondhand item\nold; used; previous\nthe late (deceased)\nreason; cause; circumstances\nintentionally; deliberately\nespecially; particularly\nformer; ex-; past; one-time" },
	{ "question": "故人", "answers": [ "こじん" ], "comment": "the deceased; the departed" },
	{ "question": "敏感", "answers": [ "びんかん" ], "comment": "sensitive; alert; aware; susceptible" },
	{ "question": "救い", "answers": [ "すくい" ], "comment": "help; aid; relief; (religious) salvation; (Christian) grace; providence" },
	{ "question": "救援", "answers": [ "きゅうえん" ], "comment": "relief; rescue; reinforcement" },
	{ "question": "救済", "answers": [ "きゅうさい" ], "comment": "relief; aid; rescue; salvation; help\nsalvation (from suffering based on Buddha's teachings)" },
	{ "question": "敗戦", "answers": [ "はいせん" ], "comment": "defeat; losing a war" },
	{ "question": "教え", "answers": [ "おしえ" ], "comment": "teaching; instruction; teachings; precept; lesson; doctrine" },
	{ "question": "教員", "answers": [ "きょういん" ], "comment": "teacher; instructor; teaching staff; faculty member" },
	{ "question": "教材", "answers": [ "きょうざい" ], "comment": "teaching materials" },
	{ "question": "教科", "answers": [ "きょうか" ], "comment": "subject; curriculum" },
	{ "question": "教習", "answers": [ "きょうしゅう" ], "comment": "training; instruction" },
	{ "question": "教職", "answers": [ "きょうしょく" ], "comment": "the teaching profession\n(in Christianity) education of laity" },
	{ "question": "教訓", "answers": [ "きょうくん" ], "comment": "lesson; precept; teachings; moral" },
	{ "question": "敢えて", "answers": [ "あえて" ], "comment": "purposely (of something needless, unexpected or seemingly counterproductive, etc.); daringly (doing something); deliberately; intentionally\nnot necessarily; not particularly; not especially\ndefinitely not" },
	{ "question": "敬具", "answers": [ "けいぐ" ], "comment": "Yours sincerely; Yours truly; Sincerely yours" },
	{ "question": "数詞", "answers": [ "すうし" ], "comment": "numeral" },
	{ "question": "整える", "answers": [ "ととのえる" ], "comment": "to put in order; to arrange; to adjust\nto get ready; to prepare\nto raise money" },
	{ "question": "整列", "answers": [ "せいれつ" ], "comment": "standing in a row; forming a line; alignment" },
	{ "question": "整然", "answers": [ "せいぜん" ], "comment": "orderly; regular; systematic; well-organized; well-organised; trim; tidy; accurate" },
	{ "question": "敵", "answers": [ "かたき", "てき" ], "comment": "rival; opponent; adversary; competitor; enemy (esp. one with which there is longstanding enmity); foe\nrevenge\nspouse\nopponent; rival; adversary\nmenace; danger; threat; enemy" },
	{ "question": "文", "answers": [ "ぶん", "ふみ" ], "comment": "letter; writings\nsentence\ncomposition; text; writings\nthe literary arts (as opposed to the military arts); academia; literature\nfigure; design\nstyle (of writing); figure (of speech)\ndesign; plot; plan\nminor market fluctuation; technical correction\ncat's cradle\nlease rod (in a loom)\none-thousandth of a kan (obsolete unit of currency)\n2.4 cm (traditional unit used to measure shoe sizes)\nletter; character; sentence\nscripture; incantation" },
	{ "question": "文化財", "answers": [ "ぶんかざい" ], "comment": "cultural assets; cultural property" },
	{ "question": "文書", "answers": [ "ぶんしょ" ], "comment": "document; writing; letter; paperwork; note; records; archives\ndocument addressed to someone in particular (jargon used in paleography)" },
	{ "question": "文語", "answers": [ "ぶんご" ], "comment": "written language; literary language\nformal (or archaic) written style based on Heian-period Japanese" },
	{ "question": "斑", "answers": [ "ハン", "まだら", "むら", "ぶち", "ふ" ], "comment": "uneven; irregular; speckled; mottled\nerratic; inconsistent\nfickle; capricious; fitful\nspots; speckles; mottles\nspots; speckles; mottles\nspeckled; spotted" },
	{ "question": "料", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "fee; charge; rate\nmaterial\nornament; adornment; decoration" },
	{ "question": "斜面", "answers": [ "しゃめん" ], "comment": "slope; slanting surface; bevel" },
	{ "question": "断然", "answers": [ "だんぜん" ], "comment": "firmly; absolutely; definitely; flatly; far and away; by far; by a long shot; hands down" },
	{ "question": "断言", "answers": [ "だんげん" ], "comment": "assertion; declaration; affirmation" },
	{ "question": "断面", "answers": [ "だんめん" ], "comment": "cross-section" },
	{ "question": "新", "answers": [ "しん", "さら" ], "comment": "new; neo-\nGregorian calendar\nXin (dynasty of China)\nnew; unused\nnew" },
	{ "question": "新人", "answers": [ "しんじん" ], "comment": "new face; newcomer; rookie; fresh recruit\nmodern humans (from Cro-Magnon man onwards)" },
	{ "question": "新入生", "answers": [ "しんにゅうせい" ], "comment": "new student; freshman; first-year student" },
	{ "question": "新婚", "answers": [ "しんこん" ], "comment": "newly-wed" },
	{ "question": "新築", "answers": [ "しんちく" ], "comment": "new building; new construction" },
	{ "question": "新興", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "rising; developing; emergent" },
	{ "question": "方式", "answers": [ "ほうしき" ], "comment": "form; method; system; formula" },
	{ "question": "方策", "answers": [ "ほうさく" ], "comment": "plan; policy" },
	{ "question": "施す", "answers": [ "ほどこす" ], "comment": "to give (time, money, goods); to donate\nto do; to perform; to conduct\nto apply (processing, makeup, etc.); to add (e.g. ornamentation, annotation)\nto sow; to seed; to scatter (e.g. fertilizer); to sprinkle\nto spread far and wide" },
	{ "question": "施行", "answers": [ "しこう", "せこう", "（せぎょう）" ], "comment": "execution; enforcing; carrying out\ngiving alms; giving food to the poor or monks" },
	{ "question": "施設", "answers": [ "しせつ" ], "comment": "institution; establishment; facility\n(army) engineer" },
	{ "question": "旅券", "answers": [ "りょけん" ], "comment": "passport" },
	{ "question": "旅客", "answers": [ "りょかく" ], "comment": "passenger (transport)" },
	{ "question": "既婚", "answers": [ "きこん" ], "comment": "marriage; married" },
	{ "question": "日々", "answers": [ "ひび" ], "comment": "every day; daily; day after day; days (e.g. good old days)" },
	{ "question": "日の丸", "answers": [ "ひのまる" ], "comment": "outline of the sun (esp. represented as a red circle)\nthe Japanese flag" },
	{ "question": "日付", "answers": [ "ひづけ" ], "comment": "date; dating" },
	{ "question": "日取り", "answers": [ "ひどり" ], "comment": "fixed date; appointed day" },
	{ "question": "日向", "answers": [ "ひなた" ], "comment": "sunny place; in the sun" },
	{ "question": "日夜", "answers": [ "にちや" ], "comment": "day and night; always" },
	{ "question": "日当", "answers": [ "にっとう" ], "comment": "daily allowance; daily wages\nexposure to the sun; sunny place\nper day" },
	{ "question": "日焼け", "answers": [ "ひやけ" ], "comment": "sunburn; suntan; tan\nbecoming discolored from the sun (e.g. paper); yellowing" },
	{ "question": "日頃", "answers": [ "ひごろ" ], "comment": "normally; habitually" },
	{ "question": "旦那", "answers": [ "だんな" ], "comment": "master (of a house, shop, etc.)\nhusband (informal)\nsir; boss; master; governor; word used to address a male patron, customer, or person of high status\npatron of a mistress, geisha, bar or nightclub hostess; sugar daddy\nalms; almsgiving; almsgiver" },
	{ "question": "旧事", "answers": [ "きゅうじ", "くじ" ], "comment": "past events; bygones" },
	{ "question": "旧知", "answers": [ "きゅうち" ], "comment": "old friend; old friendship" },
	{ "question": "早める", "answers": [ "はやめる" ], "comment": "to hasten; to quicken; to expedite; to precipitate; to accelerate" },
	{ "question": "早急", "answers": [ "さっきゅう", "そうきゅう" ], "comment": "immediate; prompt; quick; rapid; urgent; pressing" },
	{ "question": "昆虫", "answers": [ "こんちゅう" ], "comment": "insect; bug" },
	{ "question": "昇進", "answers": [ "しょうしん" ], "comment": "promotion; advancement; rising in rank" },
	{ "question": "明々後日", "answers": [ "しあさって", "みょうみょうごにち" ], "comment": "in three days' time; two days after tomorrow" },
	{ "question": "明かす", "answers": [ "あかす" ], "comment": "to pass (e.g. the night); to spend\nto reveal; to divulge" },
	{ "question": "明くる", "answers": [ "あくる" ], "comment": "next; following" },
	{ "question": "明るい", "answers": [ "あかるい" ], "comment": "bright; colourful\ncheerful\nfamiliar (with); knowledgeable (about)\nfair (e.g. politics); clean" },
	{ "question": "明後日", "answers": [ "あさって", "（みょうごにち）" ], "comment": "day after tomorrow" },
	{ "question": "明朗", "answers": [ "めいろう" ], "comment": "cheerful; bright\nclear; clean; honest; fair" },
	{ "question": "明白", "answers": [ "めいはく", "あからさま" ], "comment": "obvious; clear; plain; evident; apparent; explicit; overt\nplain; frank; candid; open; direct; straightforward; unabashed; blatant; flagrant" },
	{ "question": "明瞭", "answers": [ "めいりょう" ], "comment": "clarity; clearness" },
	{ "question": "易い", "answers": [ "やすい" ], "comment": "easy\nlikely to ...; have a tendency to ...\neasy to ..." },
	{ "question": "星座", "answers": [ "せいざ" ], "comment": "constellation; star sign; zodiac sign" },
	{ "question": "映える", "answers": [ "はえる" ], "comment": "to shine; to look attractive; to look pretty" },
	{ "question": "映像", "answers": [ "えいぞう" ], "comment": "reflection; image; picture (e.g. on a television); shot\nvideo; film; footage; clip; video recording\nimage in one's mind; mental picture" },
	{ "question": "映写", "answers": [ "えいしゃ" ], "comment": "projection" },
	{ "question": "是正", "answers": [ "ぜせい" ], "comment": "correction; revision; redressing; rectifying" },
	{ "question": "是非とも", "answers": [ "ぜひとも" ], "comment": "by all means (with sense of not taking \"no\" for an answer)" },
	{ "question": "昼間", "answers": [ "ひるま", "ちゅうかん" ], "comment": "daytime; during the day; time from sunrise until sunset; diurnal period" },
	{ "question": "昼飯", "answers": [ "ひるめし", "ちゅうはん" ], "comment": "lunch; midday meal" },
	{ "question": "時刻表", "answers": [ "じこくひょう" ], "comment": "table; diagram; chart; timetable; schedule" },
	{ "question": "時差", "answers": [ "じさ" ], "comment": "time difference" },
	{ "question": "時折", "answers": [ "ときおり" ], "comment": "sometimes" },
	{ "question": "普遍", "answers": [ "ふへん" ], "comment": "universal; general; ubiquitous; omnipresent" },
	{ "question": "普遍的", "answers": [ "ふへんてき" ], "comment": "universal; omnipresent; ubiquitous" },
	{ "question": "晴天", "answers": [ "せいてん" ], "comment": "fine weather (i.e. little or no clouds); fair weather; clear weather; clear sky; fair skies" },
	{ "question": "暇", "answers": [ "ひま", "いとま" ], "comment": "spare time; free time; leisure\ntime (e.g. time it takes to do something)\ntime off; day off; vacation; holiday; leave\nquitting (one's job); firing someone; divorcing (one's spouse)\n(of one's time) free; (of one's business) slow\nleaving; departing" },
	{ "question": "暖房", "answers": [ "だんぼう" ], "comment": "(indoor) heating" },
	{ "question": "暗殺", "answers": [ "あんさつ" ], "comment": "assassination" },
	{ "question": "暗示", "answers": [ "あんじ" ], "comment": "hint; suggestion" },
	{ "question": "暗算", "answers": [ "あんざん" ], "comment": "mental arithmetic" },
	{ "question": "暦", "answers": [ "れき", "こよみ" ], "comment": "calendar; almanac" },
	{ "question": "暴力", "answers": [ "ぼうりょく" ], "comment": "violence; mayhem" },
	{ "question": "暴動", "answers": [ "ぼうどう" ], "comment": "insurrection; rebellion; revolt; riot; uprising" },
	{ "question": "暴露", "answers": [ "ばくろ" ], "comment": "disclosure; exposure; revelation" },
	{ "question": "暴風", "answers": [ "ぼうふう" ], "comment": "storm; windstorm; gale" },
	{ "question": "曲", "answers": [ "きょく" ], "comment": "song; tune; composition; piece of music\ncorner; nook; recess\na shadow; a shade\nwickedness; evil; calamity; disaster\nlong segment of a noh play forming its musical highlight\nwrong; improper; indecent" },
	{ "question": "曲がる", "answers": [ "まがる" ], "comment": "to bend; to curve; to warp; to wind; to twist\nto turn\nto be awry; to be askew; to be crooked" },
	{ "question": "書き取り", "answers": [ "かきとり" ], "comment": "writing down from other written material; writing kanji text from hiragana\ntranscription (of spoken material)" },
	{ "question": "書き取る", "answers": [ "かきとる" ], "comment": "to write down; to take dictation; to take notes" },
	{ "question": "書評", "answers": [ "しょひょう" ], "comment": "book review" },
	{ "question": "最善", "answers": [ "さいぜん" ], "comment": "the very best" },
	{ "question": "最早", "answers": [ "もはや" ], "comment": "already; now\nno longer; not any more" },
	{ "question": "月並み", "answers": [ "つきなみ" ], "comment": "every month\ntrite; common" },
	{ "question": "月日", "answers": [ "つきひ", "がっぴ" ], "comment": "time; years; days\n(the) date" },
	{ "question": "月謝", "answers": [ "げっしゃ" ], "comment": "monthly tuition fee" },
	{ "question": "月賦", "answers": [ "げっぷ" ], "comment": "monthly installment (instalment); monthly payment" },
	{ "question": "有する", "answers": [ "ゆうする" ], "comment": "to own; to be endowed with" },
	{ "question": "有りのまま", "answers": [ "ありのまま" ], "comment": "the truth; fact; as it is; as you are; frank; bare plain" },
	{ "question": "有力", "answers": [ "ゆうりょく" ], "comment": "influential; prominent\nstrong; likely; plausible; potent" },
	{ "question": "有望", "answers": [ "ゆうぼう" ], "comment": "good prospects; full of hope; promising" },
	{ "question": "有様", "answers": [ "ありさま" ], "comment": "state; condition; circumstances; the way things are or should be; truth" },
	{ "question": "有機", "answers": [ "ゆうき" ], "comment": "organic" },
	{ "question": "有益", "answers": [ "ゆうえき" ], "comment": "beneficial; profitable" },
	{ "question": "有難う", "answers": [ "ありがとう" ], "comment": "Thank you; Thanks" },
	{ "question": "朗読", "answers": [ "ろうどく" ], "comment": "reading aloud; recitation" },
	{ "question": "望ましい", "answers": [ "のぞましい" ], "comment": "desirable; hoped for; preferable; advisable" },
	{ "question": "朝寝坊", "answers": [ "あさねぼう" ], "comment": "oversleeping; late riser" },
	{ "question": "期", "answers": [ "き", "ご" ], "comment": "period; time\nage\nterm (e.g. in office); period\nsession (e.g. of parliament)\nstage (e.g. disease)" },
	{ "question": "期日", "answers": [ "きじつ" ], "comment": "fixed date; settlement date" },
	{ "question": "期末", "answers": [ "きまつ" ], "comment": "end of term" },
	{ "question": "木綿", "answers": [ "もめん" ], "comment": "cotton (material)\nred silk-cotton tree (Bombax ceiba)\nstring made of cut steamed, soaked mulberry bark fibers" },
	{ "question": "未だ", "answers": [ "いまだ", "まだ" ], "comment": "as yet; hitherto; only; still\nnot yet (with negative verb)\nmore; besides\nunfinished; incomplete; not yet finished with" },
	{ "question": "未婚", "answers": [ "みこん" ], "comment": "unmarried" },
	{ "question": "未定", "answers": [ "みてい" ], "comment": "not yet fixed; undecided; pending" },
	{ "question": "未熟", "answers": [ "みじゅく" ], "comment": "unripe; green\ninexperienced; immature; unskilled" },
	{ "question": "未知", "answers": [ "みち" ], "comment": "not yet known; unknown; strange" },
	{ "question": "未練", "answers": [ "みれん" ], "comment": "lingering affection; attachment; regret; regrets; reluctance; ruefulness" },
	{ "question": "未開", "answers": [ "みかい" ], "comment": "savage land; backward region; uncivilized; uncivilised" },
	{ "question": "末期", "answers": [ "まっき" ], "comment": "deathbed; hour of death\nclosing years (period, days); last stage; end stage; end-of-life (care, decision making, etc.)\nterminal (e.g. cancer, disease, etc.); final" },
	{ "question": "本体", "answers": [ "ほんたい" ], "comment": "substance; real form\nmain part; main unit; body (of a machine)\nthis machine; this appliance\nobject of worship (at a shrine, temple, etc.)\nnoumenon\nbase price; pre-tax price" },
	{ "question": "本名", "answers": [ "ほんみょう", "ほんめい" ], "comment": "real name" },
	{ "question": "本場", "answers": [ "ほんば" ], "comment": "home; habitat; center; centre; best place\nauthentic; genuine" },
	{ "question": "本文", "answers": [ "ほんぶん" ], "comment": "text (of document); body (of letter)" },
	{ "question": "本格", "answers": [ "ほんかく" ], "comment": "original method or procedure\nserious; orthodox; classical; genuine" },
	{ "question": "本気", "answers": [ "ほんき" ], "comment": "seriousness; earnestness; truth; sanctity" },
	{ "question": "本能", "answers": [ "ほんのう" ], "comment": "instinct" },
	{ "question": "本質", "answers": [ "ほんしつ" ], "comment": "essence; true nature; substance; reality" },
	{ "question": "本音", "answers": [ "ほんね" ], "comment": "real intention; motive; true opinion; what one really thinks" },
	{ "question": "本館", "answers": [ "ほんかん" ], "comment": "main building" },
	{ "question": "朽ちる", "answers": [ "くちる" ], "comment": "to rot; to decay\nto die in obscurity\nto be forgotten with time" },
	{ "question": "束の間", "answers": [ "つかのま" ], "comment": "moment; brief time; brief; transient" },
	{ "question": "束縛", "answers": [ "そくばく" ], "comment": "restraint; restriction; fetters; yoke; shackles\nbinding; confinement with rope" },
	{ "question": "条約", "answers": [ "じょうやく" ], "comment": "treaty; pact" },
	{ "question": "来る", "answers": [ "くる", "きたる" ], "comment": "to come (spatially or temporally); to approach; to arrive\nto come back; to do ... and come back\nto come to be; to become; to get; to grow; to continue\nto come from; to be caused by; to derive from\nto come to (i.e. \"when it comes to spinach ...\")\nnext (e.g. \"next April\"); forthcoming; coming\nto come; to arrive; to be due to" },
	{ "question": "来場", "answers": [ "らいじょう" ], "comment": "attendance" },
	{ "question": "杯", "answers": [ "ハイ", "さかずき" ], "comment": "sake cup; cup for alcoholic beverages\nsake cup; cup for alcoholic beverages\ncounter for cupfuls\ncounter for ships, octopuses and squid\nshallow bowl" },
	{ "question": "東", "answers": [ "ひがし", "あずま" ], "comment": "eastern Japan (esp. Kamakura or Edo, from perspective of Kyoto or Nara); eastern provinces\neast\nsix-stringed Japanese zither\neast" },
	{ "question": "林業", "answers": [ "りんぎょう" ], "comment": "forestry" },
	{ "question": "枚", "answers": [ "まい" ], "comment": "counter for flat objects (e.g. sheets of paper)\nbill; handbill; flier; flyer; leaflet; poster; placard" },
	{ "question": "果たして", "answers": [ "はたして" ], "comment": "as was expected; just as one thought; sure enough; as a result\nreally? (in questions); ever?" },
	{ "question": "果たす", "answers": [ "はたす" ], "comment": "to accomplish; to achieve; to carry out; to fulfill; to fulfil; to realize; to execute; to perform; to do\nto do ... completely; to do ... entirely" },
	{ "question": "果て", "answers": [ "はて" ], "comment": "the end; the extremity; the limit; the limits; the result" },
	{ "question": "果てる", "answers": [ "はてる" ], "comment": "to end; to be finished; to be exhausted\nto die; to perish\nto do utterly; to do completely; indicates an extreme has been reached" },
	{ "question": "枠", "answers": [ "わく" ], "comment": "frame; framework\nborder; box\nlimit; restriction; quota" },
	{ "question": "染まる", "answers": [ "そまる" ], "comment": "to be dyed\nto be tainted; to be infected; to be stained; to be steeped" },
	{ "question": "染みる", "answers": [ "しみる" ], "comment": "to pierce; to penetrate; to soak in; to permeate\nto sting (wound or sensitive area, etc.); to smart; to twinge\nto be infected (with vice); to be steeped (with prejudice); to be influenced\nto feel keenly; to make a deep impression\nto have a touch of; to look like" },
	{ "question": "染める", "answers": [ "そめる" ], "comment": "to dye; to colour; to color" },
	{ "question": "柔和", "answers": [ "にゅうわ" ], "comment": "gentle; mild; meek; tender" },
	{ "question": "柔軟", "answers": [ "じゅうなん" ], "comment": "flexible; lithe; soft; pliable" },
	{ "question": "柱", "answers": [ "はしら" ], "comment": "pillar; post\nsupport; prop; mainstay\ncounter for buddhas, gods, nobles, etc.\nbridge (of a koto, etc.)\ncylinder; prism\nfret (of a biwa)" },
	{ "question": "柳眉", "answers": [ "りゅうび" ], "comment": "beautiful eyebrows" },
	{ "question": "柵", "answers": [ "さく", "しがらみ" ], "comment": "fence; paling; railing\nweir\nbonds; fetters; ties of obligation\nfortress (surrounded by a wall, moat, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "栄える", "answers": [ "さかえる" ], "comment": "to prosper; to flourish\nto shine; to look attractive; to look pretty" },
	{ "question": "校", "answers": [ "こう" ], "comment": "school\nproof (of a book, document, etc.); counter for proofs" },
	{ "question": "株式", "answers": [ "かぶしき" ], "comment": "stock (company)" },
	{ "question": "核", "answers": [ "かく", "さね" ], "comment": "pit (of a fruit); stone\ncore\nnucleus; nuclear\nnuclear weaponry\npit (of a fruit); stone\ncore\ntongue (piece of wood used to connect two boards)\nclitoris" },
	{ "question": "根回し", "answers": [ "ねまわし" ], "comment": "making necessary arrangements; laying the groundwork\ndigging around the roots of a tree (before transplanting)" },
	{ "question": "根底", "answers": [ "こんてい" ], "comment": "root; basis; foundation" },
	{ "question": "根拠", "answers": [ "こんきょ" ], "comment": "basis; foundation" },
	{ "question": "根本", "answers": [ "こんぽん", "ねもと" ], "comment": "root; source; origin; foundation; base; principle\nkabuki script\nillustrated kabuki script" },
	{ "question": "根気", "answers": [ "こんき" ], "comment": "patience; perseverance; persistence; tenacity; energy" },
	{ "question": "格", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "status; position; rank\nmethod; way; style\nrule; regulation; law\ngrammatical case\nfigure (syllogism)\namendment (of the ritsuryo)" },
	{ "question": "格差", "answers": [ "かくさ" ], "comment": "qualitative difference; disparity" },
	{ "question": "栽培", "answers": [ "さいばい" ], "comment": "cultivation" },
	{ "question": "案じる", "answers": [ "あんじる" ], "comment": "to be anxious or concerned about; to ponder (anxiously); to fear\nto investigate; to consider; to plan" },
	{ "question": "案の定", "answers": [ "あんのじょう" ], "comment": "just as one thought; as usual; sure enough" },
	{ "question": "桟橋", "answers": [ "さんばし", "さんきょう" ], "comment": "wharf; bridge; jetty; pier" },
	{ "question": "梅干", "answers": [ "うめぼし" ], "comment": "umeboshi; pickled ume; pickled plum" },
	{ "question": "棄権", "answers": [ "きけん" ], "comment": "abstention (from voting); renunciation (of a right); withdrawal (from a contest)" },
	{ "question": "棟", "answers": [ "とう", "むね" ], "comment": "large building; building with a long roof\ncounter for buildings, apartments, etc.\nridge (of roof)\nback of a sword\ncounter for buildings, apartments, etc." },
	{ "question": "植わる", "answers": [ "うわる" ], "comment": "to be planted" },
	{ "question": "植民地", "answers": [ "しょくみんち" ], "comment": "colony\ncolonial" },
	{ "question": "検事", "answers": [ "けんじ" ], "comment": "public prosecutor" },
	{ "question": "業", "answers": [ "ごう", "ぎょう", "わざ" ], "comment": "karma (i.e. actions committed in a former life)\ndeed; act; work; performance\nwork; business; company; agency\nstudy" },
	{ "question": "業務", "answers": [ "ぎょうむ" ], "comment": "business; affairs; duties; work; procedure; task; action; function; (business) operations; operational" },
	{ "question": "業績", "answers": [ "ぎょうせき" ], "comment": "achievement; performance; results; work; contribution" },
	{ "question": "業者", "answers": [ "ぎょうしゃ" ], "comment": "trader; merchant; vendor; supplier\nmanufacturer; contractor" },
	{ "question": "業腹", "answers": [ "ごうはら" ], "comment": "spite; resentment" },
	{ "question": "極めて", "answers": [ "きわめて" ], "comment": "exceedingly; extremely; decisively" },
	{ "question": "極楽", "answers": [ "ごくらく" ], "comment": "Sukhavati (Amitabha's Pure Land)\nparadise" },
	{ "question": "極端", "answers": [ "きょくたん" ], "comment": "extreme; extremity" },
	{ "question": "楽しむ", "answers": [ "たのしむ" ], "comment": "to enjoy (oneself)" },
	{ "question": "楽観", "answers": [ "らっかん" ], "comment": "optimism" },
	{ "question": "楽譜", "answers": [ "がくふ" ], "comment": "score; sheet music" },
	{ "question": "概念", "answers": [ "がいねん" ], "comment": "general idea; concept; notion" },
	{ "question": "概略", "answers": [ "がいりゃく" ], "comment": "outline; summary; gist; in brief" },
	{ "question": "概説", "answers": [ "がいせつ" ], "comment": "general statement; outline" },
	{ "question": "構え", "answers": [ "かまえ" ], "comment": "structure; construction; appearance\nposture (e.g. in martial arts); pose; stance\nreadiness; determination; preparedness\nkanji enclosure type radical (must enclose at least two sides of the kanji)" },
	{ "question": "構える", "answers": [ "かまえる" ], "comment": "to set up (a house, store, etc.); to build; to establish; to run; to maintain\nto have at the ready (e.g. a gun); to hold in preparation (e.g. a camera); to prepare in advance (e.g. a meal)\nto adopt a posture; to assume a stance; to stand ready; to be poised for\nto put on an air; to assume an attitude\nto stiffen; to tense up; to become formal\nto fabricate in order to deceive; to make up; to feign\nto plan; to scheme" },
	{ "question": "構想", "answers": [ "こうそう" ], "comment": "plan; plot; idea; conception" },
	{ "question": "様", "answers": [ "さま", "よう" ], "comment": "mess; sorry state; plight; sad sight\n-ways; -wards\nin the act of ...; just as one is ...\nmanner of ...; way of ...\nMr.; Mrs.; Miss; Ms.\nmakes words more polite (usu. in fixed expressions)\nstate; situation; appearance\nappearing ...; looking ...\nway to ...; method of ...ing\nform; style; design\nlike; similar to\nthing (thought or spoken)\nMr.; Mrs.; Ms.\nprecedent; example" },
	{ "question": "様式", "answers": [ "ようしき" ], "comment": "style; form; pattern" },
	{ "question": "様相", "answers": [ "ようそう" ], "comment": "aspect; phase; condition\nmodality (philosophy)" },
	{ "question": "標語", "answers": [ "ひょうご" ], "comment": "motto; slogan; catchword" },
	{ "question": "模倣", "answers": [ "もほう" ], "comment": "imitation; copying" },
	{ "question": "模型", "answers": [ "もけい" ], "comment": "model; dummy; maquette" },
	{ "question": "模範", "answers": [ "もはん" ], "comment": "exemplar; exemplification; exemplum; model; example" },
	{ "question": "模索", "answers": [ "もさく" ], "comment": "groping (for); exploring for a solution" },
	{ "question": "権", "answers": [ "けん" ], "comment": "right (to do something)\nauthority; power" },
	{ "question": "権力", "answers": [ "けんりょく" ], "comment": "(political) power; authority; influence" },
	{ "question": "権威", "answers": [ "けんい" ], "comment": "authority; power; influence" },
	{ "question": "権限", "answers": [ "けんげん" ], "comment": "power; authority; jurisdiction" },
	{ "question": "横綱", "answers": [ "よこづな" ], "comment": "yokozuna (highest rank in sumo); grand champion\nbest in its field; crème de la crème; cream of the crop" },
	{ "question": "樹木", "answers": [ "じゅもく" ], "comment": "tree; trees and shrubs" },
	{ "question": "樹立", "answers": [ "じゅりつ" ], "comment": "establish; create" },
	{ "question": "橋渡し", "answers": [ "はしわたし" ], "comment": "bridge building; mediation; go-between; intermediary; (through the) good offices (of someone)" },
	{ "question": "機", "answers": [ "キ", "はた" ], "comment": "loom\nchance; opportunity\nmachine\naircraft\ncounter for aircraft\ncounter for remaining lives (in video games)" },
	{ "question": "機構", "answers": [ "きこう" ], "comment": "mechanism; organization; organisation" },
	{ "question": "欠く", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "to chip; to nick; to break; to crack\nto lack" },
	{ "question": "欠乏", "answers": [ "けつぼう" ], "comment": "want; shortage; famine" },
	{ "question": "次", "answers": [ "つぎ" ], "comment": "next; following; subsequent\nstage; station\nnext\nhypo- (i.e. containing an element with low valence)\norder; sequence; time; times" },
	{ "question": "次いで", "answers": [ "ついで" ], "comment": "next; secondly; subsequently" },
	{ "question": "欲望", "answers": [ "よくぼう" ], "comment": "desire; appetite; lust" },
	{ "question": "欲深い", "answers": [ "よくぶかい" ], "comment": "greedy" },
	{ "question": "欺く", "answers": [ "あざむく" ], "comment": "to deceive; to delude; to trick; to fool\nto be as ... as ... (e.g. \"as bright as day\", \"as beautiful as a rose\")" },
	{ "question": "歓声", "answers": [ "かんせい" ], "comment": "cheer; shout of joy" },
	{ "question": "止まる", "answers": [ "とまる", "とどまる" ], "comment": "to stop (moving); to come to a stop\nto stop (doing, working, being supplied); to come to a halt; to cease; to be stopped; to be suspended\nto alight; to perch on\nto remain; to abide; to stay (in the one place)\nto be limited to; to be confined to\nto cease; to stop; to be over" },
	{ "question": "止むを得ない", "answers": [ "やむをえない" ], "comment": "cannot be helped; unavoidable" },
	{ "question": "止める", "answers": [ "とめる", "やめる", "とどめる" ], "comment": "to stop; to turn off\nto park\nto prevent; to suppress (a cough); to hold back (tears); to hold (one's breath); to relieve (pain)\nto stop (someone from doing something); to dissuade; to forbid; to prohibit\nto notice; to be aware of; to concentrate on; to pay attention to; to remember; to bear in mind\nto fix (in place); to fasten; to tack; to pin; to nail; to button; to staple\nto detain; to keep in custody\nto stop (an activity); to cease; to discontinue; to end; to quit\nto cancel; to abandon; to give up; to abolish; to abstain; to refrain\nto stop; to stay (e.g. the night); to cease; to put an end to\nto contain; to keep (in position, in place); to limit\nto record (e.g. a fact); to retain" },
	{ "question": "正しく", "answers": [ "まさしく", "ただしく" ], "comment": "surely; no doubt; evidently\nright; rightly; properly; correctly" },
	{ "question": "正に", "answers": [ "まさに" ], "comment": "exactly; surely; certainly\nright then; just then; at that moment\njust (about to); on the verge (of doing or happening)\nduly; naturally" },
	{ "question": "正常", "answers": [ "せいじょう" ], "comment": "normalcy; normality; normal" },
	{ "question": "正弦", "answers": [ "せいげん" ], "comment": "sine" },
	{ "question": "正当", "answers": [ "せいとう" ], "comment": "just; justifiable; right; due; proper; equitable; reasonable; legitimate; legal; lawful" },
	{ "question": "正義", "answers": [ "せいぎ" ], "comment": "justice; right; righteousness; correct meaning" },
	{ "question": "正規", "answers": [ "せいき" ], "comment": "regular; normal; formal; legal; established; legitimate" },
	{ "question": "正解", "answers": [ "せいかい" ], "comment": "correct; right; correct interpretation (answer, solution)" },
	{ "question": "武力", "answers": [ "ぶりょく" ], "comment": "armed might; military power; the sword; force" },
	{ "question": "武装", "answers": [ "ぶそう" ], "comment": "arms; armament" },
	{ "question": "歩", "answers": [ "ほ", "ふ", "ぶ" ], "comment": "pawn\nstep; stride\ncounter for steps\nwalking\nprogress; advance\nunit of land measurement; 3.95 square yards; 3.31 square metres (meters)\nfoot soldier (Edo period); samurai on foot\ngoing on foot; walking" },
	{ "question": "歩む", "answers": [ "あゆむ" ], "comment": "to walk; to go on foot" },
	{ "question": "歯磨き", "answers": [ "はみがき" ], "comment": "dental brushing; brushing one's teeth\ndentifrice; toothpaste; tooth powder" },
	{ "question": "歯科", "answers": [ "しか" ], "comment": "dentistry" },
	{ "question": "歳", "answers": [ "さい", "とし" ], "comment": "-years-old\nyear\nage; years\npast one's prime; old age\ncounter for years (following a number in the hito-futa-mi counting system)" },
	{ "question": "死", "answers": [ "し" ], "comment": "death; decease\ndeath penalty (by strangulation or decapitation)\n(an) out" },
	{ "question": "死刑", "answers": [ "しけい" ], "comment": "death penalty; capital punishment" },
	{ "question": "殊に", "answers": [ "ことに" ], "comment": "especially; particularly; unusually; above all\nadditionally" },
	{ "question": "残酷", "answers": [ "ざんこく" ], "comment": "cruelty; harshness" },
	{ "question": "残金", "answers": [ "ざんきん" ], "comment": "remaining money" },
	{ "question": "残高", "answers": [ "ざんだか" ], "comment": "(bank) balance; remainder" },
	{ "question": "殴る", "answers": [ "なぐる" ], "comment": "to strike; to hit; to beat; to punch" },
	{ "question": "段々", "answers": [ "だんだん" ], "comment": "gradually; by degrees; little by little; more and more; increasingly\nsteps; stairs; staircase; terrace" },
	{ "question": "殺人", "answers": [ "さつじん" ], "comment": "murder" },
	{ "question": "殺生", "answers": [ "せっしょう" ], "comment": "killing; destruction of life\nbarbarous; callous; brutal; cruel" },
	{ "question": "殿", "answers": [ "しんがり", "との" ], "comment": "rear; rear unit guard\nanchor (man)\nfeudal lord\nmansion; palace\nform of address used for official letters and business letters, and in letters to inferiors; Mr." },
	{ "question": "殿様", "answers": [ "とのさま" ], "comment": "feudal lord; daimyo" },
	{ "question": "母校", "answers": [ "ぼこう" ], "comment": "alma mater" },
	{ "question": "毎", "answers": [ "ごと", "まい" ], "comment": "each; every\nevery (usu. with events, e.g. every weekend); each" },
	{ "question": "比例", "answers": [ "ひれい" ], "comment": "proportion" },
	{ "question": "比率", "answers": [ "ひりつ" ], "comment": "ratio; proportion; percentage" },
	{ "question": "比重", "answers": [ "ひじゅう" ], "comment": "specific gravity; weight; part\nrelative weight; relative importance" },
	{ "question": "氏", "answers": [ "し", "うじ" ], "comment": "family name; lineage; birth\nclan\nMr; Mrs; Ms; Miss\nclan\nhe; him\ncounter for people" },
	{ "question": "民主", "answers": [ "みんしゅ" ], "comment": "democracy; popular sovereignty\ndemocratic" },
	{ "question": "民俗", "answers": [ "みんぞく" ], "comment": "folk customs; folkways; ethnic customs" },
	{ "question": "民宿", "answers": [ "みんしゅく" ], "comment": "pension; guesthouse; bed and breakfast; private home providing lodging for travelers (travellers)" },
	{ "question": "民族", "answers": [ "みんぞく" ], "comment": "people; race; nation; ethnic group; ethnos" },
	{ "question": "気兼ね", "answers": [ "きがね" ], "comment": "constraint; reserve; feeling hesitant; being afraid of troubling someone" },
	{ "question": "気品", "answers": [ "きひん" ], "comment": "elegance; refinement; grace; dignity\naroma" },
	{ "question": "気楽", "answers": [ "きらく" ], "comment": "carefree; comfortable; at ease\neasygoing; happy-go-lucky" },
	{ "question": "気泡", "answers": [ "きほう" ], "comment": "(air) bubble (esp. in a liquid)" },
	{ "question": "気流", "answers": [ "きりゅう" ], "comment": "atmospheric current; air current; airflow" },
	{ "question": "気立て", "answers": [ "きだて" ], "comment": "disposition; nature" },
	{ "question": "気象", "answers": [ "きしょう" ], "comment": "weather; climate\ndisposition; temperament" },
	{ "question": "気質", "answers": [ "きしつ", "かたぎ" ], "comment": "spirit; character; trait; temperament; turn of mind; disposition" },
	{ "question": "気軽", "answers": [ "きがる" ], "comment": "carefree; buoyant; lighthearted; sprightly\nease" },
	{ "question": "気配", "answers": [ "けはい", "きはい" ], "comment": "indication; sign; hint; presence; trend\nquotation (esp. stock market)" },
	{ "question": "気風", "answers": [ "きふう" ], "comment": "character; traits; ethos\ncharacter; disposition; spirit; temperament" },
	{ "question": "水気", "answers": [ "みずけ", "すいき" ], "comment": "moisture; dampness; vapor; vapour\ndropsy; edema; oedema" },
	{ "question": "水洗", "answers": [ "すいせん" ], "comment": "rinsing with water; flushing" },
	{ "question": "水源", "answers": [ "すいげん" ], "comment": "source of river; fountainhead" },
	{ "question": "水田", "answers": [ "すいでん" ], "comment": "(water-filled) paddy field" },
	{ "question": "氾濫", "answers": [ "はんらん" ], "comment": "overflowing; flood; inundation; deluge\noversupply; plethora" },
	{ "question": "汚す", "answers": [ "よごす", "けがす" ], "comment": "to pollute; to contaminate; to soil; to make dirty; to stain\nto disgrace; to dishonour; to dishonor; to defile" },
	{ "question": "汚らわしい", "answers": [ "けがらわしい" ], "comment": "filthy; unfair; dirty; untouchable; disgusting; nasty; foul; odious; repulsive" },
	{ "question": "汚れ", "answers": [ "よごれ", "けがれ" ], "comment": "disgrace; shame; stain; blot; corruption; depravity\nuncleanness; impurity; defilement\ndirt; filth; stain; blot; spot" },
	{ "question": "汚れる", "answers": [ "よごれる", "けがれる" ], "comment": "to be violated; to be corrupted; to be polluted; to be stained\nto get dirty; to become dirty\nto become sullied; to become corrupted; to lose one's chastity" },
	{ "question": "決まり悪い", "answers": [ "きまりわるい" ], "comment": "feeling awkward; being ashamed; being bashful" },
	{ "question": "決まる", "answers": [ "きまる" ], "comment": "to be decided; to be settled\nto look good in (clothes)" },
	{ "question": "決勝", "answers": [ "けっしょう" ], "comment": "decision of a contest; finals (in sports)" },
	{ "question": "決意", "answers": [ "けつい" ], "comment": "decision; determination; resolution" },
	{ "question": "決断", "answers": [ "けつだん" ], "comment": "decision; determination" },
	{ "question": "決算", "answers": [ "けっさん" ], "comment": "settlement of accounts; closing accounts; financial results; reporting (of accounts)" },
	{ "question": "決行", "answers": [ "けっこう" ], "comment": "doing (with resolve); carrying out (e.g. a plan)" },
	{ "question": "決議", "answers": [ "けつぎ" ], "comment": "resolution; vote; decision" },
	{ "question": "汽船", "answers": [ "きせん" ], "comment": "steamship; steamboat; steamer" },
	{ "question": "沈める", "answers": [ "しずめる" ], "comment": "to sink; to submerge\nto floor (an opponent)" },
	{ "question": "沈殿", "answers": [ "ちんでん" ], "comment": "precipitation; deposition; settlement (e.g. of sediment)" },
	{ "question": "沈没", "answers": [ "ちんぼつ" ], "comment": "sinking; foundering; going down; submersion\ngetting dead drunk\nhaving too much fun (esp. in a red-light district, etc.) and missing work or neglecting one's duties\nstaying in one place for a long time" },
	{ "question": "沈黙", "answers": [ "ちんもく" ], "comment": "silence; being silent; quiet; hush\nreticence; inaction" },
	{ "question": "没収", "answers": [ "ぼっしゅう" ], "comment": "forfeiture; seizure; confiscation; impounding" },
	{ "question": "没落", "answers": [ "ぼつらく" ], "comment": "ruin; fall; collapse" },
	{ "question": "沢山", "answers": [ "たくさん" ], "comment": "a lot; lots; plenty; many; a large number; much; a great deal; a good deal\nenough; sufficient\nenough; too many; too much\nenough; too many; too much" },
	{ "question": "河川", "answers": [ "かせん" ], "comment": "rivers" },
	{ "question": "沸騰", "answers": [ "ふっとう" ], "comment": "boiling; seething\nbecoming heated (e.g. debate); excitement; agitation; fermentation\nsoaring (prices); shooting up" },
	{ "question": "油井", "answers": [ "ゆせい" ], "comment": "oil well" },
	{ "question": "油絵", "answers": [ "あぶらえ" ], "comment": "oil painting" },
	{ "question": "治まる", "answers": [ "おさまる" ], "comment": "to be at peace; to clamp down; to lessen (storm, terror, anger)" },
	{ "question": "治安", "answers": [ "ちあん" ], "comment": "public order\nJian era (1021.2.2-1024.7.13)" },
	{ "question": "治療", "answers": [ "ちりょう" ], "comment": "medical treatment; cure" },
	{ "question": "沼", "answers": [ "ぬま" ], "comment": "marsh; swamp; wetland; bog; pond" },
	{ "question": "沿う", "answers": [ "そう" ], "comment": "to run along; to run beside\nto follow (a plan, etc.); to act in accordance with" },
	{ "question": "沿岸", "answers": [ "えんがん" ], "comment": "coast; shore; littoral" },
	{ "question": "沿線", "answers": [ "えんせん" ], "comment": "along railway line" },
	{ "question": "泊", "answers": [ "はく" ], "comment": "counter for nights of a stay" },
	{ "question": "法学", "answers": [ "ほうがく" ], "comment": "law; jurisprudence" },
	{ "question": "法廷", "answers": [ "ほうてい" ], "comment": "courtroom" },
	{ "question": "法案", "answers": [ "ほうあん" ], "comment": "bill (law); measure" },
	{ "question": "泡", "answers": [ "あわ", "あぶく" ], "comment": "bubble; foam; froth; head on beer" },
	{ "question": "洋風", "answers": [ "ようふう" ], "comment": "Western style" },
	{ "question": "津波", "answers": [ "つなみ" ], "comment": "tsunami; tidal wave" },
	{ "question": "洪水", "answers": [ "こうずい" ], "comment": "flood" },
	{ "question": "活かす", "answers": [ "いかす" ], "comment": "to make (the best) use of; to leverage (skills, attributes, experience, etc.); to capitalise on (experience, etc)\nto let live; to keep alive\nto revive; to resuscitate" },
	{ "question": "活発", "answers": [ "かっぱつ" ], "comment": "lively; active; vigorous; animated; brisk" },
	{ "question": "派", "answers": [ "は" ], "comment": "clique; faction; school" },
	{ "question": "派遣", "answers": [ "はけん" ], "comment": "dispatch; despatch; deployment\ntemporary employee (esp. from an agency); temporary worker; agency temp" },
	{ "question": "流", "answers": [ "りゅう" ], "comment": "fashion; way; style; manner\nschool (of thought)\nclass; rank; rate\ncurrent (electrical, water, etc.); flow; stream\nexile" },
	{ "question": "流し", "answers": [ "ながし" ], "comment": "sink (e.g. kitchen)\ncruising (e.g. taxi); strolling (entertainer, musician, etc.)\nwashing area in a Japanese-style bath\nback-washing service (in a public bath)\nfloating (something on water); setting adrift; washing away" },
	{ "question": "流行", "answers": [ "はやり", "りゅうこう" ], "comment": "fashion; fad; vogue; craze\nprevalence (e.g. of a disease)" },
	{ "question": "流通", "answers": [ "りゅうつう" ], "comment": "circulation (e.g.money, goods); flow (water, air); distribution\nnegotiable (e.g. shares); distributional; circulating" },
	{ "question": "浅ましい", "answers": [ "あさましい" ], "comment": "wretched; miserable; shameful; mean; despicable; abject" },
	{ "question": "浅瀬", "answers": [ "あさせ" ], "comment": "shoal; shallows; sand bar; ford" },
	{ "question": "浜", "answers": [ "はま" ], "comment": "beach; seashore\ncaptured pieces (in the game of go); captured stones\nYokohama\nriverbank; riverside" },
	{ "question": "浜辺", "answers": [ "はまべ" ], "comment": "beach; foreshore" },
	{ "question": "浪費", "answers": [ "ろうひ" ], "comment": "waste; extravagance" },
	{ "question": "浮かぶ", "answers": [ "うかぶ" ], "comment": "to float; to be suspended\nto rise to surface\nto come to mind; to have inspiration" },
	{ "question": "浮力", "answers": [ "ふりょく" ], "comment": "buoyancy; floating power" },
	{ "question": "浮気", "answers": [ "うわき" ], "comment": "extramarital sex; affair; fooling around\ninfidelity; wantonness; unfaithfulness; inconstancy; fickleness; caprice" },
	{ "question": "浴室", "answers": [ "よくしつ" ], "comment": "bathroom" },
	{ "question": "海峡", "answers": [ "かいきょう" ], "comment": "channel (e.g. between two land masses); strait" },
	{ "question": "海抜", "answers": [ "かいばつ" ], "comment": "height above sea level" },
	{ "question": "海流", "answers": [ "かいりゅう" ], "comment": "ocean current" },
	{ "question": "海路", "answers": [ "かいろ", "うみじ" ], "comment": "sea route" },
	{ "question": "海運", "answers": [ "かいうん" ], "comment": "maritime; marine transportation" },
	{ "question": "浸す", "answers": [ "ひたす" ], "comment": "to soak; to dip; to steep; to immerse\nto moisten; to wet" },
	{ "question": "消去", "answers": [ "しょうきょ" ], "comment": "elimination; erasure; dying out; clearing; purge; melting away" },
	{ "question": "消息", "answers": [ "しょうそく" ], "comment": "news (from somebody); letter; contact\n(somebody's) whereabouts; (somebody's) movements" },
	{ "question": "消耗", "answers": [ "しょうもう", "しょうこう" ], "comment": "exhaustion; consumption; waste; dissipation" },
	{ "question": "液", "answers": [ "えき" ], "comment": "liquid; fluid\njuice; sap\nsoup; broth\n(dipping) sauce" },
	{ "question": "深める", "answers": [ "ふかめる" ], "comment": "to deepen; to heighten; to intensify" },
	{ "question": "混む", "answers": [ "こむ" ], "comment": "to be crowded; to be packed\nto be complex" },
	{ "question": "混同", "answers": [ "こんどう" ], "comment": "confusion; mixing; merger" },
	{ "question": "混血", "answers": [ "こんけつ" ], "comment": "mixed race; mixed parentage" },
	{ "question": "添う", "answers": [ "そう" ], "comment": "to meet (one's expectations, etc.); to satisfy; to comply with\nto accompany; to stay by one's side\nto marry; to wed\nto be added" },
	{ "question": "添える", "answers": [ "そえる" ], "comment": "to garnish; to accompany (as a card does a gift)\nto add to as support; to prop up\nto accompany (as an aid, guide, translator, etc.)\nto mimic; to imitate\nto draw something near to oneself; to approach nearby" },
	{ "question": "清らか", "answers": [ "きよらか" ], "comment": "clean; pure; chaste" },
	{ "question": "清濁", "answers": [ "せいだく" ], "comment": "good and evil; purity and impurity\nvoiced and unvoiced consonants" },
	{ "question": "清算", "answers": [ "せいさん" ], "comment": "settlement (financial); squaring accounts; clearing debts\nliquidation\nending (a relationship); breaking up (with); burying (the past); redeeming (one's faults)" },
	{ "question": "清純", "answers": [ "せいじゅん" ], "comment": "purity; innocence" },
	{ "question": "済ます", "answers": [ "すます" ], "comment": "to finish; to get it over with; to conclude\nto settle; to pay back\nto get along (without something); to make do with (without)" },
	{ "question": "済まない", "answers": [ "すまない" ], "comment": "inexcusable; unjustifiable; unpardonable\nsorry; remorseful; apologetic; conscience-stricken; contrite\nexcuse me; (I'm) sorry; thank you" },
	{ "question": "済みません", "answers": [ "すみません" ], "comment": "excuse me; pardon me; I'm sorry\nthank you" },
	{ "question": "渋い", "answers": [ "しぶい" ], "comment": "astringent; bitter; puckery; rough; harsh; tart\naustere; elegant (and unobtrusive); refined; quiet (and simple); sober; sombre; subdued; tasteful (in a quiet way); understated\nsour (look); glum; grim; sullen; sulky\nstingy; tight-fisted" },
	{ "question": "減少", "answers": [ "げんしょう" ], "comment": "decrease; reduction; decline" },
	{ "question": "減点", "answers": [ "げんてん" ], "comment": "subtract; give a demerit" },
	{ "question": "渡り鳥", "answers": [ "わたりどり" ], "comment": "migratory bird; bird of passage" },
	{ "question": "渦", "answers": [ "うず" ], "comment": "whirlpool; swirl; eddy; vortex; maelstrom" },
	{ "question": "温厚", "answers": [ "おんこう" ], "comment": "gentle" },
	{ "question": "温和", "answers": [ "おんわ" ], "comment": "gentle; mild; moderate" },
	{ "question": "湿気る", "answers": [ "しっける", "しける" ], "comment": "to be damp; to be moist" },
	{ "question": "満たす", "answers": [ "みたす" ], "comment": "to satisfy; to fulfill; to appease\nto fill (e.g. a cup); to pack\nto reach (a certain number)" },
	{ "question": "満場", "answers": [ "まんじょう" ], "comment": "whole house; whole audience" },
	{ "question": "満月", "answers": [ "まんげつ" ], "comment": "full moon" },
	{ "question": "源", "answers": [ "みなもと" ], "comment": "source (of a river); fountainhead\nsource; origin; root\nsource; origin" },
	{ "question": "準じる", "answers": [ "じゅんじる" ], "comment": "to follow; to conform; to apply to" },
	{ "question": "準ずる", "answers": [ "じゅんずる" ], "comment": "to apply correspondingly; to correspond to; to be proportionate to; to conform to" },
	{ "question": "準急", "answers": [ "じゅんきゅう" ], "comment": "semi-express train; local express train; sub-express train; slower than an express (more stops)" },
	{ "question": "溝", "answers": [ "どぶ", "みぞ", "こう" ], "comment": "10^32; hundred nonillion\nditch; drain; gutter; trench\ngroove; tread\ngap (between people, countries, etc.); gulf" },
	{ "question": "溶液", "answers": [ "ようえき" ], "comment": "solution (liquid)" },
	{ "question": "溺れる", "answers": [ "おぼれる" ], "comment": "to drown; to nearly drown; to sink below the surface (of water)\nto indulge in; to lose one's head over something; to wallow in" },
	{ "question": "溺死", "answers": [ "できし" ], "comment": "death by drowning" },
	{ "question": "滅びる", "answers": [ "ほろびる" ], "comment": "to be ruined; to go under; to perish; to be destroyed" },
	{ "question": "滅ぼす", "answers": [ "ほろぼす" ], "comment": "to destroy; to overthrow; to wreck; to ruin" },
	{ "question": "滅亡", "answers": [ "めつぼう" ], "comment": "downfall; ruin; collapse; destruction" },
	{ "question": "滅茶苦茶", "answers": [ "めちゃくちゃ" ], "comment": "absurd; unreasonable; nonsensical; preposterous; incoherent\nextreme; senseless; reckless; wanton\ndisorder; confusion; mess; wreck" },
	{ "question": "滑らか", "answers": [ "なめらか" ], "comment": "smooth (of a surface); glassy; velvety; soft\nsmooth (of an action, proceedings, etc.); fluent (speech); fluid; trouble-free" },
	{ "question": "滑稽", "answers": [ "こっけい" ], "comment": "funny; humorous; humourous; comical; laughable; ridiculous; joking" },
	{ "question": "滞る", "answers": [ "とどこおる" ], "comment": "to stagnate; to be delayed; to be left undone\nto be overdue (of a payment); to fall into arrears; to be outstanding" },
	{ "question": "滞納", "answers": [ "たいのう" ], "comment": "falling behind (with a payment); being in arrears; non-payment; default; delinquency" },
	{ "question": "滲む", "answers": [ "にじむ" ], "comment": "to run (of liquid); to spread\nto blur; to blot; to be blurred\nto ooze; to well up (of tears, etc.)\nto show through (of feelings, emotions, etc.); to reveal itself" },
	{ "question": "滴", "answers": [ "しずく" ], "comment": "drop (of water); drip\ndripping; drop\ncounter for drops of liquid" },
	{ "question": "漁村", "answers": [ "ぎょそん" ], "comment": "fishing village" },
	{ "question": "漁船", "answers": [ "ぎょせん" ], "comment": "fishing boat" },
	{ "question": "漂う", "answers": [ "ただよう" ], "comment": "to drift; to float\nto waft (e.g. a scent); to hang in the air\nto be in the air (e.g. a feeling or mood)\nto wander; to walk around aimlessly\nto be unsteady; to be unstable\nto falter; to flinch; to wince\nto live in unreliable circumstances" },
	{ "question": "漏らす", "answers": [ "もらす" ], "comment": "to let leak; to reveal\nto wet one's pants\nto give utterance; to vent; to express\nto omit; to leave out" },
	{ "question": "漏る", "answers": [ "もる" ], "comment": "to leak; to run out" },
	{ "question": "漏れる", "answers": [ "もれる" ], "comment": "to leak out; to escape; to come through; to shine through; to filter out\nto find expression; to give vent\nto leak out; to be divulged; to be disclosed\nto be omitted; to be left out; to be excluded; to be not included" },
	{ "question": "演じる", "answers": [ "えんじる" ], "comment": "to perform (a play); to play (a part); to act (a part); to commit (a blunder)" },
	{ "question": "演ずる", "answers": [ "えんずる" ], "comment": "to perform; to play" },
	{ "question": "演出", "answers": [ "えんしゅつ" ], "comment": "production (e.g. play); direction" },
	{ "question": "演習", "answers": [ "えんしゅう" ], "comment": "practice; practising\nexercises; manoeuvres; maneuvers\nseminar (student debates, presentations, etc.); practicum" },
	{ "question": "漠然", "answers": [ "ばくぜん" ], "comment": "obscure; vague; equivocal" },
	{ "question": "漢語", "answers": [ "かんご" ], "comment": "Chinese word; Sino-Japanese word" },
	{ "question": "潜る", "answers": [ "もぐる", "くぐる" ], "comment": "to go under; to pass under; to go through; to pass through\nto dive (into or under the water)\nto evade; to get around; to slip past\nto survive; to surmount\nto dive (into or under water)\nto get under; to get into; to get in; to creep into; to crawl under; to bury oneself; to burrow into; to dig oneself into; to snuggle under\nto hide oneself (esp. from the government); to conceal oneself; to go underground" },
	{ "question": "潜入", "answers": [ "せんにゅう" ], "comment": "infiltration; sneaking in" },
	{ "question": "潜水", "answers": [ "せんすい" ], "comment": "diving; submerging; going underwater" },
	{ "question": "潤う", "answers": [ "うるおう" ], "comment": "to be moist; to be damp; to get wet; to be watered\nto profit by; to receive benefits; to receive favors (favours)\nto become rich; to become at ease financially" },
	{ "question": "潮", "answers": [ "しお", "うしお" ], "comment": "tide; current\nsalt water\nopportunity" },
	{ "question": "澄ます", "answers": [ "すます" ], "comment": "to clear; to make clear\nto be unruffled; to look unconcerned; to feign indifference\nto look demure; to look prim; to put on airs\nto strain (one's ears); to listen carefully" },
	{ "question": "激励", "answers": [ "げきれい" ], "comment": "encouragement" },
	{ "question": "濫用", "answers": [ "らんよう" ], "comment": "abuse; misuse; misappropriation; using to excess" },
	{ "question": "火傷", "answers": [ "やけど", "かしょう" ], "comment": "burn; scald" },
	{ "question": "火星", "answers": [ "かせい" ], "comment": "Mars (planet)" },
	{ "question": "火花", "answers": [ "ひばな" ], "comment": "spark" },
	{ "question": "灯", "answers": [ "ともしび", "ひ", "あかし", "あかり" ], "comment": "light; lamp; torch\nlamp; light\nlight (esp. as a religious offering); lamp\nlight; lamp\ncounter for electric lights\nlight; lamp\nbaiting deer with a lighted torch\nlight; lamp" },
	{ "question": "灰", "answers": [ "はい" ], "comment": "ash; ashes" },
	{ "question": "灰皿", "answers": [ "はいざら" ], "comment": "ashtray" },
	{ "question": "災害", "answers": [ "さいがい" ], "comment": "calamity; disaster; misfortune" },
	{ "question": "炭素", "answers": [ "たんそ" ], "comment": "carbon (C)" },
	{ "question": "点検", "answers": [ "てんけん" ], "comment": "inspection; examination; checking" },
	{ "question": "点火", "answers": [ "てんか" ], "comment": "ignition; lighting; set fire to\nlight; lamp" },
	{ "question": "点線", "answers": [ "てんせん" ], "comment": "dotted line; perforated line" },
	{ "question": "為さる", "answers": [ "なさる" ], "comment": "to do" },
	{ "question": "仕来り", "answers": [ "しきたり" ], "comment": "custom; convention; tradition; mores; conventional practice" },
	{ "question": "無下に", "answers": [ "むげに" ], "comment": "bluntly (refusing, etc.); flatly; out of hand; completely" },
	{ "question": "無効", "answers": [ "むこう" ], "comment": "invalid; no effect; unavailable; illegal" },
	{ "question": "無口", "answers": [ "むくち" ], "comment": "reticence; taciturnity; silent person\nreticent; taciturn; silent\nastomatous" },
	{ "question": "無念", "answers": [ "むねん" ], "comment": "regret; chagrin; mortification\nfreedom from obstructive thoughts" },
	{ "question": "無意味", "answers": [ "むいみ" ], "comment": "nonsense; no meaning; meaningless" },
	{ "question": "無断", "answers": [ "むだん" ], "comment": "without permission; without notice" },
	{ "question": "無用", "answers": [ "むよう" ], "comment": "useless; futile\nunnecessary; needless\nnot on business; unrelated; unauthorised; unauthorized\nprohibited; banned; forbidden" },
	{ "question": "無知", "answers": [ "むち" ], "comment": "ignorance; innocence; stupidity" },
	{ "question": "無礼", "answers": [ "ぶれい" ], "comment": "impolite; rude" },
	{ "question": "無線", "answers": [ "むせん" ], "comment": "wireless; radio" },
	{ "question": "無能", "answers": [ "むのう" ], "comment": "inefficiency; incompetence\nincompetent person" },
	{ "question": "無茶", "answers": [ "むちゃ" ], "comment": "absurd; unreasonable; excessive; rash\nvery; extremely; excessively" },
	{ "question": "無茶苦茶", "answers": [ "むちゃくちゃ" ], "comment": "nonsensical; unreasonable; absurd; unrealistic\nawfully; extremely; to excess; senseless; reckless\ndisorder; confusion; being jumbled; being mixed up\nvery; extremely; excessively" },
	{ "question": "無言", "answers": [ "むごん" ], "comment": "silence" },
	{ "question": "無論", "answers": [ "むろん" ], "comment": "of course; naturally" },
	{ "question": "無邪気", "answers": [ "むじゃき" ], "comment": "innocence; simple-mindedness" },
	{ "question": "無闇に", "answers": [ "むやみに" ], "comment": "thoughtlessly; recklessly; rashly; indiscriminately; indiscreetly; at random\nexcessively; unreasonably; immoderately; absurdly" },
	{ "question": "無難", "answers": [ "ぶなん" ], "comment": "safe; secure\nacceptable; passable; faultless; innocuous" },
	{ "question": "無駄遣い", "answers": [ "むだづかい" ], "comment": "wasting ... on (e.g. money); squandering; waste; frittering away" },
	{ "question": "焦げ茶", "answers": [ "こげちゃ" ], "comment": "dark brown; olive brown" },
	{ "question": "焦る", "answers": [ "あせる" ], "comment": "to be in a hurry; to be impatient; to be flustered; to lose one's presence of mind; to be surprised" },
	{ "question": "煙たい", "answers": [ "けむたい" ], "comment": "smoky\nawkward; ill at ease" },
	{ "question": "煙る", "answers": [ "けむる" ], "comment": "to smoke (e.g. fire)\nto be hazy" },
	{ "question": "煙草", "answers": [ "たばこ" ], "comment": "tobacco; cigarette; cigaret; cigar\ntobacco plant (Nicotiana tabacum)" },
	{ "question": "照り返す", "answers": [ "てりかえす" ], "comment": "to reflect; to throw back light" },
	{ "question": "照合", "answers": [ "しょうごう" ], "comment": "collation; comparison" },
	{ "question": "照明", "answers": [ "しょうめい" ], "comment": "illumination; lighting" },
	{ "question": "煩わしい", "answers": [ "わずらわしい" ], "comment": "troublesome; annoying; complicated" },
	{ "question": "熱意", "answers": [ "ねつい" ], "comment": "zeal; enthusiasm" },
	{ "question": "熱湯", "answers": [ "ねっとう" ], "comment": "boiling water\nwarmer than usual bath" },
	{ "question": "熱量", "answers": [ "ねつりょう" ], "comment": "calorific value; quantity of heat; calorie" },
	{ "question": "燃料", "answers": [ "ねんりょう" ], "comment": "fuel" },
	{ "question": "燃焼", "answers": [ "ねんしょう" ], "comment": "burning; combustion" },
	{ "question": "爆弾", "answers": [ "ばくだん" ], "comment": "bomb\nalcohol with liquor added (esp. wine-based shochu highball, also beer with whiskey)" },
	{ "question": "爆破", "answers": [ "ばくは" ], "comment": "destructive blast; explosion; blow up" },
	{ "question": "父母", "answers": [ "ふぼ", "ちちはは" ], "comment": "father and mother; parents" },
	{ "question": "爽やか", "answers": [ "さわやか" ], "comment": "fresh; refreshing; invigorating\nclear (e.g. voice); fluent; eloquent" },
	{ "question": "片付け", "answers": [ "かたづけ" ], "comment": "tidying up; finishing" },
	{ "question": "片思い", "answers": [ "かたおもい" ], "comment": "unrequited love" },
	{ "question": "片言", "answers": [ "かたこと", "へんげん" ], "comment": "prattle; broken language; halting language; baby talk; imperfect speech; smattering\nbrief remark; few words\none side (e.g. of an argument); ex-parte statement" },
	{ "question": "版", "answers": [ "はん", "ばん" ], "comment": "edition; version; printing; impression; implementation (e.g. software)\nplate; block; cast\neditions of a publication" },
	{ "question": "版画", "answers": [ "はんが" ], "comment": "woodcut; woodblock print; art print" },
	{ "question": "牧師", "answers": [ "ぼくし" ], "comment": "pastor; minister; clergyman; reverend" },
	{ "question": "物体", "answers": [ "ぶったい" ], "comment": "body; object\nsuperior airs; air of importance\noveremphasis" },
	{ "question": "勿体ない", "answers": [ "もったいない" ], "comment": "impious; profane; sacrilegious\ntoo good; more than one deserves; unworthy of\nwasteful" },
	{ "question": "物好き", "answers": [ "ものずき" ], "comment": "(idle) curiosity; fancifulness; whimsy; (having) strange tastes" },
	{ "question": "物置き", "answers": [ "ものおき" ], "comment": "storage room; storeroom; lumber room" },
	{ "question": "物議", "answers": [ "ぶつぎ" ], "comment": "public discussion; public criticism; controversy" },
	{ "question": "物資", "answers": [ "ぶっし" ], "comment": "goods; materials" },
	{ "question": "物足りない", "answers": [ "ものたりない" ], "comment": "unsatisfied; unsatisfactory; insufficient" },
	{ "question": "特技", "answers": [ "とくぎ" ], "comment": "special skill" },
	{ "question": "特有", "answers": [ "とくゆう" ], "comment": "characteristic (of); peculiar (to)" },
	{ "question": "特権", "answers": [ "とっけん" ], "comment": "privilege; special right" },
	{ "question": "特派", "answers": [ "とくは" ], "comment": "send specially; special envoy" },
	{ "question": "特産", "answers": [ "とくさん" ], "comment": "specialty; special product" },
	{ "question": "特許", "answers": [ "とっきょ" ], "comment": "patent; special permission; licence (license); concession; franchise; charter\nproprietary" },
	{ "question": "特集", "answers": [ "とくしゅう" ], "comment": "feature (e.g. newspaper); special edition; report" },
	{ "question": "犠牲", "answers": [ "ぎせい" ], "comment": "victim; sacrifice; scapegoat" },
	{ "question": "犬死に", "answers": [ "いぬじに" ], "comment": "dying in vain; wasteful sacrifice of life" },
	{ "question": "犯す", "answers": [ "おかす" ], "comment": "to commit (e.g. crime); to perpetrate; to make (e.g. mistake)\nto break (e.g. rule); to violate; to transgress; to contravene\nto rape; to violate; to ravish; to deflower" },
	{ "question": "状", "answers": [ "じょう" ], "comment": "shape; state\nletter; correspondence\nMr.; Mrs.; Miss; Ms.\nmakes words more polite (usu. in fixed expressions)\nstate; situation; appearance" },
	{ "question": "狙撃", "answers": [ "そげき" ], "comment": "shooting; sniping" },
	{ "question": "独創", "answers": [ "どくそう" ], "comment": "originality" },
	{ "question": "独占", "answers": [ "どくせん" ], "comment": "monopoly; monopolization\nhogging; keeping to oneself" },
	{ "question": "独自", "answers": [ "どくじ" ], "comment": "original; unique; distinctive; characteristic; peculiar\nindependent; one's own; personal" },
	{ "question": "独裁", "answers": [ "どくさい" ], "comment": "dictatorship; despotism" },
	{ "question": "猛烈", "answers": [ "もうれつ" ], "comment": "violent; vehement; raging; stout; intense; spirited; stormy" },
	{ "question": "獣", "answers": [ "けもの", "けだもの" ], "comment": "beast; brute; animal\nbeast (esp. one used for its meat, such as a boar or a deer)\nhunting (of animals such as boar, deer, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "獲得", "answers": [ "かくとく" ], "comment": "acquisition; possession" },
	{ "question": "獲物", "answers": [ "えもの" ], "comment": "game; spoils; trophy; prey" },
	{ "question": "率いる", "answers": [ "ひきいる" ], "comment": "to lead; to spearhead (a group); to command (troops)" },
	{ "question": "率直", "answers": [ "そっちょく" ], "comment": "frankness; candour; candor; openheartedness; directness" },
	{ "question": "玉", "answers": [ "たま", "ぎょく" ], "comment": "ball; sphere; globe; orb\nbead (of sweat, dew, etc.); drop; droplet\nball (in sports)\npile (of noodles, etc.)\nbullet\nbulb (i.e. a light bulb)\nlens (of glasses, etc.)\nbead (of an abacus)\nball (i.e. a testicle)\ngem; jewel (esp. spherical; sometimes used figuratively); pearl\nfemale entertainer (e.g. a geisha)\nperson (when commenting on their nature); character\nitem, funds or person used as part of a plot\negg\ncoin\nprecious; beautiful; excellent\nprecious stone (esp. jade)\negg (sometimes esp. as a sushi topping)\nstock or security being traded; product being bought or sold\nposition (in finance, the amount of a security either owned or owed by an investor or dealer)\ngeisha\ntime charge for a geisha\nking (of the junior player)" },
	{ "question": "玩具", "answers": [ "がんぐ", "おもちゃ" ], "comment": "toy; plaything" },
	{ "question": "班", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "group; party; team\nsquad; section" },
	{ "question": "現れ", "answers": [ "あらわれ" ], "comment": "embodiment; manifestation; materialization; materialisation; expression; indication" },
	{ "question": "現れる", "answers": [ "あらわれる" ], "comment": "to appear; to come in sight; to become visible; to come out; to embody; to materialize; to materialise\nto be expressed (e.g. emotions); to become apparent (e.g. trends, effects)" },
	{ "question": "現像", "answers": [ "げんぞう" ], "comment": "developing (film)" },
	{ "question": "現地", "answers": [ "げんち" ], "comment": "actual place; local; on-site" },
	{ "question": "現場", "answers": [ "げんば", "げんじょう" ], "comment": "actual spot; scene; scene of the crime; site; location; setting\nshop floor; factory floor; (on) site" },
	{ "question": "現行", "answers": [ "げんこう" ], "comment": "present; current; in operation" },
	{ "question": "球根", "answers": [ "きゅうこん" ], "comment": "(plant) bulb" },
	{ "question": "理屈", "answers": [ "りくつ" ], "comment": "theory; reason" },
	{ "question": "理性", "answers": [ "りせい" ], "comment": "reason; reasoning power; (one's) sense" },
	{ "question": "理論", "answers": [ "りろん" ], "comment": "theory" },
	{ "question": "瓶", "answers": [ "びん", "かめ" ], "comment": "earthenware pot\nbottle; jar; decanter; flagon; phial; vial" },
	{ "question": "甘い", "answers": [ "あまい", "うまい" ], "comment": "sweet-tasting; sweet; sugary; sugared\nfragrant (smelling); sweet (music)\nlightly salted; light in salt; not spicy\nnaive; overly optimistic; soft on; generous; indulgent; easy-going; lenient\nhalf-hearted; not finished properly\ninsufficient; not satisfactory; inadequate; loose\nmild\ntempting; enticing; luring\nskillful; skilful; clever; expert; wise; successful\ndelicious; appetizing; appetising; tasty\nfortunate; splendid; promising" },
	{ "question": "甘える", "answers": [ "あまえる" ], "comment": "to behave like a spoiled child; to fawn on\nto take advantage of; to presume upon (e.g. another's benevolence); to depend on" },
	{ "question": "甘口", "answers": [ "あまくち" ], "comment": "sweet flavour; sweet flavor; mildness\nflattery\nstupidity" },
	{ "question": "甚だ", "answers": [ "はなはだ" ], "comment": "very; greatly; exceedingly" },
	{ "question": "生", "answers": [ "なま", "せい", "しょう", "き" ], "comment": "pure; undiluted; raw; crude\nraw; uncooked; fresh\nnatural; as it is; unedited; unprocessed\nunprotected (i.e. not wearing a condom)\nlive (i.e. not recorded)\ninexperienced; unpolished; green; crude\nimpudence; sauciness\nunpasteurized beer; draft beer; draught beer\njust a little; somehow; vaguely; partially; somewhat; half-; semi-\nirresponsibly; half-baked\ncash\ntipsiness\ninnocent; naive; unsophisticated; inexperienced; green; wet behind the ears\nbirth-\nlife; living\nI; me; myself\nvital; virile; lively\narea of thick growth (of trees, grass, etc.)\nboiled and half-dried bonito" },
	{ "question": "生かす", "answers": [ "いかす" ], "comment": "to make (the best) use of; to leverage (skills, attributes, experience, etc.); to capitalise on (experience, etc)\nto let live; to keep alive\nto revive; to resuscitate" },
	{ "question": "生まれつき", "answers": [ "うまれつき" ], "comment": "by nature; by birth; naturally; natural; innate" },
	{ "question": "生やす", "answers": [ "はやす" ], "comment": "to grow; to cultivate; to wear a beard" },
	{ "question": "生死", "answers": [ "せいし" ], "comment": "life and death\nsamsara (cycle of death and rebirth)\ndeath" },
	{ "question": "生理", "answers": [ "せいり" ], "comment": "physiology\nmenstruation; one's period; menses" },
	{ "question": "生真面目", "answers": [ "きまじめ" ], "comment": "too serious; person who is too serious; honesty; sincerity" },
	{ "question": "生育", "answers": [ "せいいく" ], "comment": "birth and growth; giving birth and raising; development; breeding" },
	{ "question": "生臭い", "answers": [ "なまぐさい" ], "comment": "smelling of fish; fishy; smelling of blood; bloody\ndegenerate (of a monk); depraved; corrupt; fallen\nworldly; mundane; secular; common; ordinary\nfishy; suspicious; questionable" },
	{ "question": "生計", "answers": [ "せいけい" ], "comment": "livelihood; living" },
	{ "question": "生身", "answers": [ "なまみ" ], "comment": "living flesh; flesh and blood\nphysical body of Buddha or a bodhisattva" },
	{ "question": "産む", "answers": [ "うむ" ], "comment": "to give birth; to bear (child); to lay (eggs)\nto produce; to yield; to give rise to; to deliver" },
	{ "question": "産休", "answers": [ "さんきゅう" ], "comment": "maternity leave" },
	{ "question": "産出", "answers": [ "さんしゅつ" ], "comment": "yield; produce" },
	{ "question": "産婦人科", "answers": [ "さんふじんか" ], "comment": "maternity and gynaecology department (gynecology); department of obstetrics and gynaecology (gynecology)" },
	{ "question": "産後", "answers": [ "さんご" ], "comment": "postpartum; after childbirth" },
	{ "question": "産物", "answers": [ "さんぶつ" ], "comment": "product; produce\nresult; fruit" },
	{ "question": "用件", "answers": [ "ようけん" ], "comment": "business; thing to be done; something that should be performed; information that should be conveyed" },
	{ "question": "用品", "answers": [ "ようひん" ], "comment": "articles; supplies; parts" },
	{ "question": "用法", "answers": [ "ようほう" ], "comment": "directions; rules of use" },
	{ "question": "用紙", "answers": [ "ようし" ], "comment": "blank form\nsheets of paper; sheet of paper" },
	{ "question": "田園", "answers": [ "でんえん" ], "comment": "the country; countryside; rural districts\ncultivated land; fields" },
	{ "question": "甲", "answers": [ "こう", "きのえ" ], "comment": "armor; armour\nhelmet (of armor, armour); headpiece\ncarapace; shell\n1st in rank; grade A\ninstep; back of hand\nthe A party (e.g. in a contract); the first party; plaintiff (label in legal documents)\ntreble range (in Japanese music); high note\nfirst sign of the Chinese calendar" },
	{ "question": "甲乙", "answers": [ "こうおつ" ], "comment": "A and B; excellent and good; similarity\ndiscrimination; discernment; distinction\nfirst and second parties (in legal contexts)" },
	{ "question": "申し入れる", "answers": [ "もうしいれる" ], "comment": "to propose; to suggest" },
	{ "question": "申し出", "answers": [ "もうしで" ], "comment": "proposal; request; claim; report; notice; offer" },
	{ "question": "申し出る", "answers": [ "もうしでる" ], "comment": "to report to; to tell; to suggest; to submit; to request; to make an offer; to come forward with information" },
	{ "question": "申し分", "answers": [ "もうしぶん" ], "comment": "objection; shortcomings" },
	{ "question": "申し込み", "answers": [ "もうしこみ" ], "comment": "application; entry; request; subscription; offer; proposal; overture; challenge" },
	{ "question": "申告", "answers": [ "しんこく" ], "comment": "report; statement; filing a return; notification" },
	{ "question": "画期", "answers": [ "かっき" ], "comment": "transition from one epoch to another; change of era" },
	{ "question": "留める", "answers": [ "とめる", "とどめる" ], "comment": "to stop; to turn off\nto park\nto prevent; to suppress (a cough); to hold back (tears); to hold (one's breath); to relieve (pain)\nto stop (someone from doing something); to dissuade; to forbid; to prohibit\nto notice; to be aware of; to concentrate on; to pay attention to; to remember; to bear in mind\nto fix (in place); to fasten; to tack; to pin; to nail; to button; to staple\nto detain; to keep in custody\nto stop; to stay (e.g. the night); to cease; to put an end to\nto contain; to keep (in position, in place); to limit\nto record (e.g. a fact); to retain" },
	{ "question": "畜生", "answers": [ "ちくしょう" ], "comment": "beast (i.e. any animal other than man)\nperson reborn into the animal realm\nbrute (i.e. a contemptible human being)\nson of a bitch; for Christ's sake; damn it" },
	{ "question": "畜産", "answers": [ "ちくさん" ], "comment": "animal husbandry" },
	{ "question": "略奪", "answers": [ "りゃくだつ" ], "comment": "pillage; plunder; looting; robbery" },
	{ "question": "略語", "answers": [ "りゃくご" ], "comment": "abbreviation; acronym" },
	{ "question": "異動", "answers": [ "いどう" ], "comment": "change (personnel); transfer; reshuffle" },
	{ "question": "異性", "answers": [ "いせい" ], "comment": "the opposite sex\nisomerism" },
	{ "question": "異見", "answers": [ "いけん" ], "comment": "different opinion; objection" },
	{ "question": "異論", "answers": [ "いろん" ], "comment": "different opinion; objection" },
	{ "question": "異議", "answers": [ "いぎ" ], "comment": "objection; dissent; protest" },
	{ "question": "畳", "answers": [ "たたみ", "じょう" ], "comment": "counter for tatami mats\nmeasure of room size (in mat units)\ntatami mat; Japanese straw floor coverings\nfolding paper-case; kimono wrapping paper" },
	{ "question": "疎か", "answers": [ "おろそか" ], "comment": "negligent; neglectful; careless; remiss\nnot to mention ...; needless to say ...; not to speak of ...; not only ...\nnegligent; neglectful; careless; remiss" },
	{ "question": "疑惑", "answers": [ "ぎわく" ], "comment": "doubt; misgivings; distrust; suspicion" },
	{ "question": "疲労", "answers": [ "ひろう" ], "comment": "fatigue; weariness" },
	{ "question": "疾病", "answers": [ "しっぺい" ], "comment": "illness; disease" },
	{ "question": "病", "answers": [ "やまい" ], "comment": "illness; disease\nbad habit; weakness; fault\npain; trouble\nillness\ndisease; -pathy" },
	{ "question": "病む", "answers": [ "やむ" ], "comment": "to fall ill; to suffer from; to have something wrong with" },
	{ "question": "症", "answers": [ "しょう" ], "comment": "illness" },
	{ "question": "痛む", "answers": [ "いたむ" ], "comment": "to hurt; to ache; to feel a pain\nto be injured; to be spoiled (e.g. food); to be damaged" },
	{ "question": "痛める", "answers": [ "いためる" ], "comment": "to hurt; to injure; to cause pain\nto harm; to damage; to spoil\nto worry; to bother; to be grieved over; to afflict\nto cause financial loss; to hurt one's pocket\nto hurt; to ache" },
	{ "question": "痛切", "answers": [ "つうせつ" ], "comment": "keen; acute" },
	{ "question": "痛感", "answers": [ "つうかん" ], "comment": "feeling keenly; fully realizing" },
	{ "question": "発", "answers": [ "はつ" ], "comment": "departure; departing (from ...); departing (at time ...)\nsending; sent (by ...); sent (at ...)\nengine\ngreen dragon tile\ncounter for gunshots, bursts of gas, etc.; counter for bullets, bombs, etc.; counter for blows (punches)" },
	{ "question": "発作", "answers": [ "ほっさ" ], "comment": "fit; spasm; attack; seizure" },
	{ "question": "発掘", "answers": [ "はっくつ" ], "comment": "excavation; exhumation\ndiscovery (e.g. new talent)" },
	{ "question": "発条", "answers": [ "ばね", "はつじょう", "ぜんまい" ], "comment": "spring (e.g. coil, leaf); mainspring; power spring" },
	{ "question": "発生", "answers": [ "はっせい" ], "comment": "outbreak; spring forth; occurrence; incidence\ngeneration (e.g. of power or heat); genesis; origin\nontogeny; development of complex multicellular structures from cell(s) in a simple state" },
	{ "question": "発病", "answers": [ "はつびょう" ], "comment": "attack (disease)" },
	{ "question": "発育", "answers": [ "はついく" ], "comment": "(physical) growth; development" },
	{ "question": "発芽", "answers": [ "はつが" ], "comment": "germination; sprouting; budding" },
	{ "question": "発言", "answers": [ "はつげん" ], "comment": "statement; remark; observation; utterance; speech; proposal" },
	{ "question": "発足", "answers": [ "ほっそく", "はっそく" ], "comment": "starting; inauguration; launch; founding; establishment; start-up" },
	{ "question": "登校", "answers": [ "とうこう" ], "comment": "attendance (at school); going to school" },
	{ "question": "登録", "answers": [ "とうろく" ], "comment": "registration; accession; register; entry; record" },
	{ "question": "白状", "answers": [ "はくじょう" ], "comment": "confession" },
	{ "question": "百科事典", "answers": [ "ひゃっかじてん" ], "comment": "encyclopedia; encyclopaedia" },
	{ "question": "百科辞典", "answers": [ "ひゃっかじてん" ], "comment": "encyclopedia; encyclopaedia" },
	{ "question": "的", "answers": [ "まと" ], "comment": "-like; typical\nmark; target" },
	{ "question": "皇居", "answers": [ "こうきょ" ], "comment": "Imperial Palace (of Japan); imperial residence" },
	{ "question": "盗み", "answers": [ "ぬすみ" ], "comment": "stealing" },
	{ "question": "盛り上がる", "answers": [ "もりあがる" ], "comment": "to swell; to rise; to bulge; to be piled up\nto rouse; to get excited" },
	{ "question": "盛る", "answers": [ "さかる", "もる" ], "comment": "to prosper; to flourish\nto copulate (animals)\nto serve (food, etc.); to dish out\nto fill up; to pile up; to heap\nto prescribe; to administer; to dose out\nto put into (e.g. information in a report)\nto mark out (e.g. scale); to graduate (e.g. thermometer)\nto exaggerate; to apply heavy makeup" },
	{ "question": "盛大", "answers": [ "せいだい" ], "comment": "grand; magnificent; lavish; large scale; prosperous; thriving; lively\nforceful; powerful; vigorous" },
	{ "question": "盛装", "answers": [ "せいそう" ], "comment": "dressing up in fine clothes; splendid clothes; one's best clothes" },
	{ "question": "監視", "answers": [ "かんし" ], "comment": "monitoring; watching; observation; surveillance; guarding; inspection" },
	{ "question": "目付き", "answers": [ "めつき" ], "comment": "look; expression of the eyes; eyes" },
	{ "question": "目方", "answers": [ "めかた" ], "comment": "weight" },
	{ "question": "目盛", "answers": [ "めもり" ], "comment": "scale; gradations" },
	{ "question": "目蓋", "answers": [ "まぶた" ], "comment": "eyelid; eyelids" },
	{ "question": "目覚しい", "answers": [ "めざましい" ], "comment": "brilliant; splendid; striking; remarkable" },
	{ "question": "目覚める", "answers": [ "めざめる" ], "comment": "to wake up; to awake\nto awaken to (instinct, ability, perception, etc.); to become aware of; to become conscious of; to realize\nto come to one's senses" },
	{ "question": "目論見", "answers": [ "もくろみ" ], "comment": "plan; scheme; project; program; programme; intention; goal" },
	{ "question": "目録", "answers": [ "もくろく" ], "comment": "catalogue; catalog; inventory; index; list\ncertificate indicating an impending gift" },
	{ "question": "盲点", "answers": [ "もうてん" ], "comment": "blind spot" },
	{ "question": "直ぐ", "answers": [ "すぐ" ], "comment": "immediately; at once; directly\nsoon; before long; shortly\neasily; readily; without difficulty\nright (near); nearby; just (handy)\nhonest; upright; frank; straightforward" },
	{ "question": "直感", "answers": [ "ちょっかん" ], "comment": "intuition; instinct; insight; hunch; immediacy" },
	{ "question": "直面", "answers": [ "ちょくめん" ], "comment": "confrontation\nto face; to confront; to encounter\nperforming without a mask (noh)" },
	{ "question": "相", "answers": [ "そう", "しょう", "あい" ], "comment": "one's nature; one's destiny\ncustom; tradition; habit\ntogether; mutually; fellow\nappearance; look; countenance\na 'seeming' that fortune-tellers relate to one's fortune\naspect\nphase (e.g. solid, liquid and gaseous)\nalternately; in succession\nminister of state" },
	{ "question": "相場", "answers": [ "そうば" ], "comment": "market price\nspeculation (e.g. on stocks)\nreputation (according to conventional wisdom); estimation; esteem" },
	{ "question": "相変わらず", "answers": [ "あいかわらず" ], "comment": "as ever; as usual; the same; still" },
	{ "question": "相対", "answers": [ "あいたい", "そうたい" ], "comment": "confrontation; facing; between ourselves; no third party; tete-a-tete\nrelativity\nrelative" },
	{ "question": "相応", "answers": [ "そうおう" ], "comment": "suitability; fitness" },
	{ "question": "相応しい", "answers": [ "ふさわしい" ], "comment": "appropriate; adequate; suitable; fitting; worthy" },
	{ "question": "盾", "answers": [ "たて" ], "comment": "shield; buckler; escutcheon; pretext" },
	{ "question": "省みる", "answers": [ "かえりみる" ], "comment": "to look back (e.g. over shoulder or at the past); to turn around\nto reflect on the past; to reconsider; to review\nto reflect on oneself; to introspect; to contemplate oneself\nto consider (usu. used in negative); to concern oneself about; to pay attention to; to take into consideration" },
	{ "question": "省略", "answers": [ "しょうりゃく" ], "comment": "omission; abbreviation; abridgment; abridgement" },
	{ "question": "眉", "answers": [ "まゆ" ], "comment": "eyebrow; eyebrows" },
	{ "question": "看護", "answers": [ "かんご" ], "comment": "nursing; (army) nurse" },
	{ "question": "真っ二つ", "answers": [ "まっぷたつ" ], "comment": "in two equal parts" },
	{ "question": "真に", "answers": [ "しんに", "まことに" ], "comment": "indeed; really; absolutely; truly; actually; very; quite" },
	{ "question": "真ん中", "answers": [ "まんなか" ], "comment": "middle; centre; center; mid-way" },
	{ "question": "真ん丸い", "answers": [ "まんまるい" ], "comment": "perfectly round; perfectly circular" },
	{ "question": "真ん前", "answers": [ "まんまえ" ], "comment": "right in front; just opposite; under the nose" },
	{ "question": "真上", "answers": [ "まうえ" ], "comment": "just above; right overhead" },
	{ "question": "真下", "answers": [ "ました" ], "comment": "right under; directly below" },
	{ "question": "真実", "answers": [ "しんじつ" ], "comment": "truth; reality" },
	{ "question": "真心", "answers": [ "まごころ" ], "comment": "sincerity; devotion" },
	{ "question": "真珠", "answers": [ "しんじゅ" ], "comment": "pearl" },
	{ "question": "真理", "answers": [ "しんり" ], "comment": "truth" },
	{ "question": "真相", "answers": [ "しんそう" ], "comment": "truth; real situation" },
	{ "question": "眠たい", "answers": [ "ねむたい" ], "comment": "sleepy; drowsy" },
	{ "question": "眼球", "answers": [ "がんきゅう" ], "comment": "eyeball" },
	{ "question": "眼科", "answers": [ "がんか" ], "comment": "ophthalmology" },
	{ "question": "眼鏡", "answers": [ "めがね", "がんきょう" ], "comment": "spectacles; glasses\njudgement; discrimination; discernment; insight" },
	{ "question": "着", "answers": [ "ちゃく" ], "comment": "counter for suits of clothing\narriving at ...\nclothes; outfit; uniform" },
	{ "question": "着工", "answers": [ "ちゃっこう" ], "comment": "start of (construction) work" },
	{ "question": "着席", "answers": [ "ちゃくせき" ], "comment": "sit down; seat" },
	{ "question": "着手", "answers": [ "ちゃくしゅ" ], "comment": "to start work (on); to undertake\nembarkation; launch" },
	{ "question": "着目", "answers": [ "ちゃくもく" ], "comment": "attention; giving one's attention; focusing" },
	{ "question": "着色", "answers": [ "ちゃくしょく" ], "comment": "colouring; coloring; colorant" },
	{ "question": "着陸", "answers": [ "ちゃくりく" ], "comment": "landing; alighting; touch down" },
	{ "question": "着飾る", "answers": [ "きかざる" ], "comment": "to dress up" },
	{ "question": "瞬き", "answers": [ "またたき", "まばたき" ], "comment": "blink (of eyes); wink\ntwinkling (of stars); flicker (of light); blink (of light)" },
	{ "question": "矢", "answers": [ "や" ], "comment": "arrow\nwedge; chock" },
	{ "question": "知り合い", "answers": [ "しりあい" ], "comment": "acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "知性", "answers": [ "ちせい" ], "comment": "intelligence" },
	{ "question": "知恵", "answers": [ "ちえ" ], "comment": "wisdom; wit; sagacity; sense; intelligence\nprajna (insight leading to enlightenment)" },
	{ "question": "知的", "answers": [ "ちてき" ], "comment": "intellectual" },
	{ "question": "短大", "answers": [ "たんだい" ], "comment": "junior college; vocationally oriented two or three year post-secondary education institution" },
	{ "question": "短歌", "answers": [ "たんか" ], "comment": "tanka; 31-mora Japanese poem" },
	{ "question": "短気", "answers": [ "たんき" ], "comment": "quick temper; short temper" },
	{ "question": "短波", "answers": [ "たんぱ" ], "comment": "short wave" },
	{ "question": "短縮", "answers": [ "たんしゅく" ], "comment": "shortening; contraction; reduction; curtailment; abbreviation" },
	{ "question": "砂利", "answers": [ "じゃり" ], "comment": "gravel; ballast; pebbles\nchild; rugrat; ankle-biter" },
	{ "question": "砂糖", "answers": [ "さとう" ], "comment": "sugar" },
	{ "question": "研ぐ", "answers": [ "とぐ" ], "comment": "to sharpen; to hone; to whet; to grind\nto wash (rice)\nto scour; to polish; to burnish" },
	{ "question": "破壊", "answers": [ "はかい" ], "comment": "destruction; disruption\n(application) crash" },
	{ "question": "破廉恥", "answers": [ "はれんち" ], "comment": "shameless; infamous; disgraceful" },
	{ "question": "破損", "answers": [ "はそん" ], "comment": "damage" },
	{ "question": "破棄", "answers": [ "はき" ], "comment": "tearing up and discarding (e.g. documents); disposal (e.g. weaponry); destruction\nannulment; cancellation; abrogation; voiding; breaking (e.g. treaty)\nreversal (of an original ruling)" },
	{ "question": "破裂", "answers": [ "はれつ" ], "comment": "explosion; rupture; break off" },
	{ "question": "碁盤", "answers": [ "ごばん" ], "comment": "Go board" },
	{ "question": "碑石", "answers": [ "ひせき" ], "comment": "stone monument" },
	{ "question": "確保", "answers": [ "かくほ" ], "comment": "guarantee; maintain; ensure; insure; secure; reservation" },
	{ "question": "確信", "answers": [ "かくしん" ], "comment": "conviction; belief; confidence" },
	{ "question": "確定", "answers": [ "かくてい" ], "comment": "decision; settlement\ndefinition" },
	{ "question": "確立", "answers": [ "かくりつ" ], "comment": "establishment; settlement\nto establish; to settle" },
	{ "question": "磁器", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "porcelain (esp. hard-paste porcelain); china; chinaware" },
	{ "question": "磁気", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "magnetism" },
	{ "question": "社", "answers": [ "やしろ", "しゃ" ], "comment": "shrine (usually Shinto)\ncompany; association; society\nregional Chinese god of the earth (or a village built in its honour)\ncounter for companies, shrines, etc." },
	{ "question": "社交", "answers": [ "しゃこう" ], "comment": "social life; social intercourse" },
	{ "question": "社宅", "answers": [ "しゃたく" ], "comment": "company owned house" },
	{ "question": "祈り", "answers": [ "いのり" ], "comment": "prayer; supplication" },
	{ "question": "祝賀", "answers": [ "しゅくが" ], "comment": "celebration; congratulations" },
	{ "question": "神殿", "answers": [ "しんでん" ], "comment": "temple; sacred place; shrine; sanctuary; tabernacle" },
	{ "question": "神秘", "answers": [ "しんぴ" ], "comment": "mystery; mysteriousness; secret" },
	{ "question": "神聖", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "holiness; sacredness; sanctity; dignity" },
	{ "question": "票", "answers": [ "ひょう" ], "comment": "vote; ballot\nlabel; ticket; tag; stub" },
	{ "question": "禁じる", "answers": [ "きんじる" ], "comment": "to prohibit" },
	{ "question": "禁ずる", "answers": [ "きんずる" ], "comment": "to forbid; to suppress" },
	{ "question": "禁物", "answers": [ "きんもつ" ], "comment": "taboo; forbidden thing" },
	{ "question": "禅", "answers": [ "ぜん" ], "comment": "dhyana (profound meditation)\nZen (Buddhism)" },
	{ "question": "福", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "good fortune" },
	{ "question": "福祉", "answers": [ "ふくし" ], "comment": "welfare; well-being; social welfare; social security; social service" },
	{ "question": "私有", "answers": [ "しゆう" ], "comment": "private ownership" },
	{ "question": "私物", "answers": [ "しぶつ" ], "comment": "private property; personal effects" },
	{ "question": "私用", "answers": [ "しよう" ], "comment": "personal use\nprivate business" },
	{ "question": "科", "answers": [ "か", "とが", "しな" ], "comment": "department; section; faculty; school; arm\ncourse (of study); branch of study; specialization\n(taxonomical) family\narticle; item; thing; goods; stock\nquality\nflirtatiousness; coquetry\nerror; mistake; fault\nsin; wrongdoing; offense" },
	{ "question": "秘書", "answers": [ "ひしょ" ], "comment": "(private) secretary\ntreasured book; secret book" },
	{ "question": "秩序", "answers": [ "ちつじょ" ], "comment": "order; regularity; system; method" },
	{ "question": "称する", "answers": [ "しょうする" ], "comment": "to take the name of; to call oneself\nto pretend; to feign; to purport" },
	{ "question": "移住", "answers": [ "いじゅう" ], "comment": "migration; immigration" },
	{ "question": "移民", "answers": [ "いみん" ], "comment": "emigration; immigration\nemigrant; immigrant" },
	{ "question": "移行", "answers": [ "いこう" ], "comment": "switching over to; migration; transition" },
	{ "question": "税務署", "answers": [ "ぜいむしょ" ], "comment": "tax office" },
	{ "question": "種", "answers": [ "たね", "しゅ" ], "comment": "kind; variety\n(biological) species\n(logical) species\nseed (e.g. of a plant); pip; kind; variety; quality; tone\nmaterial (e.g. for an article); matter (e.g. of a story); subject; theme; (news) copy\ningredient; leaven (bread); main ingredient of a sushi\ncause; source\ntrick; secret; magician's trick; inside story\npaternal blood; lineage\nbreed (of a stock); sperm; semen\ncause; seed; origin\nvariety; kind\ncounter for varieties" },
	{ "question": "種々", "answers": [ "しゅじゅ", "くさぐさ" ], "comment": "variety" },
	{ "question": "稲光", "answers": [ "いなびかり" ], "comment": "(flash of) lightning" },
	{ "question": "穂", "answers": [ "ほ" ], "comment": "ear (of plant); head (of plant)\npoint; tip\nscion (in grafting); cion" },
	{ "question": "積もり", "answers": [ "つもり" ], "comment": "intention; plan\nconviction; belief" },
	{ "question": "究極", "answers": [ "きゅうきょく" ], "comment": "ultimate; extreme; final; eventual" },
	{ "question": "空しい", "answers": [ "むなしい" ], "comment": "empty; void; vacant\nvain; fruitless; futile; ineffective\nlifeless" },
	{ "question": "空ろ", "answers": [ "うつろ" ], "comment": "cavity; hollow; void\nhollow (voice); empty (heart); blank (eyes, face, etc.); vacant (stare)" },
	{ "question": "空腹", "answers": [ "くうふく" ], "comment": "hunger" },
	{ "question": "空間", "answers": [ "くうかん", "あきま" ], "comment": "space; room; airspace\nvacancy; room for rent or lease" },
	{ "question": "突く", "answers": [ "つく", "つつく" ], "comment": "to prick; to stab\nto poke; to prod; to push; to thrust; to nudge; to hit; to strike\nto use (a cane); to prop oneself up with; to press against (the floor, etc.)\nto attack\nto brave (the rain, etc.)\nto poke (repeatedly, lightly); to nudge\nto peck at (one's food); to pick at\nto peck at (someone's faults, etc.)\nto egg on; to put up to" },
	{ "question": "突っ張る", "answers": [ "つっぱる" ], "comment": "to support; to become stiff; to become taut; to thrust (one's opponent); to stick to (one's opinion); to insist on" },
	{ "question": "突如", "answers": [ "とつじょ" ], "comment": "suddenly; all of a sudden" },
	{ "question": "突破", "answers": [ "とっぱ" ], "comment": "breaking through; breakthrough; penetration" },
	{ "question": "窒息", "answers": [ "ちっそく" ], "comment": "suffocation; choking; asphyxia" },
	{ "question": "窮乏", "answers": [ "きゅうぼう" ], "comment": "poverty; destitution; privation; indigence; penury" },
	{ "question": "窮屈", "answers": [ "きゅうくつ" ], "comment": "narrow; tight; cramped\nformal; stiff; strict; ceremonious; rigid\nconstrained; uncomfortable\ntight (e.g. finances)" },
	{ "question": "立ち寄る", "answers": [ "たちよる" ], "comment": "to stop by; to drop in for a short visit" },
	{ "question": "立体", "answers": [ "りったい" ], "comment": "solid body; three-dimensional object\nmulti-storey car park" },
	{ "question": "立方", "answers": [ "りっぽう", "たちかた" ], "comment": "way of standing\ndancer (in a Japanese dance performance)\ncube" },
	{ "question": "立法", "answers": [ "りっぽう" ], "comment": "legislation; lawmaking" },
	{ "question": "第", "answers": [ "だい" ], "comment": "prefix for forming ordinal numbers" },
	{ "question": "第一", "answers": [ "だいいち" ], "comment": "first; foremost; number one" },
	{ "question": "等", "answers": [ "など", "とう" ], "comment": "et cetera; etc.; and the like; and so forth\nor something\nthe likes of\nclass; order; rank\net cetera; etc.; and the like\nequal; iso-\npluralizing suffix\nor so; rough indicator of direction, location, amount, etc.\nnominalizing suffix" },
	{ "question": "等級", "answers": [ "とうきゅう" ], "comment": "grade; class; degree; rank; rating; order; points\nmagnitude" },
	{ "question": "筒", "answers": [ "つつ" ], "comment": "pipe; tube; cylinder\ngun barrel\ngun" },
	{ "question": "策", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "plan; policy\nwhip; lash; scourge\nstick; cane; rod; pointer" },
	{ "question": "箇所", "answers": [ "かしょ" ], "comment": "passage; place; point; part" },
	{ "question": "箇条書き", "answers": [ "かじょうがき" ], "comment": "itemized form; itemised form; itemization; itemisation" },
	{ "question": "管", "answers": [ "くだ", "かん" ], "comment": "pipe; tube" },
	{ "question": "節", "answers": [ "せつ", "ふし" ], "comment": "occasion; time\nsection (of a literary work); paragraph; verse; stanza; passage\nprinciple; integrity\nnode (of a plant stem)\nclause\n(taxonomical) section\nknot (nautical mile per hour)\njoint; knuckle\ntune; melody\nknot (in wood); node in a bamboo stem\npart; notable characteristic\ncharacteristic way of speaking\nspace between two nodes (on bamboo, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "築く", "answers": [ "きずく" ], "comment": "to build; to construct; to erect\nto amass (e.g. fortune); to pile up" },
	{ "question": "簡易", "answers": [ "かんい" ], "comment": "simplicity; convenience; easiness; quasi-" },
	{ "question": "簡潔", "answers": [ "かんけつ" ], "comment": "brevity; conciseness; simplicity" },
	{ "question": "簡素", "answers": [ "かんそ" ], "comment": "simplicity; plain" },
	{ "question": "粉々", "answers": [ "こなごな" ], "comment": "in very small pieces" },
	{ "question": "粉末", "answers": [ "ふんまつ" ], "comment": "fine powder" },
	{ "question": "粋", "answers": [ "いき", "すい" ], "comment": "chic; smart; stylish; tasteful; refined; sophisticated; worldly\nconsiderate; understanding; sympathetic\nessence; the best; the cream" },
	{ "question": "粗筋", "answers": [ "あらすじ" ], "comment": "outline; summary; argument" },
	{ "question": "粘り", "answers": [ "ねばり" ], "comment": "stickiness; viscosity\ntenacity; persistence" },
	{ "question": "粘る", "answers": [ "ねばる" ], "comment": "to be sticky; to be adhesive\nto persevere; to persist; to stick to; to hold out; to linger" },
	{ "question": "精密", "answers": [ "せいみつ" ], "comment": "precise; exact; detailed; minute; close" },
	{ "question": "精巧", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "elaborate; delicate; exquisite" },
	{ "question": "系", "answers": [ "けい" ], "comment": "system; lineage; group\ncorollary\nsystem (range of strata that correspond to a particular time period)\n(taxonomical) series" },
	{ "question": "納まる", "answers": [ "おさまる" ], "comment": "to be in one's place; to be installed; to settle into\nto be delivered; to be obtained; to be paid\nto be settled; to be sorted out\nto lessen (e.g. of storms, pain); to calm down\nto be fit tightly into (e.g. a frame); to be sheathed (in a scabbard)" },
	{ "question": "納入", "answers": [ "のうにゅう" ], "comment": "payment (taxes, fees, etc.)\nsupply (of goods); delivery" },
	{ "question": "紛らわしい", "answers": [ "まぎらわしい" ], "comment": "confusing; misleading; equivocal; ambiguous; easily mixed up (e.g. similar words)" },
	{ "question": "紛れる", "answers": [ "まぎれる" ], "comment": "to disappear into; to be lost in; to slip into; to get mixed in among\nto do something under the cover of (confusion, etc.)\nto be almost indistinguishable; to be confusingly similar\nto be diverted from (negative emotions, etc.); to forget about\nto be distracted by; to be too absorbed in" },
	{ "question": "紛争", "answers": [ "ふんそう" ], "comment": "dispute; trouble; strife" },
	{ "question": "紛失", "answers": [ "ふんしつ" ], "comment": "losing something" },
	{ "question": "素っ気ない", "answers": [ "そっけない" ], "comment": "cold; short; curt; blunt" },
	{ "question": "素敵", "answers": [ "すてき" ], "comment": "lovely; dreamy; beautiful; great; fantastic; superb; cool; capital" },
	{ "question": "素早い", "answers": [ "すばやい" ], "comment": "fast; quick; prompt; nimble; agile\nquick (to understand); sharp (judgement)" },
	{ "question": "素朴", "answers": [ "そぼく" ], "comment": "simplicity; artlessness; naivete; pristineness; idyll" },
	{ "question": "素材", "answers": [ "そざい" ], "comment": "raw materials; subject matter" },
	{ "question": "紡績", "answers": [ "ぼうせき" ], "comment": "spinning" },
	{ "question": "細やか", "answers": [ "こまやか", "ささやか" ], "comment": "friendly; heartfelt; tender\nmeagre; meager; modest" },
	{ "question": "細工", "answers": [ "さいく" ], "comment": "work; craftsmanship; tactics; trick" },
	{ "question": "細胞", "answers": [ "さいぼう", "さいほう" ], "comment": "cell" },
	{ "question": "細菌", "answers": [ "さいきん" ], "comment": "bacillus; bacterium; germ" },
	{ "question": "紳士", "answers": [ "しんし" ], "comment": "gentleman" },
	{ "question": "終始", "answers": [ "しゅうし" ], "comment": "beginning and end\ndoing something from beginning to end; being unchanged from beginning to end\nfrom beginning to end; the whole time; throughout; consistently" },
	{ "question": "終日", "answers": [ "しゅうじつ" ], "comment": "all day; for a whole day" },
	{ "question": "組み合わせ", "answers": [ "くみあわせ" ], "comment": "combination" },
	{ "question": "組み合わせる", "answers": [ "くみあわせる" ], "comment": "to join together; to combine; to join up" },
	{ "question": "組み込む", "answers": [ "くみこむ" ], "comment": "to insert; to include; to incorporate; to cut in (printing)" },
	{ "question": "経る", "answers": [ "へる" ], "comment": "to pass; to elapse; to go by\nto pass through; to go through\nto experience; to go through; to undergo" },
	{ "question": "経歴", "answers": [ "けいれき" ], "comment": "personal history; career" },
	{ "question": "経緯", "answers": [ "けいい", "いきさつ" ], "comment": "details; particulars; whole story; sequence of events; chronology; circumstances; how it started; how things got this way\nlongitude and latitude\nwarp and weft; warp and woof" },
	{ "question": "経費", "answers": [ "けいひ" ], "comment": "expenses; cost; outlay" },
	{ "question": "経路", "answers": [ "けいろ" ], "comment": "course; route; path; channel\nprocess; means" },
	{ "question": "経過", "answers": [ "けいか" ], "comment": "passage; expiration; progress; transition" },
	{ "question": "結び", "answers": [ "むすび" ], "comment": "ending; conclusion\njoin; union; connecting\nknot; knotting\nrice ball" },
	{ "question": "結び付き", "answers": [ "むすびつき" ], "comment": "connection; relation" },
	{ "question": "結び付く", "answers": [ "むすびつく" ], "comment": "to be related; to be connected; to be joined together\nto result in; to lead to; to bring about" },
	{ "question": "結び付ける", "answers": [ "むすびつける" ], "comment": "to combine; to join; to tie on; to attach with a knot; to bind (e.g. an address)" },
	{ "question": "結合", "answers": [ "けつごう" ], "comment": "combination; union; binding; catenation; coupling; joining\nbond" },
	{ "question": "結成", "answers": [ "けっせい" ], "comment": "formation; combination" },
	{ "question": "結晶", "answers": [ "けっしょう" ], "comment": "crystal; crystallization; crystallisation\nfruits (of labor, union, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "結束", "answers": [ "けっそく" ], "comment": "union; unity; solidarity\nbundling; binding; tying\nputting on (clothes, armour, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "結核", "answers": [ "けっかく" ], "comment": "tuberculosis; tubercule" },
	{ "question": "絡む", "answers": [ "からむ" ], "comment": "to entangle; to entwine\nto pick a quarrel; to find fault\nto be involved with; to be influenced by; to develop a connection with" },
	{ "question": "給う", "answers": [ "たまう" ], "comment": "semi-polite or endearing auxiliary verb indicating reception by the speaker" },
	{ "question": "給仕", "answers": [ "きゅうじ" ], "comment": "waiting on a table; serving (at dinner)\nwaiter; waitress; waitperson; server; cabin boy; bellboy; page; pageboy\noffice boy; office girl" },
	{ "question": "給食", "answers": [ "きゅうしょく" ], "comment": "provision of lunch (e.g. at office, school, etc.); providing a meal; lunch service" },
	{ "question": "統制", "answers": [ "とうせい" ], "comment": "regulation; control" },
	{ "question": "統合", "answers": [ "とうごう" ], "comment": "integration; unification; synthesis\nintegrated; built-in" },
	{ "question": "統治", "answers": [ "とうち", "とうじ" ], "comment": "rule; reign; government; governing" },
	{ "question": "統率", "answers": [ "とうそつ" ], "comment": "command; lead; generalship; leadership" },
	{ "question": "絶える", "answers": [ "たえる" ], "comment": "to die out; to peter out; to become extinct\nto cease; to be stopped; to be discontinued; to be cut off" },
	{ "question": "絶つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to sever; to cut off\nto suppress; to eradicate; to exterminate\nto abstain (from); to give up" },
	{ "question": "絶望", "answers": [ "ぜつぼう" ], "comment": "despair; hopelessness" },
	{ "question": "絶版", "answers": [ "ぜっぱん" ], "comment": "out of print" },
	{ "question": "継ぎ目", "answers": [ "つぎめ" ], "comment": "joint; seam; joining point" },
	{ "question": "継ぐ", "answers": [ "つぐ" ], "comment": "to succeed (someone in a business or inheritance)" },
	{ "question": "網", "answers": [ "あみ" ], "comment": "net; netting\nweb\nnetwork" },
	{ "question": "綻びる", "answers": [ "ほころびる" ], "comment": "to come apart at the seams; to be ripped; to be torn\nto begin to open; to begin to bloom\nto smile broadly; to break into a smile" },
	{ "question": "緊急", "answers": [ "きんきゅう" ], "comment": "urgent; pressing; emergency" },
	{ "question": "総", "answers": [ "そう", "ふさ" ], "comment": "whole; all; general; gross; entire; overall\ntuft; tassel\nbunch (of grapes, etc.)\nsection (of an orange, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "総会", "answers": [ "そうかい" ], "comment": "general meeting" },
	{ "question": "総合", "answers": [ "そうごう" ], "comment": "synthesis; coordination; putting together; integration; composite\ncomprehensive" },
	{ "question": "締め切り", "answers": [ "しめきり" ], "comment": "deadline; closing; cut-off; end\ncofferdam\nclosed (door, window, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "編", "answers": [ "へん" ], "comment": "compilation (of a text); editing\nvolume (of a text)\ncompleted literary work" },
	{ "question": "緩む", "answers": [ "ゆるむ" ], "comment": "to become loose; to slacken (e.g. rope)\nto become less tense; to relax; to let one's guard down\nto slacken (e.g. coldness, supervision); to become lax\nto become softer (e.g. ground, facial expression); (of ice) to partially melt\nto decrease (e.g. speed)\n(of a market price) to go down slightly" },
	{ "question": "緩める", "answers": [ "ゆるめる" ], "comment": "to loosen; to slow down" },
	{ "question": "緩やか", "answers": [ "ゆるやか" ], "comment": "loose; slack\ngentle; easy; slow\nlenient; liberal; lax" },
	{ "question": "緩和", "answers": [ "かんわ" ], "comment": "relief; mitigation; alleviation; relaxation; softening" },
	{ "question": "練る", "answers": [ "ねる" ], "comment": "to knead; to thicken into a paste (stirring over a flame)\nto polish (a plan, etc.); to refine; to elaborate; to work out\nto train; to drill; to exercise\nto gloss (silk); to soften; to degum\nto tan (leather)\nto temper (steel)\nto walk in procession; to parade; to march" },
	{ "question": "縁", "answers": [ "えん", "ゆかり", "ふち", "へり", "えにし" ], "comment": "related to (some person or place); affinity; connection\nfate; destiny (esp. as a mysterious force that binds two people together)\nrelationship (e.g. between two people); bond; link; connection\nfamily ties; affinity\nopportunity; chance (to meet someone and start a relationship)\npratyaya (indirect conditions, as opposed to direct causes)\nnarrow open-air veranda\nrim; brim; edge; brink\nreason; significance; cause\nsomething to rely on; aid; clue; way; means\nsomeone to rely on; relative\nreminder; memento\nedge (of a river, woods, etc.); shoulder (of a road)\nrim; brim; hem; margin; fringe; selvage\nfabric border (of a tatami mat, etc.); edging" },
	{ "question": "縁側", "answers": [ "えんがわ" ], "comment": "veranda; porch; balcony; open corridor\nbone at the base of a fin; meat at the base of a fin (esp. of a flatfish)" },
	{ "question": "縁談", "answers": [ "えんだん" ], "comment": "marriage proposal; marriage talks" },
	{ "question": "縮まる", "answers": [ "ちぢまる" ], "comment": "to shorten; to narrow; to close" },
	{ "question": "繁栄", "answers": [ "はんえい" ], "comment": "prospering; prosperity; thriving; flourishing" },
	{ "question": "繁殖", "answers": [ "はんしょく" ], "comment": "breeding; multiplication; increase; propagation; reproduction" },
	{ "question": "繁盛", "answers": [ "はんじょう" ], "comment": "prosperity; flourishing; thriving" },
	{ "question": "繊維", "answers": [ "せんい" ], "comment": "fibre; fiber; textile" },
	{ "question": "織", "answers": [ "おり" ], "comment": "weave; weaving; woven item" },
	{ "question": "織る", "answers": [ "おる" ], "comment": "to weave" },
	{ "question": "織物", "answers": [ "おりもの" ], "comment": "textile; fabric" },
	{ "question": "繕う", "answers": [ "つくろう" ], "comment": "to mend; to patch up; to repair; to fix; to darn; to trim\nto fix (hair, clothes, appearance etc.); to adjust; to tidy up; to groom\nto keep up appearances; to cover up (mistakes etc.); to gloss over\nto treat (illness, injury, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "罰", "answers": [ "ばつ", "ばち" ], "comment": "(divine) punishment; curse; retribution\npunishment; penalty" },
	{ "question": "罵る", "answers": [ "ののしる" ], "comment": "to abuse (verbally); to curse at; to shout abuse at; to speak ill of" },
	{ "question": "美", "answers": [ "び" ], "comment": "beauty\naugust\nbeautiful" },
	{ "question": "美味しい", "answers": [ "おいしい" ], "comment": "delicious; tasty; sweet\nattractive; appealing; convenient; favorable; desirable" },
	{ "question": "美術", "answers": [ "びじゅつ" ], "comment": "art; fine arts" },
	{ "question": "群", "answers": [ "ぐん" ], "comment": "group; bunch; crowd; throng; swarm; band\ngroup\ngathering" },
	{ "question": "群がる", "answers": [ "むらがる" ], "comment": "to swarm; to gather" },
	{ "question": "群集", "answers": [ "ぐんしゅう" ], "comment": "crowd; community; group; herd; gathering; assembly" },
	{ "question": "義理", "answers": [ "ぎり" ], "comment": "duty; sense of duty; honor; honour; decency; courtesy; debt of gratitude; social obligation\nin-law; relation by marriage" },
	{ "question": "羽毛", "answers": [ "うもう" ], "comment": "feathers; plumage; down" },
	{ "question": "羽音", "answers": [ "はおと" ], "comment": "sound of flapping wings (of a bird)\nbuzz; hum (of an insect)" },
	{ "question": "老いる", "answers": [ "おいる" ], "comment": "to age; to grow old" },
	{ "question": "老ける", "answers": [ "ふける" ], "comment": "to age; to grow old (esp. in appearance); to show marks of age" },
	{ "question": "老衰", "answers": [ "ろうすい" ], "comment": "senility; senile decay; infirmity (through age)" },
	{ "question": "考古学", "answers": [ "こうこがく" ], "comment": "archaeology; archeology" },
	{ "question": "耐える", "answers": [ "たえる" ], "comment": "to bear; to stand; to endure; to put up with\nto support; to withstand; to resist; to brave\nto be fit for; to be equal to" },
	{ "question": "耕作", "answers": [ "こうさく" ], "comment": "cultivation; farming" },
	{ "question": "耳鼻科", "answers": [ "じびか" ], "comment": "otolaryngology; concerning the ear, nose, and throat" },
	{ "question": "聖書", "answers": [ "せいしょ" ], "comment": "Bible; scriptures" },
	{ "question": "聞き取り", "answers": [ "ききとり" ], "comment": "listening comprehension; aural comprehension\nhearing what others say; gathering information, opinions, etc.; public hearing" },
	{ "question": "聴覚", "answers": [ "ちょうかく" ], "comment": "the sense of hearing" },
	{ "question": "聴診器", "answers": [ "ちょうしんき" ], "comment": "stethoscope" },
	{ "question": "聴講", "answers": [ "ちょうこう" ], "comment": "lecture attendance; auditing" },
	{ "question": "職務", "answers": [ "しょくむ" ], "comment": "professional duties" },
	{ "question": "職員", "answers": [ "しょくいん" ], "comment": "staff member; personnel" },
	{ "question": "肉体", "answers": [ "にくたい" ], "comment": "the body; the flesh" },
	{ "question": "肉親", "answers": [ "にくしん" ], "comment": "blood relationship; blood relative" },
	{ "question": "肝心", "answers": [ "かんじん" ], "comment": "essential; fundamental; crucial; vital; main" },
	{ "question": "股", "answers": [ "もも", "また" ], "comment": "crotch; crutch; groin; thigh\nfork (in a tree, road, river, etc.); tines (of a fork)\nthigh\nfemoral" },
	{ "question": "肥料", "answers": [ "ひりょう" ], "comment": "manure; fertilizer; fertiliser" },
	{ "question": "育ち", "answers": [ "そだち" ], "comment": "breeding; growth" },
	{ "question": "育成", "answers": [ "いくせい" ], "comment": "rearing; training; nurture; cultivation; promotion" },
	{ "question": "肺", "answers": [ "はい" ], "comment": "lung" },
	{ "question": "背く", "answers": [ "そむく" ], "comment": "to run counter to; to go against; to disobey; to infringe" },
	{ "question": "背後", "answers": [ "はいご" ], "comment": "back; rear\nbackground; behind the scenes" },
	{ "question": "背景", "answers": [ "はいけい" ], "comment": "background; scenery; backdrop; setting; circumstance; context\nbacking; support (from behind the scenes)" },
	{ "question": "胴", "answers": [ "どう" ], "comment": "trunk; torso; body; abdomen; waist\nplastron (in kendo); touching the plastron (kimari-te in kendo)\nframe (of a drum, etc.); sound box (of a shamisen, etc.); hull (of a ship)" },
	{ "question": "脂肪", "answers": [ "しぼう" ], "comment": "fat; grease; blubber" },
	{ "question": "脅かす", "answers": [ "おどかす", "おびやかす" ], "comment": "to threaten; to menace\nto startle; to surprise\nto intimidate; to scare\nto jeopardize; to endanger; to imperil" },
	{ "question": "脅す", "answers": [ "おどす" ], "comment": "to threaten; to menace; to bully" },
	{ "question": "脅迫", "answers": [ "きょうはく" ], "comment": "threat; menace; coercion; terrorism" },
	{ "question": "脈", "answers": [ "みゃく" ], "comment": "pulse\nvein\nchain (of mountains, etc.)\nhope\nthread (of an argument)" },
	{ "question": "脚本", "answers": [ "きゃくほん" ], "comment": "script; screenplay; scenario" },
	{ "question": "脚色", "answers": [ "きゃくしょく" ], "comment": "dramatization (e.g. of a novel); dramatisation; adaptation\ndramatization; embellishment; exaggeration; embroidery" },
	{ "question": "脱する", "answers": [ "だっする" ], "comment": "to escape from; to get out" },
	{ "question": "脱出", "answers": [ "だっしゅつ" ], "comment": "escape; break-out\nprolapse; proptosis" },
	{ "question": "脱退", "answers": [ "だったい" ], "comment": "secession; retirement; withdrawal (e.g. from a lawsuit)" },
	{ "question": "脳", "answers": [ "のう" ], "comment": "brain\nbrains; mind\nbrain; skull; head" },
	{ "question": "腐敗", "answers": [ "ふはい" ], "comment": "decomposition; putrefaction; putrescence; spoilage\ncorruption; degeneracy; decay; depravity" },
	{ "question": "腕前", "answers": [ "うでまえ" ], "comment": "ability; skill; facility" },
	{ "question": "腫れる", "answers": [ "はれる" ], "comment": "to swell (from inflammation); to become swollen" },
	{ "question": "腸", "answers": [ "ちょう", "わた" ], "comment": "guts; bowels; intestines" },
	{ "question": "腹立ち", "answers": [ "はらだち" ], "comment": "anger" },
	{ "question": "膜", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "membrane; film" },
	{ "question": "膨れる", "answers": [ "ふくれる" ], "comment": "to swell (out); to expand; to be inflated; to distend; to bulge\nto get cross; to get sulky; to pout" },
	{ "question": "膳", "answers": [ "ぜん" ], "comment": "small dining table (usu. for a single person); serving tray (with legs)\nmeal; food; serving\ncounter for bowlfuls of rice; counter for pairs of chopsticks" },
	{ "question": "臆病", "answers": [ "おくびょう" ], "comment": "cowardice; timidity" },
	{ "question": "臨む", "answers": [ "のぞむ" ], "comment": "to look out on\nto face\nto deal with\nto attend (e.g. function); to appear (e.g. in court)" },
	{ "question": "自ら", "answers": [ "みずから", "おのずから" ], "comment": "naturally; as a matter of course\noneself\nfor one's self; personally" },
	{ "question": "自主", "answers": [ "じしゅ" ], "comment": "independence; autonomy" },
	{ "question": "自信", "answers": [ "じしん" ], "comment": "self-confidence; confidence (in oneself)" },
	{ "question": "自動詞", "answers": [ "じどうし" ], "comment": "intransitive verb" },
	{ "question": "自在", "answers": [ "じざい" ], "comment": "freely; at will" },
	{ "question": "自尊心", "answers": [ "じそんしん" ], "comment": "self-esteem; self-respect; self-importance; conceit; pride" },
	{ "question": "自己", "answers": [ "じこ" ], "comment": "self; oneself" },
	{ "question": "自我", "answers": [ "じが" ], "comment": "self; the ego" },
	{ "question": "自立", "answers": [ "じりつ" ], "comment": "independence; self-reliance" },
	{ "question": "自覚", "answers": [ "じかく" ], "comment": "self-consciousness; self-awareness" },
	{ "question": "自転", "answers": [ "じてん" ], "comment": "rotation (usu. on an axis); turning; spin" },
	{ "question": "自首", "answers": [ "じしゅ" ], "comment": "surrender; give oneself up" },
	{ "question": "至って", "answers": [ "いたって" ], "comment": "very much; exceedingly; extremely" },
	{ "question": "興じる", "answers": [ "きょうじる" ], "comment": "to amuse oneself; to make merry" },
	{ "question": "興奮", "answers": [ "こうふん" ], "comment": "excitement; stimulation; agitation; arousal" },
	{ "question": "興業", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "industrial enterprise" },
	{ "question": "舗装", "answers": [ "ほそう" ], "comment": "pavement; road surface" },
	{ "question": "舞う", "answers": [ "まう" ], "comment": "to dance (orig. a whirling dance)\nto flutter about; to revolve" },
	{ "question": "舟運", "answers": [ "しゅううん" ], "comment": "transportation by water (e.g. by ship)" },
	{ "question": "航海", "answers": [ "こうかい" ], "comment": "sail; voyage" },
	{ "question": "船乗り", "answers": [ "ふなのり" ], "comment": "getting on board\nsailor; seaman" },
	{ "question": "船舶", "answers": [ "せんぱく" ], "comment": "ship" },
	{ "question": "良い", "answers": [ "いい", "よい" ], "comment": "good; excellent; fine; nice; pleasant; agreeable\nsufficient (can be used to turn down an offer); ready; prepared\nprofitable (e.g. deal, business offer, etc.); beneficial\nOK" },
	{ "question": "良好", "answers": [ "りょうこう" ], "comment": "favorable; favourable; satisfactory" },
	{ "question": "良心", "answers": [ "りょうしん" ], "comment": "conscience" },
	{ "question": "良識", "answers": [ "りょうしき" ], "comment": "good sense" },
	{ "question": "良質", "answers": [ "りょうしつ" ], "comment": "good quality; fine quality; superior quality; high quality" },
	{ "question": "色々", "answers": [ "いろいろ" ], "comment": "various\nvarious colors (colours)" },
	{ "question": "色彩", "answers": [ "しきさい" ], "comment": "colour; color; hue; tints" },
	{ "question": "艶", "answers": [ "えん", "つや", "あで" ], "comment": "gloss; glaze\ncharm; romance; love; youthfulness\ncolor; colour; feeling\ncharming; fascinating; voluptuous" },
	{ "question": "芝", "answers": [ "しば" ], "comment": "lawn; sod; turf" },
	{ "question": "花びら", "answers": [ "はなびら" ], "comment": "(flower) petal" },
	{ "question": "花壇", "answers": [ "かだん" ], "comment": "flower bed" },
	{ "question": "花粉", "answers": [ "かふん" ], "comment": "pollen" },
	{ "question": "苗", "answers": [ "なえ" ], "comment": "seedling\nMiao (people); Hmong" },
	{ "question": "苛める", "answers": [ "いじめる" ], "comment": "to tease; to torment; to persecute; to chastise" },
	{ "question": "若しくは", "answers": [ "もしくは" ], "comment": "or; otherwise" },
	{ "question": "若干", "answers": [ "じゃっかん" ], "comment": "some; few; a number of; a little (bit)\nsomewhat; to a certain extent\nmany; a lot" },
	{ "question": "苦しめる", "answers": [ "くるしめる" ], "comment": "to torment; to pain; to inflict (physical) pain; to hurt\nto harass; to cause (emotional) pain; to afflict; to distress; to bother; to trouble; to stump; to baffle" },
	{ "question": "英字", "answers": [ "えいじ" ], "comment": "English letter; alphabetic character" },
	{ "question": "英雄", "answers": [ "えいゆう" ], "comment": "hero; heroine; great person\nEroica Symphony (Beethoven, 1804)\nHeroic Polonaise (Chopin)" },
	{ "question": "茎", "answers": [ "くき" ], "comment": "stalk; stem\ncore\ntang (of a sword, etc.)\nmiddle of a nest of boxes" },
	{ "question": "茶の湯", "answers": [ "ちゃのゆ" ], "comment": "tea ceremony" },
	{ "question": "茶の間", "answers": [ "ちゃのま" ], "comment": "living room (Japanese-style)" },
	{ "question": "荒っぽい", "answers": [ "あらっぽい" ], "comment": "rough; rude" },
	{ "question": "荒らす", "answers": [ "あらす" ], "comment": "to lay waste; to devastate; to damage\nto invade; to break into\nto troll (e.g. web forums); to spam" },
	{ "question": "荒廃", "answers": [ "こうはい" ], "comment": "ruin; destruction; devastation; waste; decay" },
	{ "question": "荷", "answers": [ "に" ], "comment": "load; baggage; cargo; freight; goods\nburden; responsibility\ncounter for loads (that can be carried on one's shoulders)" },
	{ "question": "荷造り", "answers": [ "にづくり" ], "comment": "packing; baling; crating" },
	{ "question": "華々しい", "answers": [ "はなばなしい" ], "comment": "brilliant; magnificent; spectacular" },
	{ "question": "華やか", "answers": [ "はなやか" ], "comment": "showy; brilliant; gorgeous; florid; gay" },
	{ "question": "華美", "answers": [ "かび" ], "comment": "pomp; splendor; splendour; gaudiness" },
	{ "question": "萎える", "answers": [ "なえる" ], "comment": "to lose strength; to become weak; to waste away\nto wither; to droop" },
	{ "question": "落ちる", "answers": [ "おちる" ], "comment": "to fall down; to drop; to fall (e.g. rain); to sink (e.g. sun or moon); to fall onto (e.g. light or one's gaze); to be used in a certain place (e.g. money)\nto be omitted; to be missing\nto decrease; to sink\nto fail (e.g. exam or class); to lose (contest, election, etc.)\nto crash; to degenerate; to degrade; to fall behind\nto become indecent (of a conversation)\nto be ruined; to go under\nto fade; to come out (e.g. a stain); to come off (e.g. makeup); to be removed (e.g. illness, possessing spirit, name on a list)\nto fall (into someone's hands); to become someone's possession\nto fall (into a trap); to fall (for a trick)\nto give in; to give up; to confess; to flee\nto fall; to be defeated; to surrender\nto come to (in the end); to end in\nto fall (in love, asleep, etc.)\nto swoon (judo)\nto consent; to understand\nto crash; to freeze\nto die\nto move to the depths" },
	{ "question": "落ち着き", "answers": [ "おちつき" ], "comment": "calmness; composure; presence of mind\nstability; steadiness" },
	{ "question": "落ち葉", "answers": [ "おちば" ], "comment": "fallen leaves; leaf litter\ndeciduous" },
	{ "question": "落ち込む", "answers": [ "おちこむ" ], "comment": "to feel down; to feel sad; to be depressed; to be in low spirits\nto be in a slump (business, economy, etc.); to be in an unfavourable condition\nto fall into (e.g. a hole)" },
	{ "question": "落とす", "answers": [ "おとす" ], "comment": "to drop; to lose; to let fall; to shed (light); to cast (one's gaze); to pour in (liquid); to leave behind\nto clean off (dirt, makeup, paint, etc.); to remove (e.g. stains or facial hair); to lose; to spend money at a certain place; to omit; to leave out; to secretly let escape\nto lose (a match); to reject (an applicant); to fail (a course); to defeat (in an election)\nto lower (e.g. shoulders or voice); to lessen (e.g. production or body weight); to worsen (quality); to reduce (e.g. rank or popularity); to speak badly of; to make light of; to fall into straitened circumstances\nto fall into (e.g. a dilemma or sin); to make one's own; to have one's bid accepted; to force surrender; to take (e.g. an enemy camp or castle); to forcefully convince; to press for a confession; to deal with\nto download; to copy from a computer to another medium\nto make someone swoon (judo)\nto finish a story (e.g. with the punch line)\nto finish (a period, e.g. of fasting)" },
	{ "question": "落下", "answers": [ "らっか" ], "comment": "fall; drop; coming down" },
	{ "question": "著", "answers": [ "ちょ" ], "comment": "work; book\n(a book) by\nobvious; striking" },
	{ "question": "著しい", "answers": [ "いちじるしい" ], "comment": "striking; remarkable; considerable (used for good, bad, and neutral observations)" },
	{ "question": "著名", "answers": [ "ちょめい" ], "comment": "well-known; noted; celebrated" },
	{ "question": "著書", "answers": [ "ちょしょ" ], "comment": "literary work; book" },
	{ "question": "葬る", "answers": [ "ほうむる" ], "comment": "to bury; to inter; to entomb\nto cover up; to hush up; to shelve" },
	{ "question": "蒸留", "answers": [ "じょうりゅう" ], "comment": "distillation" },
	{ "question": "蓄積", "answers": [ "ちくせき" ], "comment": "accumulation; accumulate; store" },
	{ "question": "蓋", "answers": [ "ふた" ], "comment": "cover; lid; cap" },
	{ "question": "蔵", "answers": [ "くら", "ぞう" ], "comment": "warehouse; storehouse; cellar; magazine; granary; godown; depository; treasury; elevator\npossession; ownership\n(former) Ministry of Finance\nTibet; Tibetan people" },
	{ "question": "蔵相", "answers": [ "ぞうしょう" ], "comment": "Minister of Finance" },
	{ "question": "薄弱", "answers": [ "はくじゃく" ], "comment": "feebleness; weakness; weak" },
	{ "question": "蜂蜜", "answers": [ "はちみつ" ], "comment": "honey" },
	{ "question": "蜜", "answers": [ "みつ" ], "comment": "nectar\nhoney\nhoneydew\ntreacle; molasses\nsorbitol (when visible as dark patches inside an apple)" },
	{ "question": "融資", "answers": [ "ゆうし" ], "comment": "financing; loan" },
	{ "question": "融通", "answers": [ "ゆうずう", "ゆうづう" ], "comment": "lending (money); finance\nadaptability; versatility; flexibility; accommodation" },
	{ "question": "血管", "answers": [ "けっかん" ], "comment": "blood vessel; vein" },
	{ "question": "衆", "answers": [ "しゅう" ], "comment": "great numbers (of people); numerical superiority; masses\npeople; folk; clique; bunch" },
	{ "question": "衆議院", "answers": [ "しゅうぎいん" ], "comment": "lower house; House of Representatives" },
	{ "question": "行い", "answers": [ "おこない" ], "comment": "deed; act; action; conduct; behavior; behaviour; asceticism" },
	{ "question": "行き違い", "answers": [ "いきちがい" ], "comment": "crossing without meeting (e.g. letters in the post, people on the road); going astray\ndifference of opinion; misunderstanding; estrangement; disagreement" },
	{ "question": "行員", "answers": [ "こういん" ], "comment": "bank clerk" },
	{ "question": "行政", "answers": [ "ぎょうせい" ], "comment": "administration" },
	{ "question": "行為", "answers": [ "こうい" ], "comment": "act; deed; conduct" },
	{ "question": "行進", "answers": [ "こうしん" ], "comment": "march; parade" },
	{ "question": "街", "answers": [ "まち", "がい" ], "comment": ".. street; .. quarter; .. district\ntown; block; neighbourhood; neighborhood\nstreet; road\ndowntown; main street" },
	{ "question": "街道", "answers": [ "かいどう" ], "comment": "highway (esp. one existing from the Edo period); main road\nhighway (e.g. to success); path (to becoming ...)" },
	{ "question": "街頭", "answers": [ "がいとう" ], "comment": "in the street" },
	{ "question": "衛生", "answers": [ "えいせい" ], "comment": "health; hygiene; sanitation; medical" },
	{ "question": "衝撃", "answers": [ "しょうげき" ], "comment": "shock; impact; crash" },
	{ "question": "衣料", "answers": [ "いりょう" ], "comment": "clothing" },
	{ "question": "衣装", "answers": [ "いしょう" ], "comment": "clothing; costume; outfit; garment; dress" },
	{ "question": "衣類", "answers": [ "いるい" ], "comment": "clothes; clothing; garments" },
	{ "question": "衰える", "answers": [ "おとろえる" ], "comment": "to become weak; to decline; to wear; to abate; to decay; to wither; to waste away" },
	{ "question": "裁く", "answers": [ "さばく" ], "comment": "to judge" },
	{ "question": "裂ける", "answers": [ "さける" ], "comment": "to split; to tear; to burst" },
	{ "question": "装備", "answers": [ "そうび" ], "comment": "equipment" },
	{ "question": "装飾", "answers": [ "そうしょく" ], "comment": "ornament; decoration" },
	{ "question": "裏返し", "answers": [ "うらがえし" ], "comment": "inside out; upside down\nflip side; opposite; contrary; reverse" },
	{ "question": "補償", "answers": [ "ほしょう" ], "comment": "compensation; reparation" },
	{ "question": "補充", "answers": [ "ほじゅう" ], "comment": "replenishment; supplementation; supplement; replacement; refilling" },
	{ "question": "補助", "answers": [ "ほじょ" ], "comment": "assistance; support; aid; help\nsubsidy; supplement; subvention; grant-in-aid\nauxiliary; subsidiary\nspot (in bodybuilding)" },
	{ "question": "補強", "answers": [ "ほきょう" ], "comment": "compensation; reinforcement" },
	{ "question": "補給", "answers": [ "ほきゅう" ], "comment": "supply; supplying; replenishment" },
	{ "question": "補足", "answers": [ "ほそく" ], "comment": "supplement; complement" },
	{ "question": "裸足", "answers": [ "はだし" ], "comment": "barefoot\nsuperior to (a professional, etc. in ability or achievement)" },
	{ "question": "製", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "-made; make" },
	{ "question": "製法", "answers": [ "せいほう" ], "comment": "manufacturing method; recipe; formula" },
	{ "question": "製鉄", "answers": [ "せいてつ" ], "comment": "iron manufacture" },
	{ "question": "裾", "answers": [ "すそ" ], "comment": "hem; (trouser) cuff; shirttail\nbottom edge\nfoot (of a mountain)\ntips (of hair)\ndownstream" },
	{ "question": "複合", "answers": [ "ふくごう" ], "comment": "composite; combined; complex" },
	{ "question": "褒美", "answers": [ "ほうび" ], "comment": "reward; prize" },
	{ "question": "襟", "answers": [ "えり" ], "comment": "collar; lapel; neckband; neck\nnape of the neck; scruff of the neck" },
	{ "question": "襲う", "answers": [ "おそう" ], "comment": "to attack; to assail; to make an assault; to strike; to hunt down\nto succeed (someone in a post, role, etc.)\nto make a sudden visit" },
	{ "question": "襲撃", "answers": [ "しゅうげき" ], "comment": "attack; charge; raid" },
	{ "question": "西日", "answers": [ "にしび" ], "comment": "westering sun; setting sun\nSpanish-Japanese (gen. for translations and dictionaries)" },
	{ "question": "要する", "answers": [ "ようする" ], "comment": "to need; to demand; to take; to require" },
	{ "question": "要因", "answers": [ "よういん" ], "comment": "main cause; primary factor" },
	{ "question": "要望", "answers": [ "ようぼう" ], "comment": "demand for; request" },
	{ "question": "要請", "answers": [ "ようせい" ], "comment": "appeal; call for something; request; claim; demand\naxiom" },
	{ "question": "覆す", "answers": [ "くつがえす" ], "comment": "to overturn; to capsize; to upset\nto overthrow (government etc.)\nto reverse (decision etc.); to disprove (an established theory etc.); to overrule" },
	{ "question": "覆面", "answers": [ "ふくめん" ], "comment": "mask; veil; disguise\nanonymous; unmarked; incognito" },
	{ "question": "見すぼらしい", "answers": [ "みすぼらしい" ], "comment": "shabby; seedy" },
	{ "question": "見せびらかす", "answers": [ "みせびらかす" ], "comment": "to show off; to flaunt" },
	{ "question": "見せ物", "answers": [ "みせもの" ], "comment": "show; exhibition; spectacle" },
	{ "question": "見っともない", "answers": [ "みっともない" ], "comment": "shameful; disgraceful; indecent; unseemly; unbecoming; improper" },
	{ "question": "見合い", "answers": [ "みあい" ], "comment": "formal marriage interview; marriage meeting" },
	{ "question": "見合わせる", "answers": [ "みあわせる" ], "comment": "to exchange glances; to look at each other\nto postpone; to put off; to withhold; to abandon\nto contrast; to compare" },
	{ "question": "見地", "answers": [ "けんち" ], "comment": "point of view" },
	{ "question": "見掛ける", "answers": [ "みかける" ], "comment": "to (happen to) see; to notice; to catch sight of" },
	{ "question": "見方", "answers": [ "みかた" ], "comment": "viewpoint; point of view\nway of understanding; way of appreciating; how to look at something (e.g. noh, train schedule)" },
	{ "question": "見晴らし", "answers": [ "みはらし" ], "comment": "view; prospect; outlook" },
	{ "question": "見渡す", "answers": [ "みわたす" ], "comment": "to look out over; to survey (scene); to take an extensive view of" },
	{ "question": "見積り", "answers": [ "みつもり" ], "comment": "estimate; estimation; valuation; quotation" },
	{ "question": "見舞", "answers": [ "みまい" ], "comment": "visiting ill or distressed people; writing get-well letters\nget-well gifts; get-well letters\nexpression of sympathy; expression of concern; enquiry; inquiry" },
	{ "question": "見苦しい", "answers": [ "みぐるしい" ], "comment": "unsightly; ugly" },
	{ "question": "見落とす", "answers": [ "みおとす" ], "comment": "to overlook; to fail to notice; to miss (seeing)" },
	{ "question": "見込み", "answers": [ "みこみ" ], "comment": "hope; promise; possibility; chance; probability; likelihood\nexpectation; anticipation; forecast; estimate\nside of a structural member" },
	{ "question": "見逃す", "answers": [ "みのがす" ], "comment": "to miss; to overlook; to fail to notice\nto turn a blind eye (to a wrongdoing etc.); to ignore\nto pass up (an opportunity etc.)" },
	{ "question": "見通し", "answers": [ "みとおし" ], "comment": "unobstructed view; perspective; visibility; vista\nforecast; outlook; prospect; prediction\ninsight; foresight" },
	{ "question": "規制", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "regulation; (traffic) policing; control; restriction" },
	{ "question": "規定", "answers": [ "きてい" ], "comment": "stipulation; prescription; provision; regulation; rule" },
	{ "question": "規格", "answers": [ "きかく" ], "comment": "standard; norm" },
	{ "question": "規模", "answers": [ "きぼ" ], "comment": "scale; scope; plan; structure" },
	{ "question": "規範", "answers": [ "きはん" ], "comment": "model; standard; pattern; norm; criterion; example" },
	{ "question": "規約", "answers": [ "きやく" ], "comment": "agreement; rules; code; protocol; convention; bylaw" },
	{ "question": "視察", "answers": [ "しさつ" ], "comment": "inspection; observation" },
	{ "question": "視点", "answers": [ "してん" ], "comment": "opinion; point of view; visual point" },
	{ "question": "視覚", "answers": [ "しかく" ], "comment": "sense of sight; vision" },
	{ "question": "視野", "answers": [ "しや" ], "comment": "field of vision; outlook" },
	{ "question": "覚え", "answers": [ "おぼえ" ], "comment": "memory; sense; experience" },
	{ "question": "親しむ", "answers": [ "したしむ" ], "comment": "to be intimate with; to befriend" },
	{ "question": "親善", "answers": [ "しんぜん" ], "comment": "friendship; goodwill; friendly relations; amity" },
	{ "question": "観", "answers": [ "かん" ], "comment": "look; appearance\nspectacle; sight\nobservation meditation\noutlook on ...; view of ..." },
	{ "question": "観点", "answers": [ "かんてん" ], "comment": "point of view" },
	{ "question": "観衆", "answers": [ "かんしゅう" ], "comment": "spectators; onlookers; members of the audience" },
	{ "question": "観覧", "answers": [ "かんらん" ], "comment": "viewing" },
	{ "question": "角", "answers": [ "かど", "つの", "かく" ], "comment": "angle\nsquare (or cube)\nbishop\nthird degree (of the Japanese & Chinese pentatonic scale)\nChinese \"horn\" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)\njiao (monetary unit of China; one-tenth of a yuan)\ncorner (e.g. desk, pavement)\nedge\nhorn\ncorner; nook; recess\ndownstage right (on a noh stage)" },
	{ "question": "解く", "answers": [ "とく", "ほどく" ], "comment": "to untie; to unfasten; to unwrap; to undo; to unbind; to unpack\nto unsew; to unstitch\nto solve; to work out; to answer\nto dispel (misunderstanding, etc.); to clear up; to remove (suspicion); to appease\nto dissolve (a contract); to cancel; to remove (a prohibition); to lift (a ban); to raise (a siege)\nto release (from duty); to relieve; to dismiss\nto comb (out); to card; to untangle (hair)\nto unfasten; to untie; to unwrap (e.g. parcel)" },
	{ "question": "解剖", "answers": [ "かいぼう" ], "comment": "dissection; autopsy\nanalysis" },
	{ "question": "解除", "answers": [ "かいじょ" ], "comment": "cancellation; rescinding; release; calling off; lifting (sanctions); delisting" },
	{ "question": "言い訳", "answers": [ "いいわけ" ], "comment": "excuse\nexplanation" },
	{ "question": "言伝", "answers": [ "ことづて" ], "comment": "(oral) message; declaration; hearsay; rumour; rumor" },
	{ "question": "言論", "answers": [ "げんろん" ], "comment": "(one's) speech; expression of views; discussion" },
	{ "question": "訂正", "answers": [ "ていせい" ], "comment": "correction; revision; amendment" },
	{ "question": "計器", "answers": [ "けいき" ], "comment": "meter; gauge" },
	{ "question": "討伐", "answers": [ "とうばつ" ], "comment": "subjugation; suppression" },
	{ "question": "討論", "answers": [ "とうろん" ], "comment": "debate; discussion" },
	{ "question": "討議", "answers": [ "とうぎ" ], "comment": "debate; discussion" },
	{ "question": "記す", "answers": [ "しるす" ], "comment": "to write down; to note; to jot down\nto remember" },
	{ "question": "記名", "answers": [ "きめい" ], "comment": "signature; register\nto put one's name on; to sign\nstamped name; typed name" },
	{ "question": "記載", "answers": [ "きさい" ], "comment": "record; statement; description; mention; listing; registration; booking; entry" },
	{ "question": "記述", "answers": [ "きじゅつ" ], "comment": "description; descriptor" },
	{ "question": "訪れる", "answers": [ "おとずれる" ], "comment": "to visit; to call on\nto arrive; to come; to appear" },
	{ "question": "設ける", "answers": [ "もうける" ], "comment": "to prepare ahead of time\nto create; to establish" },
	{ "question": "設定", "answers": [ "せってい" ], "comment": "establishment; creation; posing (a problem); setting (movie, novel, etc.); scene\noptions setting; preference settings; configuration; setup" },
	{ "question": "設立", "answers": [ "せつりつ" ], "comment": "establishment; founding; incorporation (of a business)" },
	{ "question": "設置", "answers": [ "せっち" ], "comment": "establishment; institution\ninstallation (of a machine or equipment)" },
	{ "question": "許容", "answers": [ "きょよう" ], "comment": "permission; pardon" },
	{ "question": "訴え", "answers": [ "うったえ" ], "comment": "lawsuit; complaint" },
	{ "question": "訴訟", "answers": [ "そしょう" ], "comment": "litigation; lawsuit" },
	{ "question": "診療", "answers": [ "しんりょう" ], "comment": "diagnosis and treatment; medical care" },
	{ "question": "証", "answers": [ "あかし", "しょう" ], "comment": "mark; sign\nsymbol; emblem\nbadge; crest; flag\nevidence; proof\ntoken (of gratitude, affection, etc.)\nproof (e.g. of love, of innocence); evidence; testimony; vindication (of innocence)\nlicense; membership card; permit\nto testify (usu. Christian religious context)" },
	{ "question": "証人", "answers": [ "しょうにん" ], "comment": "witness" },
	{ "question": "証拠", "answers": [ "しょうこ" ], "comment": "evidence; proof" },
	{ "question": "証言", "answers": [ "しょうげん" ], "comment": "testimony; (verbal) evidence" },
	{ "question": "詐欺", "answers": [ "さぎ" ], "comment": "fraud; swindle; graft; cheating; trick; scam" },
	{ "question": "試み", "answers": [ "こころみ" ], "comment": "attempt; trial; experiment\nendeavour (endeavor); effort; venture; initiative" },
	{ "question": "試みる", "answers": [ "こころみる" ], "comment": "to try; to attempt; to have a go (at something)" },
	{ "question": "詰まらない", "answers": [ "つまらない" ], "comment": "dull; uninteresting; boring; tedious\ninsignificant; unimportant; trifling; trivial; worthless\nabsurd; foolish; silly; stupid\nuseless; pointless; disappointing" },
	{ "question": "詰まり", "answers": [ "つまり" ], "comment": "that is to say; that is; in other words; I mean; that (this, it) means\nin short; in brief; to sum up; ultimately; in the end; in the long run; when all is said and done; what it all comes down to; when you get right down to it; basically\nclogging; obstruction; stuffing; (degree of) blockage\nshrinkage\nend; conclusion\ndead end; corner\ndistress; being at the end of one's rope" },
	{ "question": "該当", "answers": [ "がいとう" ], "comment": "corresponding to; being applicable to; relevant to; coming under; falling under; applying to; fulfilling; qualifying as" },
	{ "question": "詳細", "answers": [ "しょうさい" ], "comment": "detail; particulars" },
	{ "question": "誇る", "answers": [ "ほこる" ], "comment": "to boast of; to be proud of" },
	{ "question": "誇張", "answers": [ "こちょう" ], "comment": "exaggeration" },
	{ "question": "認める", "answers": [ "みとめる", "したためる" ], "comment": "to write up\nto recognize; to recognise; to observe; to notice\nto deem; to judge; to assess\nto approve; to deem acceptable; to allow\nto admit; to accept; to confess (to a charge)\nto watch steadily; to observe carefully\nto renown; to give renown to; to appreciate; to acknowledge" },
	{ "question": "認識", "answers": [ "にんしき" ], "comment": "recognition; awareness; perception; understanding; knowledge; cognition; cognizance; cognisance" },
	{ "question": "誘導", "answers": [ "ゆうどう" ], "comment": "guidance; leading; induction; introduction; incitement; inducement" },
	{ "question": "誘惑", "answers": [ "ゆうわく" ], "comment": "temptation; allurement; lure; enticement; seduction" },
	{ "question": "語句", "answers": [ "ごく" ], "comment": "words; phrases" },
	{ "question": "語彙", "answers": [ "ごい" ], "comment": "vocabulary; lexicon; lexis; terminology" },
	{ "question": "語源", "answers": [ "ごげん" ], "comment": "word root; word derivation; etymology" },
	{ "question": "誠", "answers": [ "まこと" ], "comment": "truth; reality\nsincerity; honesty; integrity; fidelity\nthat's right (used when recalling forgotten information, suddenly changing the subject, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "誠実", "answers": [ "せいじつ" ], "comment": "sincere; honest; faithful" },
	{ "question": "誤る", "answers": [ "あやまる" ], "comment": "to make a mistake; to err\nto mislead; to misguide" },
	{ "question": "誤差", "answers": [ "ごさ" ], "comment": "measurement error; calculation error" },
	{ "question": "誤魔化す", "answers": [ "ごまかす" ], "comment": "to deceive; to falsify; to misrepresent; to cheat; to swindle; to tamper; to juggle; to manipulate\nto dodge; to beg the question (issue, difficulties)\nto varnish over; to gloss over" },
	{ "question": "説く", "answers": [ "とく" ], "comment": "to explain; to advocate; to preach; to persuade" },
	{ "question": "説得", "answers": [ "せっとく" ], "comment": "persuasion" },
	{ "question": "読み上げる", "answers": [ "よみあげる" ], "comment": "to read out loud (and clearly); to call a roll" },
	{ "question": "読者", "answers": [ "どくしゃ" ], "comment": "reader" },
	{ "question": "誰", "answers": [ "だれ", "たれ" ], "comment": "who" },
	{ "question": "課外", "answers": [ "かがい" ], "comment": "extracurricular" },
	{ "question": "課題", "answers": [ "かだい" ], "comment": "subject; theme; issue; matter\nhomework; assignment\ntask; challenge; problem; question" },
	{ "question": "調べ", "answers": [ "しらべ" ], "comment": "investigation; inspection; examination\ntune; note; melody" },
	{ "question": "調停", "answers": [ "ちょうてい" ], "comment": "arbitration; conciliation; mediation" },
	{ "question": "調印", "answers": [ "ちょういん" ], "comment": "signature; signing; sealing" },
	{ "question": "調和", "answers": [ "ちょうわ" ], "comment": "harmony; accord; reconciliation; agreement" },
	{ "question": "調理", "answers": [ "ちょうり" ], "comment": "cooking; food preparation" },
	{ "question": "論理", "answers": [ "ろんり" ], "comment": "logic\nlogical" },
	{ "question": "論議", "answers": [ "ろんぎ" ], "comment": "discussion; argument; debate" },
	{ "question": "諦め", "answers": [ "あきらめ" ], "comment": "resignation; acceptance; consolation" },
	{ "question": "諮る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "to consult with; to discuss; to confer; to deliberate" },
	{ "question": "諸", "answers": [ "もろ", "しょ" ], "comment": "various; many; several\nboth\nmany; various; all\ntogether" },
	{ "question": "諸君", "answers": [ "しょくん" ], "comment": "you (people)\ngentlemen; ladies and gentlemen; my friends; everyone" },
	{ "question": "謀反", "answers": [ "むほん" ], "comment": "rebellion; uprising; insurrection\ntreason\nplotting to overthrow the government (by assassinating the emperor)" },
	{ "question": "講習", "answers": [ "こうしゅう" ], "comment": "short course; training" },
	{ "question": "講読", "answers": [ "こうどく" ], "comment": "reading; translation" },
	{ "question": "謝絶", "answers": [ "しゃぜつ" ], "comment": "refusal" },
	{ "question": "警戒", "answers": [ "けいかい" ], "comment": "vigilance; caution; alertness; precaution; being on guard" },
	{ "question": "警部", "answers": [ "けいぶ" ], "comment": "police inspector" },
	{ "question": "議事堂", "answers": [ "ぎじどう" ], "comment": "assembly hall; parliament house; diet building; capitol; houses of parliament; congress hall" },
	{ "question": "議案", "answers": [ "ぎあん" ], "comment": "legislative bill; measure\nagenda item" },
	{ "question": "議決", "answers": [ "ぎけつ" ], "comment": "resolution; decision; vote" },
	{ "question": "議題", "answers": [ "ぎだい" ], "comment": "topic of discussion; agenda" },
	{ "question": "譲歩", "answers": [ "じょうほ" ], "comment": "concession; conciliation; compromise" },
	{ "question": "護衛", "answers": [ "ごえい" ], "comment": "guard; convoy; escort" },
	{ "question": "豊作", "answers": [ "ほうさく" ], "comment": "abundant harvest; bumper crop" },
	{ "question": "象徴", "answers": [ "しょうちょう" ], "comment": "symbol" },
	{ "question": "豪", "answers": [ "ごう" ], "comment": "strong; hard; manly\ntremendous; huge\nAustralia" },
	{ "question": "貝殻", "answers": [ "かいがら" ], "comment": "seashell; shell" },
	{ "question": "負う", "answers": [ "おう" ], "comment": "to bear; to carry on one's back\nto take responsibility for; to accept a duty\nto be injured\nto owe" },
	{ "question": "負かす", "answers": [ "まかす" ], "comment": "to defeat" },
	{ "question": "負債", "answers": [ "ふさい" ], "comment": "debt; liabilities" },
	{ "question": "負傷", "answers": [ "ふしょう" ], "comment": "injury; wound" },
	{ "question": "負担", "answers": [ "ふたん" ], "comment": "burden; charge; responsibility" },
	{ "question": "財", "answers": [ "ざい" ], "comment": "fortune; riches\ngoods\nincorporated foundation\ntreasure" },
	{ "question": "財政", "answers": [ "ざいせい" ], "comment": "public finance\nfinancial affairs; financial situation" },
	{ "question": "財源", "answers": [ "ざいげん" ], "comment": "source of funds; resources; finances" },
	{ "question": "貧乏", "answers": [ "びんぼう" ], "comment": "poverty; destitute; poor" },
	{ "question": "貧困", "answers": [ "ひんこん" ], "comment": "poor; needy\nlacking; meagre; meager" },
	{ "question": "貧弱", "answers": [ "ひんじゃく" ], "comment": "poor; meagre; meager; insubstantial" },
	{ "question": "貨幣", "answers": [ "かへい" ], "comment": "money; currency; coinage" },
	{ "question": "貫く", "answers": [ "つらぬく" ], "comment": "to go through; to pierce; to penetrate\nto carry out; to persist; to keep (faith); to stick to (principles); to maintain (independence)" },
	{ "question": "責務", "answers": [ "せきむ" ], "comment": "duty; obligation" },
	{ "question": "貯蓄", "answers": [ "ちょちく" ], "comment": "savings" },
	{ "question": "貴い", "answers": [ "とうとい", "たっとい" ], "comment": "precious; valuable; priceless; noble; exalted; sacred" },
	{ "question": "貴方", "answers": [ "あなた" ], "comment": "your home; your residence\nyou (referring to one's equal; epistolary style)\nyou (referring to someone of equal or lower status)\ndear (what a wife calls a husband)\nyou" },
	{ "question": "貴族", "answers": [ "きぞく" ], "comment": "noble; aristocrat" },
	{ "question": "費", "answers": [ "ひ" ], "comment": "cost; expense\nAtai (post-Taika hereditary title often given to regional administrators)" },
	{ "question": "費やす", "answers": [ "ついやす" ], "comment": "to spend; to expend; to consume\nto waste; to squander; to throw away\nto devote" },
	{ "question": "賃金", "answers": [ "ちんぎん" ], "comment": "wages\ncash payment of rent" },
	{ "question": "賄う", "answers": [ "まかなう" ], "comment": "to give board to; to provide meals; to pay; to cover (the cost)" },
	{ "question": "資格", "answers": [ "しかく" ], "comment": "qualifications; requirements; capabilities" },
	{ "question": "資産", "answers": [ "しさん" ], "comment": "property; fortune; means; assets" },
	{ "question": "資金", "answers": [ "しきん" ], "comment": "funds; capital" },
	{ "question": "賛成", "answers": [ "さんせい" ], "comment": "approval; agreement; support; favour; favor" },
	{ "question": "賛美", "answers": [ "さんび" ], "comment": "praise; adoration; glorification" },
	{ "question": "賜る", "answers": [ "たまわる" ], "comment": "to be given; to be granted; to be honored with; to be honoured with\nto give; to bestow; to confer; to honor; to honour" },
	{ "question": "賠償", "answers": [ "ばいしょう" ], "comment": "compensation; reparations; indemnity; damages" },
	{ "question": "賢明", "answers": [ "けんめい" ], "comment": "wisdom; intelligence; prudence" },
	{ "question": "質疑", "answers": [ "しつぎ" ], "comment": "question\ninterpellation" },
	{ "question": "質素", "answers": [ "しっそ" ], "comment": "simple; plain\nmodest; frugal; reserved" },
	{ "question": "賭け", "answers": [ "かけ" ], "comment": "betting; gambling; a gamble" },
	{ "question": "賭ける", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "to wager; to bet; to risk; to stake; to gamble" },
	{ "question": "購入", "answers": [ "こうにゅう" ], "comment": "purchase; buy" },
	{ "question": "購読", "answers": [ "こうどく" ], "comment": "paid subscription (e.g. magazine)" },
	{ "question": "購買", "answers": [ "こうばい" ], "comment": "procurement; purchase; buying\nschool store; co-op; school canteen; tuck shop" },
	{ "question": "赤らむ", "answers": [ "あからむ" ], "comment": "to become red; to redden; to blush" },
	{ "question": "赤字", "answers": [ "あかじ" ], "comment": "deficit; (being in or going into) the red\nred text; red letters\ncorrections (by a teacher or proofreader) written in red" },
	{ "question": "走行", "answers": [ "そうこう" ], "comment": "running a wheeled vehicle (e.g. car); running to program, job, etc.; traveling; travelling" },
	{ "question": "赴く", "answers": [ "おもむく" ], "comment": "to go in the direction of; to proceed toward; to proceed according to; to repair to; to betake oneself to\nto become; to face (facts, circumstances, etc.)\nto abide by; to agree to; to consent to; to obey" },
	{ "question": "赴任", "answers": [ "ふにん" ], "comment": "moving to a different location to start a new job; (proceeding to) new appointment" },
	{ "question": "起こす", "answers": [ "おこす" ], "comment": "to raise; to raise up; to set up; to pick up\nto wake; to wake up; to waken; to awaken\nto cause; to bring about; to lead to; to trigger; to give rise to; to create; to generate (e.g. heat, electricity); to produce\nto start; to begin; to launch; to establish; to found; to set up; to open\nto plough; to plow; to till\nto fall ill with\nto transcribe; to write down (what is spoken)\nto turn over (a card)" },
	{ "question": "起伏", "answers": [ "きふく" ], "comment": "undulation\nups and downs; highs and lows" },
	{ "question": "起源", "answers": [ "きげん" ], "comment": "origin; beginning; rise" },
	{ "question": "起点", "answers": [ "きてん" ], "comment": "starting point; origin" },
	{ "question": "超", "answers": [ "ちょう" ], "comment": "super-; ultra-; hyper-; very; really\nover (after a number or counter); more than" },
	{ "question": "趣", "answers": [ "おもむき" ], "comment": "meaning; tenor; gist\neffect; influence\nappearance; aspect\ntaste\ngrace; charm; refinement" },
	{ "question": "趣旨", "answers": [ "しゅし" ], "comment": "meaning; point (e.g. of a statement); gist; effect\ngoal; intent; object; aim; point" },
	{ "question": "足し算", "answers": [ "たしざん" ], "comment": "addition" },
	{ "question": "距離", "answers": [ "きょり" ], "comment": "distance; range" },
	{ "question": "跡継ぎ", "answers": [ "あとつぎ" ], "comment": "heir; successor" },
	{ "question": "踏まえる", "answers": [ "ふまえる" ], "comment": "to be based on; to have origin in\nto have one's feet firmly planted on; to plant oneself on" },
	{ "question": "蹴飛ばす", "answers": [ "けとばす" ], "comment": "to kick away; to kick off; to kick hard\nto refuse curtly; to reject outright" },
	{ "question": "身なり", "answers": [ "みなり" ], "comment": "dress; attire; clothing; getup; outfit; personal appearance" },
	{ "question": "身体", "answers": [ "からだ", "しんたい" ], "comment": "body\ntorso; trunk\nbuild; physique; constitution\nhealth\ncorpse; dead body\nbody; physical system; person" },
	{ "question": "身振り", "answers": [ "みぶり" ], "comment": "gesture; gesticulation; motion" },
	{ "question": "身近", "answers": [ "みぢか" ], "comment": "near oneself; close to one; familiar" },
	{ "question": "軌道", "answers": [ "きどう" ], "comment": "orbit; trajectory\nrailroad track\n(on the right) track; going smoothly" },
	{ "question": "軍", "answers": [ "ぐん", "いくさ" ], "comment": "army; force; troops\nwar; battle; campaign; fight\ntroops; forces" },
	{ "question": "軍事", "answers": [ "ぐんじ" ], "comment": "military affairs" },
	{ "question": "軍備", "answers": [ "ぐんび" ], "comment": "armaments; military preparations" },
	{ "question": "軍服", "answers": [ "ぐんぷく" ], "comment": "military or naval uniform" },
	{ "question": "軍艦", "answers": [ "ぐんかん" ], "comment": "warship; battleship" },
	{ "question": "軒並み", "answers": [ "のきなみ" ], "comment": "row of houses; every door\ntotally; altogether; across the board" },
	{ "question": "転じる", "answers": [ "てんじる" ], "comment": "to turn; to shift; to alter; to distract" },
	{ "question": "転任", "answers": [ "てんにん" ], "comment": "change of post" },
	{ "question": "転勤", "answers": [ "てんきん" ], "comment": "job transfer; job relocation; intra-company transfer" },
	{ "question": "転回", "answers": [ "てんかい" ], "comment": "revolution; rotation" },
	{ "question": "転居", "answers": [ "てんきょ" ], "comment": "moving; changing residence" },
	{ "question": "転換", "answers": [ "てんかん" ], "comment": "conversion; diversion; changeover; commutation; switchover" },
	{ "question": "転校", "answers": [ "てんこう" ], "comment": "changing schools" },
	{ "question": "転落", "answers": [ "てんらく" ], "comment": "fall; tumble; spill; plunge; dive\ndegradation; comedown; demotion; slump" },
	{ "question": "転転", "answers": [ "てんてん" ], "comment": "moving from place to place; being passed around repeatedly\nrolling about" },
	{ "question": "軸", "answers": [ "じく" ], "comment": "axis; shaft; axle\ncenter; centre; focal point; key point\nstalk; stem\nhanging scroll" },
	{ "question": "軽快", "answers": [ "けいかい" ], "comment": "light (of movements); nimble; sprightly; springy\nlight-hearted; cheerful; buoyant; jaunty; casual (e.g. clothing); rhythmical (e.g. melody)\ntaking a turn for the better (of an illness); receding of symptoms; recovery; convalescence" },
	{ "question": "軽減", "answers": [ "けいげん" ], "comment": "abatement; reduction" },
	{ "question": "軽率", "answers": [ "けいそつ" ], "comment": "rash; thoughtless; careless; hasty; imprudent" },
	{ "question": "軽蔑", "answers": [ "けいべつ" ], "comment": "scorn; disdain; contempt" },
	{ "question": "輪", "answers": [ "りん", "わ" ], "comment": "counter for wheels and flowers\nring; circle; loop\nhoop\nwheel\ncircle (e.g. of friends)" },
	{ "question": "辛うじて", "answers": [ "かろうじて" ], "comment": "barely; narrowly; just manage to do something" },
	{ "question": "辛抱", "answers": [ "しんぼう" ], "comment": "patience; endurance" },
	{ "question": "辞職", "answers": [ "じしょく" ], "comment": "resignation" },
	{ "question": "辞退", "answers": [ "じたい" ], "comment": "declining; refusal; nonacceptance; turning down; withdrawal (e.g. candidacy); pulling out (e.g. race); excusing oneself" },
	{ "question": "農地", "answers": [ "のうち" ], "comment": "agricultural land; farmland" },
	{ "question": "農場", "answers": [ "のうじょう" ], "comment": "farm (agriculture)" },
	{ "question": "農耕", "answers": [ "のうこう" ], "comment": "farming; agriculture; cultivation" },
	{ "question": "辺り", "answers": [ "あたり", "ほとり" ], "comment": "on the bank of; by the side of (e.g. a river, pond)\n(in the) neighbourhood; neighborhood; vicinity; nearby\naround (Sunday, last year, etc...)\nfor instance" },
	{ "question": "込める", "answers": [ "こめる" ], "comment": "to load (a gun, etc.); to charge\nto put into (e.g. emotion, effort)\nto include (e.g. tax in a sales price)\nto hang over; to shroud; to enshroud; to envelop; to screen" },
	{ "question": "迅速", "answers": [ "じんそく" ], "comment": "quick; fast; rapid; swift; prompt; streamlined; expedited; expeditious" },
	{ "question": "近々", "answers": [ "ちかぢか", "きんきん" ], "comment": "soon; nearness; before long" },
	{ "question": "近付く", "answers": [ "ちかづく" ], "comment": "to approach; to draw near; to get close\nto get acquainted with; to get closer to; to get to know" },
	{ "question": "近眼", "answers": [ "きんがん" ], "comment": "nearsightedness; shortsightedness; myopia" },
	{ "question": "近視", "answers": [ "きんし" ], "comment": "myopia; shortsightedness; nearsightedness" },
	{ "question": "近郊", "answers": [ "きんこう" ], "comment": "suburbs; outskirts" },
	{ "question": "返る", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to return; to come back; to go back\nto turn over\n(after the -masu stem of a verb) (to become) extremely; (to become) completely" },
	{ "question": "返済", "answers": [ "へんさい" ], "comment": "repayment; reimbursement; refund; redemption" },
	{ "question": "返答", "answers": [ "へんとう" ], "comment": "reply; answer" },
	{ "question": "返還", "answers": [ "へんかん" ], "comment": "return; restoration" },
	{ "question": "迫害", "answers": [ "はくがい" ], "comment": "persecution; oppression" },
	{ "question": "追い出す", "answers": [ "おいだす" ], "comment": "to expel; to drive out" },
	{ "question": "追い込む", "answers": [ "おいこむ" ], "comment": "to herd; to corner; to drive" },
	{ "question": "追及", "answers": [ "ついきゅう" ], "comment": "investigation (e.g. into someone's guilt); questioning; pressing; hounding; pinning down\ncatching up; overtaking" },
	{ "question": "追放", "answers": [ "ついほう" ], "comment": "exile; banishment; eviction; deportation; transportation" },
	{ "question": "追跡", "answers": [ "ついせき" ], "comment": "chase; pursuit; tracking; stalking\nfollowing up; tracing" },
	{ "question": "退く", "answers": [ "どく", "のく", "ひく", "しりぞく" ], "comment": "to step aside; to move (i.e. out of the way); to make way\nto resign; to retire; to quit; to secede\nto step back; to move back; to retreat\nto withdraw (from the presence of a superior); to leave; to exit\nto resign; to retire; to quit\nto concede\nto move back; to draw back; to recede\nto lessen; to subside; to ebb\nto resign; to retire; to quit" },
	{ "question": "退ける", "answers": [ "どける", "のける", "しりぞける" ], "comment": "to repel; to drive away; to repulse; to reject\nto put something out of the way; to move (something, someone) aside\nto set aside; to keep apart\nto remove (someone) from the group; to shun\nto do well despite difficulties; to accomplish despite adversity\nto do resolutely; to do boldly" },
	{ "question": "退化", "answers": [ "たいか" ], "comment": "degeneration; retrogression" },
	{ "question": "退学", "answers": [ "たいがく" ], "comment": "dropping out of school; withdrawing from school\nexpulsion from school; dismissal\nleaving school (university, etc.) after completing a course" },
	{ "question": "退治", "answers": [ "たいじ" ], "comment": "extermination (e.g. of pests, demons, bandits); elimination; eradication; suppression\nmaking someone renounce worldly desires in order to concentrate on Buddha's teachings\ncuring illness" },
	{ "question": "退職", "answers": [ "たいしょく" ], "comment": "retirement; resignation" },
	{ "question": "送金", "answers": [ "そうきん" ], "comment": "remittance; sending money" },
	{ "question": "逃げ出す", "answers": [ "にげだす" ], "comment": "to run away; to flee; to make off; to take to one's heels; to escape\nto start to run away" },
	{ "question": "逃す", "answers": [ "のがす" ], "comment": "to miss (e.g. a chance); to lose; to let get away\nto set free; to let go\nto fail to ..." },
	{ "question": "逃れる", "answers": [ "のがれる" ], "comment": "to escape" },
	{ "question": "逃亡", "answers": [ "とうぼう" ], "comment": "escape; flight; running away; elopement; fleeing" },
	{ "question": "逃走", "answers": [ "とうそう" ], "comment": "flight; desertion; escape" },
	{ "question": "逆上る", "answers": [ "さかのぼる" ], "comment": "to go upstream\nto go back (in time, to origin); to date back to; to trace back to; to make retroactive" },
	{ "question": "逆立ち", "answers": [ "さかだち" ], "comment": "handstand; headstand" },
	{ "question": "逆転", "answers": [ "ぎゃくてん" ], "comment": "(sudden) change; reversal; turn-around; coming from behind (baseball)" },
	{ "question": "逐一", "answers": [ "ちくいち" ], "comment": "one by one; in detail; minutely" },
	{ "question": "途上", "answers": [ "とじょう" ], "comment": "en route; half-way\non the road; in the street" },
	{ "question": "途中", "answers": [ "とちゅう" ], "comment": "on the way; en route\nin the middle of; midway" },
	{ "question": "途絶える", "answers": [ "とだえる" ], "comment": "to stop; to cease; to come to an end" },
	{ "question": "通", "answers": [ "つう" ], "comment": "connoisseur; authority\ncounter for letters, notes, documents, etc." },
	{ "question": "通りかかる", "answers": [ "とおりかかる" ], "comment": "to happen to pass by" },
	{ "question": "通常", "answers": [ "つうじょう" ], "comment": "common; general; normal; usual" },
	{ "question": "造り", "answers": [ "つくり" ], "comment": "make-up; structure; physique\nmaking; forming; cultivating; growing\nform; appearance" },
	{ "question": "造る", "answers": [ "つくる" ], "comment": "to make; to produce; to manufacture; to build; to construct\nto prepare (food); to brew (alcohol)\nto raise; to grow; to cultivate; to train\nto till\nto draw up (a document); to make out; to prepare; to write\nto create (an artistic work, etc.); to compose\nto coin (a phrase); to organize; to organise; to establish; to found\nto have (a child)\nto make up (one's face, etc.)\nto fabricate (an excuse, etc.)\nto form (a line, etc.)\nto set (a record)\nto commit (a sin, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "連なる", "answers": [ "つらなる" ], "comment": "to extend; to stretch out; to stand in a row\nto attend; to participate in\nto enrol; to join\nto have a connection; to be related; to be linked" },
	{ "question": "連ねる", "answers": [ "つらねる" ], "comment": "to line up; to put in a row\nto add (to a group); to accept (as a member of an organization, etc.); to join (e.g. a list)\nto link; to put together; to string together (e.g. compliments); to enumerate\nto take along with; to bring with" },
	{ "question": "連中", "answers": [ "れんちゅう", "れんじゅう" ], "comment": "company; lot; bunch; gang; pack; those guys; group\ntroupe; company (of musicians)" },
	{ "question": "連休", "answers": [ "れんきゅう" ], "comment": "consecutive holidays" },
	{ "question": "連帯", "answers": [ "れんたい" ], "comment": "solidarity; collective\njoint" },
	{ "question": "連日", "answers": [ "れんじつ" ], "comment": "day after day; every day" },
	{ "question": "連盟", "answers": [ "れんめい" ], "comment": "league; federation; union; alliance" },
	{ "question": "連邦", "answers": [ "れんぽう" ], "comment": "commonwealth; federation of states; confederation; union" },
	{ "question": "進み", "answers": [ "すすみ" ], "comment": "progress" },
	{ "question": "進出", "answers": [ "しんしゅつ" ], "comment": "advance (into a new market or stage of progress); launching (a new career or venture); expanding (into a new market); stepping forward; emerging" },
	{ "question": "進化", "answers": [ "しんか" ], "comment": "evolution; progress" },
	{ "question": "進呈", "answers": [ "しんてい" ], "comment": "presentation (e.g. of a gift)" },
	{ "question": "進展", "answers": [ "しんてん" ], "comment": "progress; development" },
	{ "question": "進度", "answers": [ "しんど" ], "comment": "progress" },
	{ "question": "進捗", "answers": [ "しんちょく" ], "comment": "progress; being under way" },
	{ "question": "進行", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "moving forward (e.g. vehicle); onward movement\nadvance (work, procedure, etc); advancement; progress\nprogress (of a disease); disease progression\nprogression (harmonic, melodic)" },
	{ "question": "進路", "answers": [ "しんろ" ], "comment": "route; course; path\none's future course (e.g. after graduating high school)" },
	{ "question": "逸らす", "answers": [ "そらす" ], "comment": "to turn away; to avert" },
	{ "question": "遂げる", "answers": [ "とげる" ], "comment": "to accomplish; to achieve; to carry out\nto arrive at (a certain outcome); to come to; to end with" },
	{ "question": "遅くとも", "answers": [ "おそくとも" ], "comment": "at the latest" },
	{ "question": "遅らす", "answers": [ "おくらす" ], "comment": "to retard; to delay" },
	{ "question": "遅れ", "answers": [ "おくれ" ], "comment": "delay; lag; postponement; falling behind" },
	{ "question": "遊山", "answers": [ "ゆさん" ], "comment": "excursion; outing; picnic" },
	{ "question": "遊牧", "answers": [ "ゆうぼく" ], "comment": "nomadism" },
	{ "question": "運命", "answers": [ "うんめい" ], "comment": "fate; destiny; lot" },
	{ "question": "運営", "answers": [ "うんえい" ], "comment": "management; administration; operation" },
	{ "question": "運搬", "answers": [ "うんぱん" ], "comment": "transport; transportation; conveyance; carriage" },
	{ "question": "運用", "answers": [ "うんよう" ], "comment": "making use of; application; practical use; investment\noperation; handling; steering (esp. a boat)" },
	{ "question": "運賃", "answers": [ "うんちん" ], "comment": "(passenger) fare\nfreight rates; shipping expenses" },
	{ "question": "運輸", "answers": [ "うんゆ" ], "comment": "transportation" },
	{ "question": "運送", "answers": [ "うんそう" ], "comment": "transport; freight; shipping" },
	{ "question": "過ぎ", "answers": [ "すぎ" ], "comment": "past; after\ntoo (much); over- (e.g. eating)" },
	{ "question": "過ち", "answers": [ "あやまち" ], "comment": "fault; error; indiscretion; faux pas" },
	{ "question": "過労", "answers": [ "かろう" ], "comment": "overwork; strain" },
	{ "question": "過多", "answers": [ "かた" ], "comment": "excess; superabundance" },
	{ "question": "過密", "answers": [ "かみつ" ], "comment": "overcrowding; crowded; congestion" },
	{ "question": "過疎", "answers": [ "かそ" ], "comment": "depopulation" },
	{ "question": "道化", "answers": [ "どうけ" ], "comment": "antics; buffoonery; clowning\nclown; jester" },
	{ "question": "道場", "answers": [ "どうじょう" ], "comment": "dojo (hall used for martial arts training)\nmanda (place of Buddhist practice or meditation, esp. the place under the bodhi tree where Buddha attained enlightenment)" },
	{ "question": "達成", "answers": [ "たっせい" ], "comment": "achievement" },
	{ "question": "達者", "answers": [ "たっしゃ" ], "comment": "in good health; healthy; well; robust; strong\nskilled; clever; proficient" },
	{ "question": "違える", "answers": [ "ちがえる", "たがえる" ], "comment": "to change; to alter\nto mistake; to make a mistake\nto fail to keep (e.g. one's promise)\nto dislocate (e.g. one's neck)\nto change; to alter\nto run counter to; to go against; to break (one's word)\nto make a mistake (in); to err" },
	{ "question": "遠ざかる", "answers": [ "とおざかる" ], "comment": "to go away; to become more distant; to fade away; to die away\nto be estranged" },
	{ "question": "遠回り", "answers": [ "とおまわり" ], "comment": "detour; roundabout way" },
	{ "question": "遠慮", "answers": [ "えんりょ" ], "comment": "reserve; constraint; restraint; modesty; diffidence; hesitation; holding back; discretion; tact; thoughtfulness\ndeclining; refraining\nforethought; foresight" },
	{ "question": "遠方", "answers": [ "えんぽう" ], "comment": "long way; distant place" },
	{ "question": "遣い", "answers": [ "つかい" ], "comment": "errand; mission; going as envoy\nmessenger; bearer; errand boy; errand girl\nfamiliar spirit\nuse; usage; user; trainer; tamer; charmer" },
	{ "question": "遣り通す", "answers": [ "やりとおす" ], "comment": "to carry through; to achieve; to complete" },
	{ "question": "遣る", "answers": [ "やる" ], "comment": "to do; to undertake; to perform; to play (a game); to study\nto send; to dispatch; to despatch\nto put; to move; to turn (one's head, glance, etc.)\nto give (esp. to someone of equal or lower status); to let have; to present; to bestow; to confer\nto make (a vehicle) go faster\nto run (a business); to keep; to be engaged in; to practice (law, medicine, etc.); to practise\nto have (food, drink, etc.); to eat; to drink; to smoke\nto hold (a performance); to perform; to show\nto ease (one's mind)\nto harm; to injure; to kill\nto have sex with\nto live; to get by; to get along\nto do ... completely\nto do ... broadly; to do ... to a great distance\nto do ... for (someone of equal or lower status); to do ... to (sometimes with negative nuance)\nto make active efforts to ..." },
	{ "question": "適宜", "answers": [ "てきぎ" ], "comment": "suitable; appropriate\nappropriately" },
	{ "question": "適応", "answers": [ "てきおう" ], "comment": "adaptation; accommodation; conformity" },
	{ "question": "適性", "answers": [ "てきせい" ], "comment": "aptitude" },
	{ "question": "遭難", "answers": [ "そうなん" ], "comment": "disaster; shipwreck; accident; being stranded" },
	{ "question": "遮る", "answers": [ "さえぎる" ], "comment": "to interrupt; to obstruct (e.g. a view, someone's way); to block (e.g. light, wind); to intercept" },
	{ "question": "選挙", "answers": [ "せんきょ" ], "comment": "election" },
	{ "question": "選考", "answers": [ "せんこう" ], "comment": "selection; screening" },
	{ "question": "遺跡", "answers": [ "いせき" ], "comment": "historic ruins (remains, relics); archeological site" },
	{ "question": "避ける", "answers": [ "さける", "よける" ], "comment": "to avoid (physical contact with)\nto avoid (situation)\nto ward off; to avert" },
	{ "question": "避難", "answers": [ "ひなん" ], "comment": "taking refuge; finding shelter; evacuation; escape" },
	{ "question": "還元", "answers": [ "かんげん" ], "comment": "reduction; resolution; deoxidization; deoxidation\nrestoration; return" },
	{ "question": "還暦", "answers": [ "かんれき" ], "comment": "60th birthday" },
	{ "question": "邪魔", "answers": [ "じゃま" ], "comment": "hindrance; obstacle; nuisance\nto visit (somebody's home)\ndemon who hinders Buddhist training; demon who obstructs sentient beings from maintaining moral behaviour" },
	{ "question": "邸宅", "answers": [ "ていたく" ], "comment": "mansion; residence" },
	{ "question": "部", "answers": [ "ぶ" ], "comment": "department (in an organization); division; bureau\nclub\npart; component; element\ncategory\ncounter for copies of a newspaper or magazine\nhereditary occupational group (Yamato period)" },
	{ "question": "部下", "answers": [ "ぶか" ], "comment": "subordinate person" },
	{ "question": "部門", "answers": [ "ぶもん" ], "comment": "division (of a larger group); branch; field; class (subclass); group; category; department" },
	{ "question": "郷愁", "answers": [ "きょうしゅう" ], "comment": "nostalgia; homesickness" },
	{ "question": "郷里", "answers": [ "きょうり" ], "comment": "birth-place; home town" },
	{ "question": "配偶者", "answers": [ "はいぐうしゃ" ], "comment": "spouse; wife; husband; partner" },
	{ "question": "配分", "answers": [ "はいぶん" ], "comment": "distribution; allotment" },
	{ "question": "配列", "answers": [ "はいれつ" ], "comment": "arrangement; disposition\narray (programming, programing)" },
	{ "question": "配布", "answers": [ "はいふ" ], "comment": "distribution" },
	{ "question": "配慮", "answers": [ "はいりょ" ], "comment": "consideration; concern; forethought" },
	{ "question": "配給", "answers": [ "はいきゅう" ], "comment": "distribution (e.g. films, rice)\nrationing (e.g. food, gasoline)\nfood ration" },
	{ "question": "配置", "answers": [ "はいち" ], "comment": "arrangement (of resources); deployment; stationing; posting; disposition; configuration; layout" },
	{ "question": "酔う", "answers": [ "よう" ], "comment": "to get drunk; to become intoxicated\nto feel sick (e.g. in a vehicle); to become nauseated\nto be elated; to be exalted; to be spellbound; to be in raptures" },
	{ "question": "酪農", "answers": [ "らくのう" ], "comment": "dairy (farm)" },
	{ "question": "酷い", "answers": [ "ひどい" ], "comment": "cruel; merciless; pitiless; brutal; atrocious; inhuman\ntragic; horrible; terrible; dreadful; miserable\ncruel; heartless; hard; harsh; severe\nviolent; intense; strong; heavy; extreme\nvery bad; terrible; awful\nexcessive; exorbitant; unreasonable; outrageous; unfair; unjust" },
	{ "question": "酸", "answers": [ "さん" ], "comment": "acid\nsourness; sour taste\nvinegar" },
	{ "question": "酸っぱい", "answers": [ "すっぱい" ], "comment": "sour; acid" },
	{ "question": "酸化", "answers": [ "さんか" ], "comment": "oxidation; oxidization" },
	{ "question": "酸素", "answers": [ "さんそ" ], "comment": "oxygen (O)" },
	{ "question": "重", "answers": [ "え", "じゅう" ], "comment": "chief; main; principal; important\nmain secondary or supporting role (in kyogen)\n-fold; -ply\nmulti-tiered food box; stacked boxes\nheavy\nserious; extreme\n-fold; -ply" },
	{ "question": "重なる", "answers": [ "かさなる", "おもなる" ], "comment": "to be piled up; to lie on top of one another\nto come one after another; to happen over and over; to pile up (e.g. stress); to accumulate\nto overlap (each other); to occur at the same time; to happen simultaneously\nmain; principal; important" },
	{ "question": "重んじる", "answers": [ "おもんじる" ], "comment": "to respect; to honor; to honour; to esteem; to prize" },
	{ "question": "重んずる", "answers": [ "おもんずる" ], "comment": "to honor; to honour; to respect; to esteem; to prize" },
	{ "question": "重宝", "answers": [ "ちょうほう", "じゅうほう" ], "comment": "convenient; useful; handy; helpful\npriceless treasure\nvaluing highly; prizing" },
	{ "question": "重役", "answers": [ "じゅうやく", "おもやく" ], "comment": "company director; top management; high executive; (person with) heavy responsibilities" },
	{ "question": "重複", "answers": [ "ちょうふく", "じゅうふく" ], "comment": "duplication; repetition; overlapping; redundancy; restoration" },
	{ "question": "野党", "answers": [ "やとう" ], "comment": "opposition party; political opposition; opposition" },
	{ "question": "野外", "answers": [ "やがい" ], "comment": "outdoors; outside; open air\nfields; outskirts; suburbs" },
	{ "question": "野心", "answers": [ "やしん" ], "comment": "ambition; aspiration\nsinister designs; treachery" },
	{ "question": "野生", "answers": [ "やせい" ], "comment": "wild; growing wild; living in the wild\nI" },
	{ "question": "金庫", "answers": [ "きんこ", "かねぐら" ], "comment": "safe; strongbox; cashbox; vault; strongroom\ndepository; cash office; treasury; provider of funds\ntreasure house; treasury\nfinancial supporter; patron; financier; backer" },
	{ "question": "金融", "answers": [ "きんゆう" ], "comment": "financing; credit transacting; loaning of money; circulation of money" },
	{ "question": "金輪際", "answers": [ "こんりんざい" ], "comment": "the deepest bottom of the earth; never; not ... at all; on no account; for all the world; till doomsday" },
	{ "question": "金銭", "answers": [ "きんせん" ], "comment": "money; cash" },
	{ "question": "釣り", "answers": [ "つり" ], "comment": "fishing; angling\nchange (e.g. for a purchase)\ntrolling; writing false posts online" },
	{ "question": "釣り鐘", "answers": [ "つりがね" ], "comment": "temple bell; hanging bell; funeral bell" },
	{ "question": "鈍る", "answers": [ "にぶる", "なまる" ], "comment": "to become blunt; to grow dull\nto become less capable; to weaken; to falter" },
	{ "question": "鉄棒", "answers": [ "てつぼう", "かなぼう" ], "comment": "iron rod; iron bar; iron club\nhorizontal bar (gymnastics)\nmetal rod; metal bar; iron rod; crowbar\niron club; iron staff with rings on top (traditionally used by night watchmen)" },
	{ "question": "鉄片", "answers": [ "てっぺん" ], "comment": "iron scraps" },
	{ "question": "鉄鋼", "answers": [ "てっこう" ], "comment": "iron and steel" },
	{ "question": "鉛", "answers": [ "なまり" ], "comment": "lead (Pb)" },
	{ "question": "鉱山", "answers": [ "こうざん" ], "comment": "mine (ore)" },
	{ "question": "鉱業", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "mining industry" },
	{ "question": "銃", "answers": [ "じゅう", "つつ" ], "comment": "gun; rifle; small arms" },
	{ "question": "錯覚", "answers": [ "さっかく" ], "comment": "optical illusion; hallucination\nmisapprehension; delusion" },
	{ "question": "錯誤", "answers": [ "さくご" ], "comment": "mistake; error; discrepancy\ndiscrepancy between one's actions and intentions" },
	{ "question": "鍛える", "answers": [ "きたえる" ], "comment": "to forge; to temper\nto drill; to train; to discipline" },
	{ "question": "長", "answers": [ "おさ", "ちょう" ], "comment": "height; stature\nlength (esp. of clothing)\nall (one has); everything\nmagnificence (of a waka poem, etc.)\nhead; chief; leader; elder\nmerit; strong point\nsuperiority\nmajor\noffice; official\nchief; head\nhead; chief; leader; elder\nthe greatest of all; the most excellent\nlong" },
	{ "question": "長々", "answers": [ "ながなが" ], "comment": "long; drawn-out; very long" },
	{ "question": "長大", "answers": [ "ちょうだい" ], "comment": "very long; great length" },
	{ "question": "長官", "answers": [ "ちょうかん" ], "comment": "secretary (government); director; chief\ndirector (highest of the four administrative positions of the ritsuryo system); chief" },
	{ "question": "長編", "answers": [ "ちょうへん" ], "comment": "long (e.g. novel, film)" },
	{ "question": "閉口", "answers": [ "へいこう" ], "comment": "dumbfounded; stumped; at one's wits' end; nonplussed\nannoyed" },
	{ "question": "閉鎖", "answers": [ "へいさ" ], "comment": "closing; closure; shutdown; lockout" },
	{ "question": "開催", "answers": [ "かいさい" ], "comment": "holding a meeting; opening an exhibition; hosting (e.g. the Olympics)" },
	{ "question": "開拓", "answers": [ "かいたく" ], "comment": "reclamation (e.g. wasteland); cultivation; development\npioneering; opening up (e.g. new market); breaking new ground; trailblazing" },
	{ "question": "開発", "answers": [ "かいはつ" ], "comment": "development; exploitation" },
	{ "question": "間々", "answers": [ "まま" ], "comment": "occasionally; now and then; sometimes" },
	{ "question": "間もなく", "answers": [ "まもなく" ], "comment": "soon; before long; in a short time\nlacking time to ...; without time to ..." },
	{ "question": "間柄", "answers": [ "あいだがら" ], "comment": "relationship; relation; terms (good, friendly, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "間違う", "answers": [ "まちがう" ], "comment": "to make a mistake; to be incorrect; to be mistaken" },
	{ "question": "関与", "answers": [ "かんよ" ], "comment": "participation; taking part in; participating in; being concerned in" },
	{ "question": "関税", "answers": [ "かんぜい" ], "comment": "tariff (import tax); duty; customs" },
	{ "question": "閲覧", "answers": [ "えつらん" ], "comment": "inspection; reading\nbrowsing (the WWW, Internet); web browsing" },
	{ "question": "闇", "answers": [ "やみ" ], "comment": "darkness; the dark; dark\nbewilderment; despair; hopelessness\nblack-marketeering; shady; illegal; under-the-table" },
	{ "question": "防火", "answers": [ "ぼうか" ], "comment": "fire prevention; fire fighting; fire proof" },
	{ "question": "防衛", "answers": [ "ぼうえい" ], "comment": "defense; defence; protection; self-defense; self-defence" },
	{ "question": "阻む", "answers": [ "はばむ" ], "comment": "to keep someone from doing; to stop; to prevent; to check; to hinder; to obstruct; to oppose; to thwart" },
	{ "question": "阻止", "answers": [ "そし" ], "comment": "obstruction; check; hindrance; prevention; impediment; interdiction; preemption; blocking" },
	{ "question": "降伏", "answers": [ "こうふく" ], "comment": "capitulation; surrender; submission\nyield" },
	{ "question": "降水", "answers": [ "こうすい" ], "comment": "rainfall; precipitation" },
	{ "question": "限定", "answers": [ "げんてい" ], "comment": "limit; restriction" },
	{ "question": "除外", "answers": [ "じょがい" ], "comment": "exception; exclusion" },
	{ "question": "陰気", "answers": [ "いんき" ], "comment": "gloomy; dismal; miserable; melancholy\nspirit of yin" },
	{ "question": "陳列", "answers": [ "ちんれつ" ], "comment": "exhibition; display; putting on show" },
	{ "question": "陶器", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "porcelain (esp. soft-paste porcelain); china; chinaware; earthenware; pottery; ceramics; crockery\nSue ware (type of unglazed pottery made from the middle of the Kofun era through the Heian era)" },
	{ "question": "階", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "storey; story; floor\nstairs\nstage (in chronostratigraphy)\ncounter for storeys and floors of a building\narticle; item; thing; goods; stock\nquality\nflirtatiousness; coquetry\nstairs\nstairs at the front of a noh stage" },
	{ "question": "階層", "answers": [ "かいそう" ], "comment": "class; level; stratum; layer; hierarchy" },
	{ "question": "階級", "answers": [ "かいきゅう" ], "comment": "(social) class; rank; grade" },
	{ "question": "隔たる", "answers": [ "へだたる" ], "comment": "to be distant" },
	{ "question": "隔週", "answers": [ "かくしゅう" ], "comment": "every other week" },
	{ "question": "障る", "answers": [ "さわる" ], "comment": "to be harmful to; to hinder; to interfere with; to irritate" },
	{ "question": "隠居", "answers": [ "いんきょ" ], "comment": "retirement\nretired person" },
	{ "question": "雄", "answers": [ "おす" ], "comment": "male (animal)\nmale; man\nhusband" },
	{ "question": "雅致", "answers": [ "がち" ], "comment": "artistry; good taste; elegance; grace" },
	{ "question": "集まる", "answers": [ "あつまる" ], "comment": "to gather; to collect; to assemble" },
	{ "question": "集計", "answers": [ "しゅうけい" ], "comment": "totalization; totalisation; aggregation; tally (e.g. votes)" },
	{ "question": "雇用", "answers": [ "こよう" ], "comment": "employment (long term); hire" },
	{ "question": "雌", "answers": [ "めす" ], "comment": "female (animal)\nfemale; woman\nwife" },
	{ "question": "雑", "answers": [ "ざつ" ], "comment": "rough; crude; sloppy; messy\nmiscellaneous\nmiscellany (classification of Japanese poetry unrelated to the seasons or to love)" },
	{ "question": "雑木", "answers": [ "ぞうき", "ざつぼく", "ぞうぼく" ], "comment": "various kinds of small trees; assorted trees" },
	{ "question": "雑談", "answers": [ "ざつだん" ], "comment": "chatting; idle talk" },
	{ "question": "雑貨", "answers": [ "ざっか" ], "comment": "miscellaneous goods; general goods; sundries" },
	{ "question": "難", "answers": [ "なん" ], "comment": "difficulty; trouble; hardship\naccident; disaster; danger\nfault; defect\ncriticism" },
	{ "question": "雨具", "answers": [ "あまぐ" ], "comment": "rain gear" },
	{ "question": "雨天", "answers": [ "うてん" ], "comment": "rainy weather" },
	{ "question": "雪崩", "answers": [ "なだれ" ], "comment": "avalanche; snowslide" },
	{ "question": "零す", "answers": [ "こぼす" ], "comment": "to spill; to drop; to shed (tears)\nto grumble; to complain\nto let one's feelings show" },
	{ "question": "零れる", "answers": [ "こぼれる" ], "comment": "to spill; to fall out of; to overflow\nto peek through; to become visible (although normally not)\nto escape (of a smile, tear, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "雷", "answers": [ "かみなり", "いかずち" ], "comment": "lightning; thunder; thunderbolt\ngod of thunder; god of lightning\nanger; fit of anger\nthunder" },
	{ "question": "電源", "answers": [ "でんげん" ], "comment": "source of electricity; electrical power\npower (button on TV, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "電線", "answers": [ "でんせん" ], "comment": "electric line; electric cable; power cable\ntelephone line; telegraph wire" },
	{ "question": "震わせる", "answers": [ "ふるわせる" ], "comment": "to (make something) quiver; to shake; to tremble; to vibrate" },
	{ "question": "露", "answers": [ "つゆ", "あらわ" ], "comment": "Russia\ndew\ntears\n(not) a bit; (not) at all\nexposed; scanty; bare; unconcealed; naked\npublic; open" },
	{ "question": "露骨", "answers": [ "ろこつ" ], "comment": "frank; blunt; plain; outspoken\nconspicuous; open\nbroad; suggestive; lewd" },
	{ "question": "青春", "answers": [ "せいしゅん" ], "comment": "youth; springtime of life; adolescent" },
	{ "question": "静止", "answers": [ "せいし" ], "comment": "stillness; repose; standing still" },
	{ "question": "静的", "answers": [ "せいてき" ], "comment": "static" },
	{ "question": "非", "answers": [ "ひ" ], "comment": "fault; error; mistake\ngoing poorly; being disadvantageous; being unfavorable\nun-; non-; an-" },
	{ "question": "非行", "answers": [ "ひこう" ], "comment": "delinquency; misconduct" },
	{ "question": "非難", "answers": [ "ひなん" ], "comment": "criticism; blame; censure; attack; reproach" },
	{ "question": "面", "answers": [ "メン", "おもて", "つら", "おも" ], "comment": "face\nsurface\nmask (esp. a noh or kyogen mask)\nface; mug\nsurface\nsurrounding area\ncheek; cheeks\nface\nmask; face guard\n(in kendo) striking the head\nsurface (esp. a geometrical surface)\npage\naspect; facet; side\nchamfer\ncounter for broad, flat objects, levels or stages, e.g. in a video game\nlooking like a ...; acting as if a ...." },
	{ "question": "面する", "answers": [ "めんする" ], "comment": "to face on; to look out on to" },
	{ "question": "面会", "answers": [ "めんかい" ], "comment": "meeting (face-to-face); interview" },
	{ "question": "面目", "answers": [ "めんぼく", "（めんもく）" ], "comment": "face; honour; honor; reputation; prestige; dignity; credit\nappearance; look" },
	{ "question": "革命", "answers": [ "かくめい" ], "comment": "revolution\n58th year of the sexagenary cycle (in Onmyōdō)" },
	{ "question": "革新", "answers": [ "かくしん" ], "comment": "reform; innovation" },
	{ "question": "音色", "answers": [ "ねいろ", "おんしょく" ], "comment": "tone color; tone colour; tone quality; timbre\nsynthesizer patch; synthesiser patch" },
	{ "question": "頂", "answers": [ "いただき" ], "comment": "crown (of head); summit (of mountain); spire\neasy win for one\nsomething received" },
	{ "question": "預金", "answers": [ "よきん" ], "comment": "deposit; bank account" },
	{ "question": "頑丈", "answers": [ "がんじょう" ], "comment": "solid; firm; stout; burly; strong; sturdy" },
	{ "question": "頑固", "answers": [ "がんこ" ], "comment": "stubborn; obstinate; pigheaded" },
	{ "question": "領土", "answers": [ "りょうど" ], "comment": "dominion; territory; possession" },
	{ "question": "領地", "answers": [ "りょうち" ], "comment": "territory; dominion; grounds (e.g. school)" },
	{ "question": "領域", "answers": [ "りょういき" ], "comment": "area; domain; territory; field; range; region; regime" },
	{ "question": "領海", "answers": [ "りょうかい" ], "comment": "territorial waters" },
	{ "question": "頬っぺた", "answers": [ "ほっぺた" ], "comment": "cheek" },
	{ "question": "頻繁", "answers": [ "ひんぱん" ], "comment": "frequent; incessant" },
	{ "question": "頼み", "answers": [ "たのみ" ], "comment": "request; favor; favour\nreliance; dependence; trust\ndepending on; dependent upon" },
	{ "question": "顎", "answers": [ "あご" ], "comment": "chin; jaw\nchin; jaw\ngills; branchia" },
	{ "question": "顔付き", "answers": [ "かおつき" ], "comment": "(outward) looks; features; face; countenance; expression" },
	{ "question": "願書", "answers": [ "がんしょ" ], "comment": "written application or petition; application form" },
	{ "question": "類", "answers": [ "るい", "たぐい" ], "comment": "kind; sort; type; class; genus; order; family\nsimilar example; parallel; the like\nkind; sort; type\nequal; match; peer" },
	{ "question": "類似", "answers": [ "るいじ" ], "comment": "resemblance; similarity; analogous; quasi\nto resemble; to be similar; to be alike" },
	{ "question": "類推", "answers": [ "るいすい" ], "comment": "analogy\nanalogical reasoning; analogical inference\nanalogy" },
	{ "question": "顧みる", "answers": [ "かえりみる" ], "comment": "to look back (e.g. over shoulder or at the past); to turn around\nto reflect on the past; to reconsider; to review\nto reflect on oneself; to introspect; to contemplate oneself\nto consider (usu. used in negative); to concern oneself about; to pay attention to; to take into consideration" },
	{ "question": "風俗", "answers": [ "ふうぞく" ], "comment": "manners; customs\nsex service; sex industry; sex-oriented entertainment" },
	{ "question": "風呂", "answers": [ "ふろ" ], "comment": "bath; bathtub\nbathroom; bathhouse\nroom for drying lacquerware\nbase (wooden joint connecting the blade of a hoe, spade, etc., to the handle)" },
	{ "question": "風土", "answers": [ "ふうど" ], "comment": "natural features; topography; climate; spiritual features" },
	{ "question": "風習", "answers": [ "ふうしゅう" ], "comment": "custom" },
	{ "question": "風車", "answers": [ "かざぐるま", "ふうしゃ" ], "comment": "pinwheel (toy); windmill (toy)\nwindmill\nClematis patens (species of climbing plant)" },
	{ "question": "食い違う", "answers": [ "くいちがう" ], "comment": "to cross each other; to run counter to; to differ; to clash; to go awry" },
	{ "question": "飲み込む", "answers": [ "のみこむ" ], "comment": "to gulp down; to swallow deeply\nto understand; to take in; to catch on to; to learn; to digest\nto engulf; to swallow up\nto be filled with (people); to be crowded\nto hold back from saying something; to swallow (one's words)" },
	{ "question": "飼育", "answers": [ "しいく" ], "comment": "breeding; raising; rearing" },
	{ "question": "飽和", "answers": [ "ほうわ" ], "comment": "saturation" },
	{ "question": "養う", "answers": [ "やしなう" ], "comment": "to support; to maintain; to provide for\nto bring up; to raise; to rear; to feed\nto adopt (a child)\nto cultivate (a habit, a quality, etc.); to develop; to build up; to foster\nto recuperate (from injury, illness, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "養成", "answers": [ "ようせい" ], "comment": "training; development" },
	{ "question": "養護", "answers": [ "ようご" ], "comment": "nursing; (protective) care" },
	{ "question": "館", "answers": [ "カン", "やかた", "たち" ], "comment": "mansion; small castle\nnobleman; noblewoman\nboat cabin\nhouse; hall; building\ninn" },
	{ "question": "首脳", "answers": [ "しゅのう" ], "comment": "head; leader; leading spirit\nimportant part" },
	{ "question": "首輪", "answers": [ "くびわ" ], "comment": "(animal) collar\nnecklace; choker" },
	{ "question": "首飾り", "answers": [ "くびかざり" ], "comment": "necklace; choker" },
	{ "question": "香辛料", "answers": [ "こうしんりょう" ], "comment": "spices; condiment" },
	{ "question": "馬力", "answers": [ "ばりき" ], "comment": "horsepower; hp\nenergy; vitality; vigour" },
	{ "question": "馬鹿らしい", "answers": [ "ばからしい" ], "comment": "absurd" },
	{ "question": "馬鹿馬鹿しい", "answers": [ "ばかばかしい" ], "comment": "absurd; ridiculous; silly; ludicrous; nonsensical; asinine; foolish" },
	{ "question": "駄作", "answers": [ "ださく" ], "comment": "poor piece of work; rubbish; trash" },
	{ "question": "駆けっこ", "answers": [ "かけっこ" ], "comment": "(foot) race; sprint" },
	{ "question": "駆ける", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "to run (race, esp. horse); to dash\nto gallop (one's horse); to canter\nto advance (against one's enemy)\nto soar; to fly\nto run; to dash" },
	{ "question": "駆け足", "answers": [ "かけあし" ], "comment": "running fast; double time\ncantering\ndoing things in a hurry" },
	{ "question": "騒動", "answers": [ "そうどう" ], "comment": "strife; riot; rebellion; turmoil\n(media) uproar; brouhaha; (public) outcry; scandal; controversy\nfeud; tussle; quarrel; dispute" },
	{ "question": "驚き", "answers": [ "おどろき" ], "comment": "surprise; astonishment; wonder; amazement" },
	{ "question": "驚異", "answers": [ "きょうい" ], "comment": "wonder; miracle; amazement; prodigy" },
	{ "question": "骨", "answers": [ "ほね", "こつ" ], "comment": "knack; skill; trick; secret; know-how; the ropes; hang\nbone\nframe\noutline; core\nbackbone; spirit; fortitude\nlaborious; troublesome; difficult" },
	{ "question": "高", "answers": [ "たか" ], "comment": "quantity; amount; volume; number; amount of money\nhigh school\nhigh-" },
	{ "question": "高まる", "answers": [ "たかまる" ], "comment": "to rise; to swell; to be promoted" },
	{ "question": "高原", "answers": [ "こうげん" ], "comment": "tableland; plateau" },
	{ "question": "高尚", "answers": [ "こうしょう" ], "comment": "high; noble; refined; advanced" },
	{ "question": "鬱陶しい", "answers": [ "うっとうしい" ], "comment": "gloomy (e.g. mood); depressing\nirritating; troublesome\nheavy (weather); cloudy" },
	{ "question": "魂", "answers": [ "こん", "たましい" ], "comment": "soul; spirit\nYang energy; spirit" },
	{ "question": "鮮やか", "answers": [ "あざやか" ], "comment": "vivid; bright; brilliant; clear; fresh; vibrant\nskillful; skilful; adept; adroit; deft; brilliant; beautiful; fine; excellent" },
	{ "question": "鳥居", "answers": [ "とりい" ], "comment": "torii; Shinto shrine archway" },
	{ "question": "麓", "answers": [ "ふもと" ], "comment": "foot (of a mountain or hill); bottom; base" },
	{ "question": "麻", "answers": [ "あさ" ], "comment": "cannabis (Cannabis sativa); hemp (plant)\nhemp (fiber); linen; flax; jute" },
	{ "question": "麻酔", "answers": [ "ますい" ], "comment": "anaesthesia; anesthesia" },
	{ "question": "黄色", "answers": [ "きいろ", "おうしょく", "こうしょく" ], "comment": "yellow; amber" },
	{ "question": "黄金", "answers": [ "おうごん" ], "comment": "gold" },
	{ "question": "黒字", "answers": [ "くろじ" ], "comment": "balance (figure) in the black" },
	{ "question": "遂に", "answers": [ "ついに" ], "comment": "finally; at last\nin the end" },
	{ "question": "籠", "answers": [ "かご" ], "comment": "basket (shopping, etc.); hamper; cage" },
	{ "question": "醸し出す", "answers": [ "かもしだす" ], "comment": "to engender; to bring about" },
	{ "question": "豪快", "answers": [ "ごうかい" ], "comment": "hearty; exciting; stirring; lively; heroic; largehearted; splendid" },
	{ "question": "忍耐", "answers": [ "にんたい" ], "comment": "endurance; perseverance; patience" },
	{ "question": "驚嘆", "answers": [ "きょうたん" ], "comment": "wonder; admiration; being struck with admiration" },
	{ "question": "起用", "answers": [ "きよう" ], "comment": "appointment (to a position, job, etc.); being used for a role; promotion" },
	{ "question": "駆け付ける", "answers": [ "かけつける" ], "comment": "to run to; to come running; to rush (someplace); to hasten" },
	{ "question": "克明", "answers": [ "こくめい" ], "comment": "detailed; elaborate; faithful (copy); accurate\nscrupulous; diligent; conscientious" },
	{ "question": "手立て", "answers": [ "てだて" ], "comment": "means; method" },
	{ "question": "渋る", "answers": [ "しぶる" ], "comment": "to hesitate; to hold back; to balk; to falter\nto be reluctant; to be unwilling; to begrudge\nto have loose painful bowel movement; to suffer from tenesmus" },
	{ "question": "交錯", "answers": [ "こうさく" ], "comment": "mixture; blending; complication; crossing; intersecting; interlacing" },
	{ "question": "誘拐", "answers": [ "ゆうかい" ], "comment": "abduction; kidnapping; kidnaping" },
	{ "question": "認定", "answers": [ "にんてい" ], "comment": "authorization; authorisation; acknowledgment; acknowledgement; certification; recognition" },
	{ "question": "解禁", "answers": [ "かいきん" ], "comment": "lifting a ban" },
	{ "question": "採取", "answers": [ "さいしゅ" ], "comment": "picking; collecting; harvesting" },
	{ "question": "多角", "answers": [ "たかく" ], "comment": "many-sided; versatile; polygonal; diversified" },
	{ "question": "多角的", "answers": [ "たかくてき" ], "comment": "multilateral; many-sided; diversified" },
	{ "question": "鮮烈", "answers": [ "せんれつ" ], "comment": "vivid; striking" },
	{ "question": "絶大", "answers": [ "ぜつだい" ], "comment": "tremendous; immense" },
	{ "question": "熱烈", "answers": [ "ねつれつ" ], "comment": "ardent; passionate; vehement" },
	{ "question": "作動", "answers": [ "さどう" ], "comment": "operation; functioning; running" },
	{ "question": "開業", "answers": [ "かいぎょう" ], "comment": "opening a business; opening a practice" },
	{ "question": "基調", "answers": [ "きちょう" ], "comment": "basic tone; underlying tone; basic theme; basis; keynote\ntrend\nkeynote" },
	{ "question": "黙る", "answers": [ "だまる" ], "comment": "to be silent" }
]
}
